I think the position should be pretty good, right?
Yeah.
You want your full body, no?
In the shot.
Me or Val?
Everybody.
Well, what part of me is in the shot now?
Well, it's just, I mean, maybe you could just a little bit on there.
Where's your, where's...
Yeah, like this.
Okay.
Yeah, so where's his free man, so he doesn't...
Yeah, I thought it was right around here, because keep in mind it goes, once you actually
hit play, hit record.
It's going to go over more.
It's not over CC.
Oh, yeah, because this is...
Yeah, you've got room.
No, sorry.
Is this okay right now?
Yeah, that's great.
Okay, great.
Okay.
Oh, Kida.
So, we are...
We are in the early days of them at Deutsche Bank, and so Edson is, as I've said, and as
you know, just like, he's unbridled id, and that's like, that's what he is.
He's like a big bundle of id.
And Bill...
A bit of ego.
Bill is more the super ego, right?
He's the one who is reserved, he kind of restrains the...
He's a practical one.
He's practical, he's conservative, and he's just like down to earth.
Sometimes in ways that people make fun of him for, like he takes the tube to work, which
is crazy, because these guys do not take the tube, and they take the tube.
No, he loves the tube.
Yeah, he loves the tube.
Loves the subway.
He loves trains.
Loves trains.
I like trains, too.
So one of...
Bill was kind of running a business, but he had a co-head of the business, a guy named
Martin Loat.
Loat?
He was a retired British military officer.
What's he a military officer?
He was in...
The rumor was that, which wasn't true, is that he was a Special Forces officer, but he's
just...
He's not.
He was in the military.
Like, doing life in the military.
I think he was in the army, I'm not quite sure what he was doing.
It doesn't really matter, for these purposes.
So, sorry, Bill took Martin under his wing a bit, and kind of trained him on...
Especially when it came to ethical things.
So he...
He trained Martin on that, yes.
And it...
So Martin always looked up to him.
Bill's mantra, which he'd always repeat, was, let's get down to first principles.
First principles.
Yeah, so he would, you know, let's cut to the chase.
Let's look at things from boiling down to their essence.
He...
When there was a problem, he would be dispatched to clean it up.
There's a financial crisis in Asia.
Bill's immediately on the flight to Hong Kong.
He reminded some of his colleagues of the wolf character in Pulp Fiction.
Oh, yeah, the fixer, sure.
Yeah, the fixer.
Some colleagues...
Yeah, and one of the good things about his restraining influence
on Edson is that, you know, he calmed people when times were too good, and he made people
kind of just be a little more restrained.
Some people, some of his colleagues told me, a number of his colleagues told me, that they
wondered if maybe he was depressed.
That was...
Well, because he was...
He dampened everything.
It was like...
But if it was...
Yeah, if everyone was, you know, extremely joyful, he said, we'll come back down to Earth
and let's...
I think what you guys described it to me is that he managed to drain the emotions from
everything.
No, but he was...
Everyone was too depressed.
Let's not argue about this.
I'm just saying this with people with his colleagues' perception.
Okay, but let me give you the opposing viewpoint.
If someone was way too happy and joyful, it would say, you know, calm down a bit, let's
focus on what's needed to be done, you're over, you know, exaggerating with a lot of
this joy when you need to focus on the reality of the matter.
If someone was too low or depressed, you would say, you're focusing too much on this misery
instead of the practicality of it.
There's no need for this depression if you think things through.
Just like there's no need for this excess joy because there's something always looming
in the background.
Be prepared for everything.
I completely understand what you're saying.
And that can be misinterpreted as depression, depending on who he's talking to.
If he's talking to someone that's really happy and my dad comes in and says he wants to burst
their bubble, they're going to say how he was depressed.
Don't be so defensive about the kinds of depression.
I'm not...
I certainly...
I just wanted to make it clear that that is very, very much dependent on one's perception
and the situation all as well.
So if someone's to say he's depressed because he bursted my bubble...
As you'll see as we go through this, there are a lot of people who at various points
wonder if Bill is depressed.
Okay, but that's why I'm just...
I know you're making the case for this depression and I'm just making the case against him.
I'm not making the case for depression.
I'm saying accurately, obviously, that that is the way a number of colleagues told me
that that is what they...
They didn't say he was depressed.
They're saying they wondered if maybe he was depressed.
That was how they perceived it.
And during what points in time?
I mean, this was...
Throughout...
Yeah, I mean at different points in time.
So this point that I'm talking about right now is in around 97.
Okay.
So this is shortly after...
This is a year or so after he's joined the Beck.
Okay.
And maybe two years after he's joined the Beck.
After he's joined Deutsche.
Okay, so let's see.
Edson started his affair with Estelle.
Yes, Estelle.
Which is a wonderful story, but let's not even go there right now.
But you've included the story.
Oh, yeah.
Okay.
Oh, and Estelle becomes like a fairly significant character.
Does she?
Going for it.
Yeah, okay.
Did you talk to her?
I'm not going to get into who I talked to and who I didn't talk to.
Okay.
Okay, so Deutsche Bank does in the late night, in 98, it buys Banker's Trust.
Yes.
Which is...
It turns out to be a real disaster of...
That's kind of one of the original sins for Deutsche Bank.
It was buying up Banker's Trust.
I mean, it's a horrible deal.
And it's a terrible deal.
They're doing it.
For buying it up and turning it into DVTCA?
Well, it became...
It kind of became a large number that became DVTCA.
This is like the kind of real point at which Deutsche Bank went from being a European-centered
investment bank into an American investment bank.
Or becoming a European bank, a German bank into a global bank.
You could argue that.
Well, it was already...
At that point, it was very big in London already.
It was asleep, as people describe it, a sleepy bank.
I think that was actually Landon.
Landon Thomas.
Sorry to hear about your...
No, I'm not being a dick.
It's just that Landon described it as a sleepy little bank at the time.
And he was right.
And then when my dad and I came along, I turned into a bad myth.
Right.
But what I'm saying...
And buying DVTCA was part of that expansion.
No, no, no, no.
DVTCA, they didn't buy DVTCA.
I mean, buying Banker's Trust and becoming DVTCA was part of that expansion.
Banker's Trust didn't become DVTCA.
Like, Banker's Trust is a...
It's an early version of DVTCA.
Okay, let's just move on.
It doesn't matter.
It matters.
I'm just wanting...
Because this is a fact check, is it not?
Yeah, but this is a fact check that we're doing of you and your father.
Okay, fine.
You're just going to need to trust me that I'm this kind of stuff in particular.
Okay.
I have done a lot of research before.
Okay, I believe you.
So, let's see.
Okay, then we'll get into a bunch of Trump shit, which I'm not going to get into with you right now.
Just purely for...
Any background?
Yeah, it's like the story of how Deutsche Bank got into Trump.
Okay.
And...
Do you know...
Do you name names here?
Yeah.
Okay.
Is this going to be breaking?
Some of this has been told previously.
Okay.
Did you get off on the guys to sign the loans?
What was that?
Did you write down the guys to sign the loans?
I think I saw that yesterday.
This is about the people who started the relationship with Trump.
Okay.
What conclusions did you come to?
Nothing.
Oh, come on.
There's no...
There's...
No, it's not even that.
No, don't turn it off.
There's not...
What?
Nothing groundbreaking or nothing...
There's interesting stuff.
I can get into that right now.
Okay.
There's...
Any connections to Justice Kennedy?
Nothing good.
I feel like I'm the reporter and you're the source.
Can you confirm or deny Justice Kennedy's involvement in the Sun?
No?
Well, Justice...
Yeah.
Okay.
I'll let it go.
Okay, so in 2000, Bill retires for a second time.
Okay.
And he felt simultaneously overwhelmed and bored.
Mm-hmm.
And he also felt like he was neglecting his daughters.
And maybe he's burning it.
So in August 2000, he decides to retire for the second time.
Edson tried to keep him.
The bill kind of equivocated a little bit and then decided he needed to get out.
Mm-hmm.
He was going to withdraw over several months.
He's going to spend time with his family and still be in Shakespeare,
involved in their soup kitchen.
And the...
What did you get?
He said to someone that it was hard to do a job and we've done it,
which didn't really run true, because the job was definitely not done.
And once again...
Which job?
Well, they're building Deutsche Bank into a modern institution,
and that was definitely not a finished thing.
By 2000?
No.
I mean, that wasn't finished for years.
Okay.
It still isn't finished.
Well, I mean, it became from small to big.
I think that's what he's referring to.
Taking small banks is making it to big global bank.
Right?
What I'm saying is that to the people he used those words with,
it did not run true.
It did not run true.
Okay.
And I'm also saying that to some of his colleagues,
the fact that these retirements were becoming a pattern,
suggested to them that he was having some trouble covering with the pressure,
and that there was a certain fragility there.
Okay.
And again, that's not...
That's simply the way they perceived it.
Sure.
Okay.
Edson...
Edson is kind of...
He's with Estelle and is, you know, losing.
Bill's gone, and that check on him and Super Ego is gone,
and he's spinning a little bit of control.
Edson.
Yeah.
And that, you guys.
And I'm recounting the scene that you encountered
in the Park Avenue apartment.
Yeah.
You could hear Sinead O'Connor,
which was weird because you got a hater Sinead O'Connor.
Yeah.
And you went in and sat down with them, and he was crying,
and the song was on repeat,
and he said, Dad, you okay?
And he said, Not really, but I will be.
That sound about right?
Yeah.
I sat with them for a while.
You go over the whole thing.
Okay.
So Bill says he will be okay.
Deutsche Bank is not going to be okay because this is the moment
where everything starts to fall apart.
Bill's gone, Edson's dead,
and a huge power struggle breaks out to fill with those voids.
And this is where Anshu starts to really gain power and climb.
And Anshu, as you know, is very ambitious.
And, okay, so we're going to skip a bunch of stuff right now
because it's just like, there's no, actually no or not.
We're coming right back to you.
We're coming right back to you right here.
Did you do any parallels with what's going on at Merrill Lynch
at the time?
Not really.
I mean, if we get into a bit later, like, that your dad was doing
some consulting.
I didn't really feel like he was being listened to by Stan O'Neill
and down here.
Okay.
And that Stan O'Neill was trying to get him to take a bigger job,
and your dad said, no, no, no, no, no, I just wouldn't do it.
And any warnings about the coming crisis?
There's, well, you know, I'm not actually getting into this
in the book.
Okay.
But your dad actually, this is one of the things,
there's a few things toward the end of his life, especially,
that he got wrong quite badly.
Yeah.
And the financial crisis is one of them.
He's one of them.
He really underestimated, there are these emails between him
and McKaylee, where they're kind of talking about how bad the crisis
is about to be.
And your dad, again, I'm not getting into this in the book,
because it's not that relevant, but he did misread it.
And again, it's like a misreading that a lot of people had,
but he predicted, he made very specific predictions about how
things were going to play out and how bad they were going to be.
And he was wrong.
But again, the, okay, we're talking about some of the,
so you graduate from college, you moved to New York,
you were taking classes at NYU, we were talking about this yesterday.
You're not going to like this.
I'm noting that a number, in fact, I'm saying many of Bill's
colleagues knew that he had two daughters,
but didn't realize he had a son.
I'm also noting that you actually had a slightly warmer relationship
with Bill than you did with your mom, who, like,
struck some of your friends and some of the family's friends
as just very icy.
And whereas Bill was really trying to understand your rebelliousness
and tried to get to know you.
And actually say that you told friends at the time that you felt
like you had been a burden to your mom ever since she fled Ukraine
and why else would she have let you be dumped and fostered here.
That's a direct quote from Matt Goldsboro.
Did you say that?
Okay, so you bounce around.
I don't remember saying that, but it's possible.
Does that sound like an accurate encapsulation of your feelings?
I'm sure at the time, maybe, yeah.
Okay, so we're going back and I'm talking about some of the jobs
you haven't mentioned, kitchen nightmares.
What was the thing you told me about yesterday that I didn't realize?
Oh, there's the website thing.
Michael Luton.
Yeah, I had no idea about that.
Big.com, Michael Luton.
There's a bunch of websites.
But I know that your main passion and obsession and love is music.
And there's Good Time Charlie's, which became Bikini Robot Army.
And the band was basically you and whoever you were jamming with at that moment.
Describing you, he was a talented musician and songwriter
tapping this deep well of painful memories for inspiration.
The result was mournful, angry, beautiful guitar piano ballads like Hey Mama,
in 2002.
And then we've got Hey Mama.
Have you listened to Hey Mama?
Hey Mama's a really nice song.
Thank you.
Your music's really good.
I actually, like, not look a smug of your ass.
Oh, thank you.
There's enough fucking smoke in this room anyway.
Okay, we meet...
It's fake.
It's vapor.
It's not smoking in mine.
There's literally, like, he's...
No, it's fine.
Keep David from sleeping.
It's fine.
Yeah, exactly.
It's like coffee.
Right, the coffee.
Oh, good.
Yeah, I need some more of that, too.
Oh, thank you.
Let's see.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Oh, this is, like, real serious.
Sweetheart.
Let's see.
Muah.
Okay.
So, Joe Ackerman, we meet.
Oh, Ackerman is the character.
Yeah.
And I'm not going to bore you with all of this.
In fact, this section...
What is important?
Because you go to the bank of Cyprus.
Yeah, I know it's important.
Val, just in the interest of time here, like, there's...
He's a very important character in the book.
But it's just not...
There's no point in fact checking that with you, because...
In Colin?
Colin Fan?
Yeah.
He's in there, so...
He's in there, too.
We talked to...
Fuck, what's his name?
Sabah, capital guy.
The camera was in there.
Boas, wine soup?
Boas, yeah.
We talked to him?
Nothing.
We've talked to him.
Okay.
Because there's an interesting relationship
between Boas and Colin.
Colin Fan.
Yeah.
Yeah, you've mentioned that.
There's an interesting relationship between Boas
and a lot of people.
Boas is...
My dad really likes him.
I know he does.
Yeah.
You've mentioned that.
Oh, Kydoke.
Kydoke?
So I note here at the end of chapter 10
that this is the late odds.
The late...
Or not the late odds.
It's like the mid odds.
Okay.
And this is like a go-go period for the bank.
And it's actually...
They don't realize it, but it's spinning out of control.
And the bank desperately needed someone to be there
to say no, and wasn't afraid to give unwanted news.
Someone like Bill.
Okay.
But Bill wasn't there.
In fact, Bill was...
In the months after the Edson died,
had been very glad that he no longer worked in the bank.
He told friends that he just realized that he even came to kind of
view Edson's death as a result of the banking industry in some ways.
Like if he hadn't been so competitive and profit hungry,
maybe Edson wouldn't have died.
If Edson hadn't been so profit hungry.
Well, I mean, the way I've got it here is that
like the endless hours, the cutthroat environment, the dubious ethics,
these things hadn't caused Edson's plane to go down.
But in some ways, if he squinted hard enough,
perhaps they'd contributed to it.
Maybe he hadn't worked so hard.
Maybe he hadn't worked as hard as his wife would have stayed in London.
And Edson wouldn't have boarded that fateful flight to Rangeley.
Maybe he wouldn't have owned his own plane.
Maybe he would have enforced a flight commercial.
Or maybe not.
I like the squinting.
That's good.
Yeah.
But Bill told acquaint...
Ladies and gentlemen, that is why David is the writer.
You see?
If you squint it, maybe you can see this.
That's good.
And I'm not blowing smoke up your ass.
Good.
Come sit down so people can see your beautiful bald head.
Yeah.
So let me just do this right here.
Off camera first.
Yes.
So I'll just keep going.
Okay, please go ahead.
So Bill, obviously not in banking anymore.
Immediate priority is to help Estelle,
who is, you know, not only heartbroken,
but also ostracized by everyone because, you know,
she was the mistress.
And so he, Bill, gave her some spending money,
kept her busy doing odd jobs,
had her fixing up the flat after it caught on fire.
Fire.
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Just some fond anecdotes about Bill that I think you already know.
About how, like, you know, he could be a penny pincher sometimes,
but he was generous when it mattered.
But he was a penny pincher.
Yeah.
But he also, like, I'm kind of...
Stop using all those paper towels.
You only need one sheet of paper towel.
Why are you using four sheets?
What's wrong?
It's like me not flushing the toilet in my...
It's like, yeah.
I'm shaking water.
David didn't flush the toilet in his hotel room.
I'm like, David, flush the toilet because I go in the bathroom.
If it's...
Yeah, I'm saving water, Val.
I'm an environmentalist, man.
I know.
That's what I said.
So I'm recounting the anecdote of when some Brookesman family member needed
some sort of expensive medical procedure that wasn't insured,
Bill offered to pay for it.
And when the person resisted and said,
no, I'm not going to accept your money,
Bill said the person who ever was resisting was a liberal.
And Bill said that if he refused to let him pay,
Bill would instead donate that money to the Republican Party.
That's about right, yeah.
Bill was bored.
Yeah.
It was monotonous.
Mm-hmm.
He bought a dog.
Yeah, lazy.
Started a family foundation.
Yeah.
Went to Vegas with some college buddies.
Mm-hmm.
He sat around puffing his pipe and watching old movies.
He sometimes joined Michael Morandy for tennis in Central Park.
And...
Turned a couple book clubs, too.
Morandy could see in his friend's eyes that Bill was not very happy.
No.
He wrote long letters to newspaper editors that never got published.
One was published.
You sure about that?
Yeah, yeah, there was one published in Washington.
I'll show it to you.
Yeah, send it to me.
He went to the baths alone.
Yes, yeah.
And it struck up conversations with the strangers
because he didn't have his best friend to go there with.
And he drank a lot.
And he diagnosed himself as an alcoholic.
He...
Some friends who he went out with at the time
said that he would get to a drunk that he puked the next morning.
You've obviously told me a kind of similar example.
Let's talk about Bob's baths already.
Yeah, that was funny.
Once again, some of Bill's friends...
But to say you're an alcoholic because you puked...
He diagnosed himself as an alcoholic.
Yeah, I mean, but that's like...
I'm not saying he's an alcoholic.
And he didn't...
At some point, everyone that's drinking too much said,
I'm an alcoholic.
But then...
As you know from your dad's notes,
he viewed himself as an alcoholic.
Yeah, I hate that, okay.
And so did your mom.
All right.
So I'm not...
Again, I'm not saying any of that in a pejorative way.
Okay.
Once again, some of his friends wonder if he was depressed.
One of them, Saman Majd...
Saman...
Was...
This is in emails asking about well-buttern.
Yeah.
And Bill says, quote,
I'm not at all depressed, just very lazy and sluggish.
Um...
So Stan and Neil calls, lures him back to Meryl.
He comes on as a consultant.
Doing lots of work.
Uh...
Describes his nothing too strenuous.
He describes to his style, actually.
He's nothing too strenuous,
but it's fun to be near the game.
Okay.
We're not the...
Uh...
What year are we at?
We're in...
It's 2004.
Um...
Yeah, 2004-2005.
Let's see...
Anju, meanwhile, is climbing up the ranks.
He's looking for jobs elsewhere.
And then I go through a bunch of Anju's piranhas,
as one person describes them.
And let's see...
Let's see...
Okay.
Um...
2007, crisis is bubbling up.
And in August, um...
Actually, in that summer, Stan and Neil
tries to get Bill to come on as a permanent employee.
Right.
And they don't.
He refuses.
And he just kind of shook his head sadly.
And Neil said,
No, I'm not going to do it.
And that was the last...
He didn't like his books.
His derivative books.
What was that?
He didn't like his derivative books.
He didn't like anything.
He didn't feel like he was being listened to.
And...
He felt it wasn't the same Merrill.
What was that?
He felt it wasn't the same Merrill Lynch.
Something had gone wrong.
Something had shifted.
Did he say that to you?
Um...
No, I didn't say it to me directly.
I don't know if I could sort of feel it.
I mean, even conversations with other people
and make a piece of it together is that...
You know, it's how he felt.
I mean, he was always loyal to Merrill Lynch
because that's what he made his mark.
Yep.
It was just kind of heartbreaking for him
to see Merrill Lynch fail.
Um...
Okay, so that August 2007,
Anshu calls
uh, convinces Bill to come back
and work as a consultant
on one condition,
which is that he doesn't want anyone to report to him.
Anshu agrees.
Um...
Anshu tells someone who he's having lunch with
there's one thing he learned from Edson
and that's when the shit hits the fan.
There's one person you want to stand beside you
and that's Bill Brooksman.
Yeah.
Um...
So back they move, Bill and your mom
move to London.
Uh, the girls and you stay in the States.
Um...
And he starts advising Anshu
on how to deal with some of the crises he's facing.
One of them immediately is mortgage IT,
which is this shitty mortgage company
Deutsche Bank had bought the previous year
like the absolute peak of the mortgage market
trying to like get stuff that they could feed into
the securitization and CDO machine.
Okay.
And Bill...
Leverage your heavily in debt?
Well, it's just like making bad mortgage loans
to like subprime customers basically.
Is it predatory?
I don't know if it's predatory.
It was certainly the...
It was definitely making...
It was churning up very risky mortgages
on kind of false pretenses
and yeah, I guess predatory is probably not a
bad word to describe it.
Um...
So he came in to manage this or to...
Well, he came in to advise Anshu on it
and the advice he provided was that...
Was this like a benchmark
or a trigger warning or something for a...
What's the word?
It's a red flag for things to come
and nobody sort of...
Nobody took this as a...
Well, no, I mean at this point things are going pretty bad
pretty quick.
Yeah, okay.
We're 2007?
No.
Yeah, this is like fall of 2007.
Okay.
And keep in mind just as we're going through this,
you're getting...
It's a marker for things to come.
Yeah, but don't think about this in such a literary way
because, you know,
as a genius literature writer
as I am,
you're not...
Yes.
Articulate too.
Well done.
Yes.
You're not getting like...
I know.
You're not getting a feel for it
because I'm jumping around.
Sure.
And these otherwise will be here.
Yeah, I'm just curious if you're using this
as like a marker for what's going on.
No, I'm using this actually as an indication
of a real, like,
weighing in on something in a very practical way.
And basically this business
that they had just spent half a billion dollars
on months earlier
is now, according to Bill, worthless.
Like literally not worth anything.
And so what do you do with that?
One option is,
at the end of the year,
you write it off entirely
and acknowledge it's worth zero.
But that means you have to take a huge loss
and account on the loss anyway.
That would mean you've recognized
and you basically take...
Whatever you spent on it,
you're taking that as a loss now.
If it's really worth zero.
In addition to being bad financially,
this is like really embarrassing.
Sure.
So Bill comes up with a different solution,
which is that it can basically hover in place
and not do any more risky loans,
only do good loans,
and that will kind of allow them to be able
to move forward without actually acknowledging
how bad their investment was.
So it's kind of a graceful way.
I mean, saying it's kind of paper things over,
but not in like a bad way.
It's just like...
So he comes back full-time in 2008.
He's got his obscure title,
which is head of capital and risk optimization
for the investment bank.
And so despite the obscure title,
you know, everyone knew
if he reported directly to Anshu,
and Anshu like deeply valued his opinion.
And Anshu could show that
for all the cowboys we have,
we also have Bill,
the former colleague said.
He starts up weekly risk management meetings,
which hadn't existed.
He starts like really just like looking
around these businesses,
looking, trying to understand them.
And, you know, seeing a lot of problems
and trying to slowly but surely clean them up.
And this is right as the financial crisis
is hitting in Deutsche Bank,
as you probably know,
is actually a big winner in the crisis,
partly because they had, you know,
they were shorting.
There's some short all these CDOs,
which they had actually helped manufacture.
And so they were,
and playing both sides of this,
and it was very profitable for them.
And that came from that Deutsche Bank guy
that made quite a good...
Yeah.
So Greg Lippmann is who you're thinking of,
who was kind of immortalized in the Big Short.
You're in Big Short.
Okay.
Okay, we're just going to pause this for a sec and...
Are you feeling tired?
I'm feeling good.
I mean, this is weird.
Yeah.
So much.
So cool.
It's intense.
Yeah, it's intense.
And it's like...
Because you kind of have to go
open everything down.
Yeah.
And also, like...
I mean, I'm telling you everything,
but I'm also trying to, like...
Be nice to us and this stuff.
Not really.
I'm just telling you, I just...
I don't want to let you hear this from anyone else.
Yeah, but...
For sure.
That's...
That's a very good way.
It'll be worse.
Absolutely.
That's why I'm doing this.
Yeah.
It's just...
The point being, not that I'm not telling you.
It's intense.
And I'm just...
I'm aware of it.
And also, cognizant of that...
What is on my computer screen right now?
It's an obvious...
The book is going to go through a zillion revisions
and changes and edits and restructures
and things like that.
So this is all...
It's all in flux, you know?
And so he's hearing it now.
You're hearing it now.
Sorry?
Yeah, let's see.
You ready?
Actually, you know what?
I'm going to drop this with a scoop of steamer.
Greg Lippmann.
Something Lippmann.
Yeah, so Deutsche Bank was creating these CDOs
and short-selling their own...
their own CDOs.
Did you pull that thing?
Yeah.
So they were creating packaging CDOs
and short-selling them?
So this is where Fred DePaul's loft came in.
They would use...
So you take...
So do you want me to just explain this as if you're an idiot?
Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah.
So...
Okay, so you take a mortgage.
Right.
Take a bunch of it, which is...
Package that together into a mortgage security.
Sure.
You then take a bunch of mortgage securities.
Right.
Mush them together and then like shop them up
depending on their risk.
Conscious.
Yeah, very good.
I told you I was going to tell you like you're an idiot
even though you're not an idiot.
So the...
And those are CDOs, right?
Right.
You then use credit default swaps.
CDS, which are insurance contracts essentially
to bet against those CDOs.
Right.
And so Deutsche Bank on the one hand
was taking all these mortgages,
some of which they were producing through mortgage IT
that's coming from what they bought.
Oh, okay.
Packaging those into mortgage-backed securities,
into CDOs, which Greg Lipman's squad was selling
to dummies all over the world.
Right.
And then simultaneously betting against those very CDOs.
Which is the short sell.
So they not only are both selling something bad
and betting that they're going to fail,
but they also kind of have inside knowledge
of what's going to do well and what's not going to do well
because they're fucking mortgages.
Sure.
So...
Yeah.
Well, they not only packed them, they originated them.
They were, because of mortgage IT,
they're actually producing these mortgages
because they know every step of the process.
I didn't realize that mortgage IT was the conduit.
Well, it was just part of it.
I mean, I didn't even actually realize that myself
until recently when I was going through
the huge settlement they had, Deutsche Bank had,
which was last year or the year before last.
And it goes, the Justice Department itself,
just goes in great detail to the role,
the fraudulent role that mortgage IT played.
And so, well, we'll get to this later,
but that's one of the things,
I don't know this, I'm just speculating,
but it's possible that your dad,
given the advice that he had given to Anchu
about that business and saying,
don't shut it down, keep it going
so we don't need to recognize that big loss.
It's not impossible that that was
like a little bit bothersome to people.
Right.
I don't know that, though, that's just pure speculation.
So, okay, crisis ends.
To not bring mortgage IT to light
or to sort of give mortgage IT to the past?
No, it gave it a, yeah, to give it a pass.
They gave it like another lease on life.
They allowed it to continue operating for a while.
Again, I'm not making much of that
because I don't really know, but it's...
That's an interesting idea.
I mean, with the benefit of hindsight,
that wasn't the best plan.
Right.
What they came up with, hindsight's 20-20.
Okay, so this is where, starting around 2010,
Deutsche Bank, it's big decline begins.
So, it survived the crisis better than most
because Greg Litman and his ilk
were making billions of dollars
short in the mortgage market.
And Deutsche Bank executives,
primarily Anchu and Joe Ackerman,
mistook their relative success during the crisis
as a sign that they were just in the clear.
And they step on the gas.
And Anchu is kind of losing touch with reality.
It seems like according to a bunch of people
who worked with him.
And also, they are...
The so-called piranhas around Anchu
are, no one is paying any attention to them.
So, that includes Christian Bittar,
who is the LIBOR trader.
It includes...
Call him, can I...
Be patient.
It includes the tax trades that they were doing
for renaissance.
The basket options.
The basket options are good.
And it includes...
It includes Monty Deposky.
And Kelly Faisola.
Good.
And yeah, it includes these crazed trading floors
that Colin Fan is presiding over.
So, here's one thing.
This is one of the most interesting things
I think I've found in my reporting.
It's just an anecdote, but it's a telling one.
So, in...
I'm trying to figure out exactly the date here.
I think 2010.
Let's give it a take, 2010.
There was a trader, a whole group of traders, actually,
in their bond traders.
And they were trading on mortgages.
But this was after the crisis.
So, they were actually betting,
whereas Deutsche Bank had made this big short bet
against the housing market.
The exposition?
This was the opposite.
So, they were now betting on the housing market
to recover.
And this guy's name is Troy Dixon.
He's like a young guy.
And it had a whole group that they were making
a very big, like multi-billion dollar bet
the housing market was going to come back to life
in a big way, which is fine.
But the bets were really, really big.
And so, risk managers started getting very worried.
How big?
Billions.
And the risk management team in the investment bank
didn't have anywhere to go.
No one would listen to their concerns.
So, they went to your dad.
And Bill took a look at...
The risk guys had basically compiled a dossier
of all this stuff.
And so, Bill started going through the dossier
and agreed that what they were showing
him did not look good.
It looked like this is just like a gigantic risk.
So, he went to talk to Troy Dixon's group.
And Dixon was like, fuck you old man.
I'm not going to...
Like, who are you?
And this went back and forth.
They fought.
Bill went back to the risk managers and said
he'd receive a strong pushback, that's a quote,
from above in the efforts to rein Dixon in.
Dixon kept...
Or Bill kept pushing.
Dixon kept getting angry.
And without any success, Bill did not manage to corral.
And he could tell that he was pissing Troy Dixon off.
Pissing off his whole group.
And so, he tried to patch those up.
And he invited Dixon and about 10 other traders
from that desk out to dinner.
It was an Italian restaurant in Tribeca.
Large candlelit table.
Floral tapestries on the wall.
Okay.
So, you went there?
Yeah.
So, dinner gets off to an awkward start.
And Bill and Troy are still bickering about the wisdom
of these trades.
And neither of them would drop.
And Dixon's crew, it's a little posse,
is around the hill like kind of snickering at your dad.
Snickering at my dad.
Snickering.
That he's out of his depth.
He doesn't understand this stuff.
Which is crazy.
Does your father is out of his depth?
They don't know who...
He wasn't out of their depth.
These guys are like young, obnoxious.
Yeah, they thought right down.
They thought they were laughing at him.
They were starting to.
Anyway, they stopped talking about this trades
and there's a conversation with me,
and there's something else.
And I don't know.
I think I'm going to be asking you at one point.
Do you know who Jerry Sundusky is?
Did I ask you that?
Yeah, it's the guy that was molesting people
in the showers or something.
He was a former college,
Penn College football coach.
Yeah.
Or Penn State College football coach.
Or he knew about the other guy.
Right?
There wasn't a documentary.
Yeah, no, that's Joe Paterno.
He's the guy who...
Now, how is this relevant?
You'll see.
Oh, right, because you didn't know who he was.
Maybe I've told you some of this before.
Yeah, and I was texting him for a long time
trying to say,
well, I didn't even know who the guy was
until he heard his name.
Yeah, it's fair enough.
Bill had never heard of the guy.
He had just write them a sentence
to at least 30 years in prison
for child molestation.
And someone at the table remarked that
child molesters in for a tough time in prison.
And your dad said,
why?
And the traitors looked at each other.
This dude for real.
And someone says,
finally, you see molested boys.
So?
Why?
Why is that reason for a tough time?
And Bill did not get that child molesters
were like the most hated people in prison.
This is like fair enough.
Kept asking questions.
Okay.
Why?
And once again, the snickering starts up.
They're just fucking laughing at him.
One of them described it as this old man was clueless.
Okay.
Uh, end of the meal.
Bill picks up the tab and just bolts.
He's like, doesn't even really say goodbye.
He just heads straight for the subway.
And Troy Dixon and his buddies go back to the bar,
go back to a bar,
and they just spend the night laughing
about how this weird guy,
like didn't know that Jerry Sandusky doesn't understand prison.
And then they went back to work.
Fuck these guys.
What were they?
Who cares?
Well, they were...
They were wrong anyway.
My dad was right.
This is...
And he cares if you didn't fucking Jerry Sandusky.
I didn't know who he was either.
And my dad isn't really up to what's going on in the prison world.
But I'm pretty sure he was trying to figure out
why they're talking about this.
I mean, I'm sure if he said to my dad,
at any point in time,
a child molester would have trouble in prison,
he would understand that.
That's not something that was over his head.
But at this, probably the context of this meeting,
if this is true what they say,
he could be either,
he's trying to fuck with them
or get a read on them,
saying why, why, why, over and over
to see how deeply, deeply moronic these people are
to continue this line of questioning,
to see why he would perceive them to be...
Their responses to his why
is how he reads other people.
My dad was here in the room.
And he says,
my dad was here in the room
and he says,
why do you want quite an obvious question?
He's got to get a read on you.
He's not actually asking why.
Like, the sky's blue, why?
He's trying to figure out how you perceive it
and what you're...
He's trying to get some time
to make up his mind about you
and he's giving you something to talk about.
I think he's pretty much made up his mind
before he went out to dinner with these guys.
He did not like them.
And I'm not sure that was bad on his part.
There's very...
My read on this, though,
is just putting aside what Bill's intent was.
The reality is that these...
It was like a generational shift
going on in Wall Street
and the guys who had grown up
viewing derivatives as casino instruments
were on the rise
and guys like Bill who had grown up
viewing them primarily as hedging devices
and client-centric devices
were on the way out
and the young guys didn't have any respect
for the slightly older guys.
That makes sense.
But in the anecdote,
it seems like the takeaway from it
is that my dad was out of touch.
No, that's not...
Because if you're saying,
why, why, why...
Trust me, Val, that's not...
Maybe I'm...
Well, this is just the danger of doing it this way.
If I read it, I'm sure...
This is kind of a sad moment for Bill.
Like, there's...
Why?
Because you think he's realizing he's out of touch?
He's realizing that there's been a generational shift.
But there's a paradox here
because yes, he's maybe out of touch
with what's going on in current events,
but he's obviously very much in touch
because he's trying to rein in these idiots
to stop doing something different.
Dixon's trades blow up,
cost Deutsche Bank half a billion dollars,
and federal regulators start investigating.
So that was totally right.
He has the last laugh,
but it's just not a very funny laugh
because people aren't listening.
And this is a pattern that's about to repeat itself
over and over and over again.
Because people stop listening to him.
To this old man from a different era.
That makes sense.
So you think he felt he was out of touch
and he didn't know how to rein in these fools?
He didn't know how to rein them in,
just no one would listen to him.
But he didn't have the backing necessary?
I mean, but he had the power of Deutsche Bank behind him.
How could they not rein in Troy Dixon
and his crew of fucking morons?
They weren't morons.
They were just making a very big, risky bet.
It sounded pretty moronic to me.
So, one of the lessons here
that I've picked up on...
Sorry, I'm just upset someone's fucking with my dad.
No, I get it, man.
And that's the direction you're supposed to have.
It's a reader you're supposed to have.
Yeah.
They're being...
Where you going?
I'm just going to put this to charge
and have a proper cigarette.
One of the big takeaways I have
about your dad and his role as a bank
is that your dad is like a good man.
He's an honest man,
makes mistakes like we all do,
but he's a good human being.
But one of the things that
there's no way it was not bothering him
is that his role was changed.
With Edson, he was like the right-hand man
who was just
an integral part of the kind of ecosystem,
the functioning.
He was the super ego to Edson's id.
In the second round at Deutsche Bank,
he's not bad.
There is no need for a super ego.
This bank is out of control.
Nobody's listening to him.
And there is...
No one wants to hear bad news anymore.
No one wants someone to say no.
They think they're so smart.
They just surfed through the financial crisis.
The greatest disruption since the 1920's
or 1930's.
They don't need
Dr. Nell.
Right.
Okay.
Anchi becomes CEO.
In 2012.
Co-CEO.
So the hubris has taken over.
The hubris has taken over.
Okay.
Anchi is one of his main priorities.
It's because they got lucky.
They thought they were smarter than everyone else.
One of the chapters right now is titled
Luck vs. Skill.
Hey.
Good.
I just predicted that.
Interesting.
Okay.
Or there while you just directed me toward that.
Interesting.
Did I just say that was...
We got that on camera.
I just said
without knowing anything about what he was saying
that this bank was lucky
but they thought that they were smarter than everyone else.
David said the next title of the chapter
is Luck vs. Skill.
So that's good.
So as a reader
this is good.
It's interesting.
I just want to point that out.
We got it.
Saved your posterity on that.
Yeah.
On my iPhone.
Interesting.
Okay.
So here comes an incident that
you know a bit about
but I think you'll learn a little bit more.
So Anchi
takes over as CEO
and wants to fill the place with his loyalists.
Right.
Your dad is a loyalist
or at least that's how he comes to perceive some.
And so he puts your dad up
for the job of chief risk officer.
And he tells Bill
that it's a perfect fit.
Like he gets risk management better than anyone else
on to trust him.
And it's like a big leap up.
He'll go on the Vorstand
which is the management committee
which is like this
rarefied board that previously
had been off-limits to anyone who wasn't German.
And it's a big jump up.
His friends congratulate him.
He and Michael Morandi
are just like weird joke
where Morandi is called monkey business.
Okay.
Which is Moran,
they would like go out to dinner together
and like clumsily hit on waitresses
and whoever other,
whatever other women were around
and like,
not they're going to do anything
but just like,
he's been around.
And so Morandi,
when he learned that Bill
has been put up for this very important job,
laments that there will be no more monkey business.
And Deutsche Bank,
after announcing this to the world,
decides that maybe it would be a good idea
to check with the German regulators,
Bafen,
over whether this is okay.
Because Bafen actually has veto power over this.
Okay.
And Bafen's students over this
for a little while.
Who says to suggest Bafen?
Deutsche Bank has to submit this
to Bafen's approval.
They have to.
The reasons that remain unclear,
they decided it would be smart to announce the job
before they'd actually sought
or received approval from the regulators.
Okay.
Not smart.
No.
Bafen already was very troubled but on to
and concerned about his recklessness
and his lack of management savvy
and perceived on to as putting into
arguably the most important job in the bank,
Chief Risk Officer,
one of his kind of flak flunkies.
So they consider my dad a flunky to answer?
Yes.
They perceive that way.
What about Ackerman?
Well, Ackerman's gone at this point.
Oh.
He stepped down.
So, in fact,
Bill wonders to his friend,
so Bafen rejects it.
It's a very embarrassing situation for him.
He's been given this big promotion.
Wait, we're in 2012.
In 2012.
Okay.
He gets this big promotion,
huge promotion.
It's all like newspapers write stories about it.
The FT did a lot on it.
They write the journal too.
And then it gets rescinded.
Right.
And so Bill wonders to his friends and colleagues
that he speculates that perhaps he was just
a victim of sabotage.
And maybe Ackerman had basically
stabbed him in the back with the regulators
because he wanted,
Ackerman wanted to hurt Anshu.
In any case,
he'd been receiving all these congrats
and throwing emails and phone calls all month
and now he has to go back to people over and over
and explain that the job has been revoked.
Okay.
Easy come, easy go,
was the voicemail he left for his mother.
And he sounds nonchalant,
but when Pete, his brother,
listens...
Peter.
I call him Peter.
It's Peter.
No one calls him Peter.
It's written Peter.
I'm just reading with notches.
Okay.
When Peter listens to the message,
you can tell that he says
there's no concealing the hurt in his voice.
Really?
I don't know.
I remember he told me.
It didn't seem...
I don't think that is what he told you.
We'll get to that in a second.
Oh.
I mean, when he told me,
I didn't take up any...
Well, he didn't...
We'll get to it.
He told you an email.
Sorry?
He told you in an email how he felt.
So we'll get to that in a second.
No, he told me over dinner.
We'll get to it in a second.
I'll read it to you.
He told Sam
that he felt insulted.
He told John Bright
the particle physicist from Merrill
that he knew he should be relieved.
But once I quote...
But once I started thinking about the job,
I liked it.
Miranda joked,
we're back in the monkey business.
Bill laughed and looked sad.
And then, at the end of the year,
this pattern defeated itself
because Bill was put up for another senior job
running the non-core unit at Deutsche Bank.
And once again,
Boppen shot it down after it had been announced.
So this is around the time that Bill,
as a consolation prize,
gets put on DBTCA's board.
So we've got a bunch of DBTCA history here.
And he felt he was being set up now at this point.
He didn't really feel he was being set up.
He felt like he needed to...
There was some concern over him feeling set up
for what was about to happen at Deutsche Bank
according to the therapist.
I don't think that's quite right.
There's to be a fall guy, in a sense.
I think he...
Because he saw what was coming.
I don't think he saw what was coming.
I think he viewed...
What do you mean there's the DOJ investigations?
We'll get there. Don't worry. I promise you.
There's a DOJ investigation involved in your dad?
You're the one that told me that.
I'm kidding, man. God!
Monty, okay.
Just be patient.
Allow me my narrative pasting.
So, what we do know about Bill at that point
is that he views...
Allow me my narrative pasting.
He feels like
he is kind of being wedged into a doubly.
He doesn't really want,
but he's just been publicly humiliated twice.
Yeah.
And this is kind of face-saving
and it's some way to get a little bit of lost status back.
Yeah, that's right.
He's not getting...
I mean, he's getting paid a lot by human standards,
but not by bankers.
It's an extra hundred grand.
So, around that time,
Bill and
Aala reconnect with Scott Mitchell.
Do you know Scott Mitchell?
Yeah, he's come a few times.
He's Edson's son.
Right.
And they hadn't seen each other in a decade,
but in 2012,
Scott happened to sit down for lunch
or something with Anshu.
Anshu pushed the two of them to...
pushed the Mitchell and Brooks McClanns
to like...
because they'd been...
there's a huge following up
because Bill and Aala had supported...
Estelle.
Estelle, which, you know,
not surprisingly,
Susan and her kids
viewed as a betrayal.
Right.
And Scott is...
both Bill and Scott
agree to a meeting.
They book reservations for lunch
and then they keep...
each of them keeps canceling.
Right.
And finally,
they get thanks to some product
from Bill's assistant.
They finally, like, plan for lunch.
And they go to a Japanese restaurant
in Union Square, 15 East.
And Alessa went to dinner.
Okay.
And so did Scott's sister.
So it was Bill, Alessa, Scott,
and Scott's sister, Ella.
Okay.
12 years since they'd seen each other.
And Scott, at this point,
is like a spitting image of Edson.
And Alessa blurts out
the moment they see him.
He's Edson.
Holy shit.
Scott, who's a little bit drunk
because he had been so nervous
and would, like, just drink a bunch
before dinner.
You know, sitting down,
they're both...
Scott's sweating profusely.
And your dad ordered some nice wine.
The more they drank,
the more things calmed down,
the more fun they're having.
Scott does his...
his arm show impersonation.
You are smarter than hell and talented.
How do we get you up to your metrics?
Scott, by the way, is a used car salesman
at that point.
That's a horrible accent, isn't it?
No, that's good.
Bill loves it.
Laughing.
They're bantering about banking.
Dinner ends.
And Alessa takes the sister aside.
The Scott's sister aside and says,
this is him looking at pointing
at your dad's direction.
I haven't seen my father like this
since Edson.
End of that summer, Bill,
and I'll invite Scott up to the house in Brooklyn.
I spent the day drinking and reminiscing.
And Bill joked about how he dodged a bullet
by not getting the chief risk officer job.
He tells Scott that he's about to retire,
thinking about retiring for a final time.
He keeps saying how much he misses Edson.
And he keeps asking Scott for a state planning advice.
For a state planning advice.
Yes, Scott was mystified by that because...
2012?
This is summer 2012.
Scott asked Bill,
what would have happened if with Deutsche,
Edson hadn't died?
It would be a better worship.
We would have made less money during the boom,
but we would have lost less money
during the bust, he said.
Hmm.
February 2013,
annual bonuses get handed out.
Bill asks Anchu for a private meeting.
Tells Anchu that he's going to retire again.
He's tired, he's deflated.
He just wants it out.
Anchu is laid,
there's a million different fires burning inside Deutsche Bank right then.
He convinces your dad to stick around
for several more months.
The...
And there's like everywhere you look,
there's scandals, everything,
all the shoes sitting in the family right now.
Well,
I mean, today it's a bit worse.
I mean, where were the scandals at the time?
There were a lot of scandals.
Libor?
Libor,
Russian merit trading was just bubbling up.
Okay.
There was a tally that the bank did
that identified...
I'm trying to find this number.
The stress test,
or before the stress test?
The stress test was beginning the problem.
There were,
in the first eight months of 2013,
there were 5,777 requests
for information from regulators,
which is about one per hour
on average,
and that's a very, very bad sign.
Okay.
There's...
The net tech, basket trees.
Yeah, the Fed is furious,
the CFTC is furious,
the SEC is investigating.
So it's bubbling.
Justice Department is starting
a bunch of investigations.
It's bubbling at this point.
It hasn't really come to fruition.
It's...
their offices are being raided by police.
Yeah, it's pretty bad.
It's pretty bad.
But you're right, it does get worse.
So...
Oh, look.
We switched back to Val for a second.
Oh, joy.
Val possessed a man of charisma,
and he charmed his way into recording studios
and meetings with music industry professionals.
His catalogue of the songs expanded.
He got gigs.
It's less lonely with an audience, he told me.
Did you see that?
Yep.
2008, Urban Plaza.
You meet Jenny,
selling merchandise up front.
Yeah.
Start dating, she's from New York.
Moved to London,
two bedroom flat in Pentishtown.
Yeah.
Good.
Your parents paid the rent
and distributed roughly 50 grand a year.
Is that right?
It was...
The rent?
I mean, including the rent?
No, not including the rent.
Oh, yeah, it's about $50,000.
I'm noting that
you really wanted your dad to respect
and that you want to please your dad
because that's normal.
Of course.
Yeah, and it's nothing bad.
But he also viewed it as the more...
the more he viewed you as responsible,
the more he would trust you.
And there was...
I'm mentioning this...
I think this was...
What's the film producer again?
What's his name?
Lawrence.
No.
Jerecki.
So you told Jerecki...
I guess I'm also trying to...
So you propose investment from your dad
into Jerecki's business.
And you say to Jerecki?
I guess I'm also trying to prove to him
that I can make sound and confident choices with money.
Yeah, I know this was a...
David Gran.
I was trying to put Jerecki with David Gran
for his other book before it was made into...
Velocity of Z.
So I was trying to put those two together
and then Jerecki wanted something about this...
You have the email, right?
It should all be in that email.
I've got the email.
And I was trying to put my dad in the middle too.
But yeah, it sounds about right.
I mean, close enough.
So we begin to hear a little bit
about your dad's view of you and money.
Okay.
Enjoy, yes.
You're nuts.
Earn more...
Sorry.
You're nuts.
Earn some money, he told you.
When you're asked for your stipend to be increased.
Yes.
Another time your allowance was frittered away somehow
and you...
He moved on to a weekly payment plan instead of a monthly.
Yeah, that was a terrible idea.
And I know that Bill, like, was pretty short with you sometimes.
Yeah.
If you meant to annoy, you succeeded.
I told you I'm on occasion.
I'm not sure you're gonna like this part.
I'm noting that you had an unkempt beard
and while your shoulder length hair was mingy on the sides,
the top was as bald as a coot.
It's not that bald.
It's pretty fucking tall.
I mean, come on.
There's still some...
That's about as bald as a coot.
Some strands.
Is that what you're gonna call that?
Some strands left.
I'm saying that your clothes were old and tattered
and your friends didn't think they were very stylish.
Quote, he looked like a right tramp.
One of your...
Who was this?
This was Simon Saren.
Simon said that a fucker.
Okay.
He said you push, push, push some more.
That friends could tell that you had money,
they didn't quite know where it came from.
You would say your mom was an artist
and your dad was a math guy,
something about algorithms.
I never said that.
Well, that sounds about right.
I said my dad was a banker.
He was a math guy.
I mean, he was a math guy.
That's not inaccurate.
It was just vague.
Why would I hide that he's a banker?
Well, that was actually interesting.
I talked to Simon about that.
I asked him that very question.
And he said it's just not like a good look in London
at that point to be...
A banker's son?
Yeah.
Not a good look.
Anyway, he told me a story.
It sounds like Simon created his own sort of story.
This is kind of going to hurt your street cred.
Oh, my street cred.
Don't have street cred.
Okay.
Well, not for long.
So Simon agreed to do like a photo shoot
for a Bikini Roulette Army cover, album cover.
Agreed.
Or offered or whatever.
Okay.
And what he offered was to help make over your wardrobe
and get proper clothes for this.
Right.
And he says that you suggested they go to Harrod's.
He said bloody hell and took you to Camden Market.
That's right.
That's true.
I didn't know.
I thought Harrod's had some cool shit.
What's wrong with Harrod's?
I don't know, man.
It's not as cool as Camden Market,
but Harrod's still nice.
If I had a choice between Harrod's and Camden Market,
would you go to Harrod's or Camden Market?
It depends what look that I try to fill off.
I wouldn't go to either, to be honest.
I would go to the Gap.
To the Gap.
So that's a sign of my fashion sense.
Okay.
So I'm telling the story of how you and Beth met.
Yes.
At a party in 2011.
She saw you across the room.
There was something magnetic about you.
She needed to know who this cocky guy was.
So sweet.
She walked over and started talking.
She's captivated, so confident, so brash, so American.
Come on, dear.
Cheesy.
You made a crack about how she looked just like Patty Boyd.
She knew who Patty Boyd was,
but she was very flattered and she got on and googled it.
And by the following spring, so we're in 2012 now,
Jenny's had a picture and you and Beth are living together.
Yes.
She realized that you were a hoarder.
A hoarder.
Years worth of junk.
Ticket stubs, tattered artwork, both clothes.
Occupying every drawer and shelf in the apartment.
What?
That's not true at all.
No?
That's maybe for books.
I kept all these books, but I threw a lot of shit away.
Okay.
I need to see it.
Wow.
Excuse me.
No.
Wow.
Amazing.
I did not throw...
There were some things I did not throw away.
I reluctantly corroborate.
But not a hoarder.
Because images...
It's a businessman.
When I think of a hoarder, I see that images on television with people stacking up piles
in these papers.
That's not...
Well, we can set up.
I mean, I don't know.
It's a majority.
I mean, it's not a compliment.
He's absolutely a hoarder, isn't he?
You're not.
Thank you.
I'm highly confident in the accuracy of that description.
She's not exaggerating.
Yeah.
Good.
Here you go, buddy.
I'm just trying to find another pack of cigarettes.
Here it is.
He's actually a very hoarder.
He's got, like, city tickets.
But he doesn't have stacks of newspapers.
Yeah.
He keeps every cinema ticket, every note.
It's amazing.
Well, hey, it's a good way to jog your memory.
It's a very good way.
Yeah.
It's a good way.
She says it is fondly, by the way.
Okay.
She wanted to do things like cook dinner and go out on dates and explore London in the
daylight with her boyfriend.
Believe it or not, your sleeping habits were not conducive to that, which is maybe a little
frustrating to her.
One of the things that surprised her about you was that you, at first glance, came across
to her as this brash, charismatic, hyper-confident American.
And I think maybe I've told you about this.
She found you to be extremely anxious, sometimes tongue-tied, by anxiety before performances.
And she gave me a specific example of a performance at the 100 Club on Oxford Street, where you
wrapped up your set, then shouted into the microphone, someone needs to call me an ambulance.
And the crowd looked at you silently, not clear, or not sure if you were serious or not.
And then you fled offstage.
And Beth, rushed backstage, thinking you were having some sort of breakdown, can't find
you, spent a while exploring the labby runth of, I guess, is that club's underground area.
And eventually, leaves me, she can't find you.
And there, on the sidewalk, you're sitting there sweating, panicked, and unable to speak,
she says.
And I thought I was going to die.
Why?
Lane, Lane Hines was playing with me, and Lane had a party the night before.
So, well, actually, Lane wasn't scheduled to play with you, I was supposed to play alone,
but we went to Lane's house, we had a party, we were up all night, a lot of cocaine, a lot
of cocaine.
And we did not sleep.
And then sometime around 7am, he said, Lane, why don't you join me on stage?
He's like, OK, it's cocaine conversation.
And then we just decided not to sleep and stay up to the show.
So we get to the hunter club, like, at night, cooked up out of our heads with the guitars.
And then I start performing, and I was so exhausted, and then not only the anxiety from
playing mixed with the cocaine, mixed with the no sleep, I thought I was going to die
at the last song.
Like, I was singing.
I didn't think I was going to finish the song.
And so I thought I was going to fall right off the fucking stage and die.
So he said, call me an ambulance.
And I was dead serious.
I thought I was going to die.
So I had to go outside and catch my breath and calm down and relax.
It's terrible.
Well, that matches up pretty well.
Yeah.
That's your perspective.
I've now got both perspectives of them.
They mesh.
So you and Bill go to Wimbledon.
June 2013, lovely picture of you guys together there.
Faded Giants hat that couldn't corral your long hair.
Half button denim shirt that exposed your chest.
Your bearded face projecting too cool for school detachment.
You at one point asked Bill, asked your dad, say, tell me about work, and he didn't answer.
I'm noting, let's say, going into that suicide at the Swiss insurance company where Ackerman
had gone on to.
The double murder suicide?
No.
No, that's a different one.
This is the one in fall of 2013, and your dad and some of his friends afterwards are
emailing about this one and saying it doesn't look too good for Ackerman because this guy
had just hung himself and left a suicide note that blamed Ackerman for putting too much
pressure on him.
Did it?
Yeah.
I didn't know this.
That's public.
I didn't know that.
What did they not say?
Do you have it in there?
I don't.
Ackerman then resigned from that company and said, I have reason to believe that the families
of the opinion that I should take my share of responsibility.
He later told someone that a certain amount of pressure or occasional factual criticism
were perfectly normal in such positions.
They did not even begin to justify suicide.
I remember this.
Yes.
Okay.
The wife had done a campaign.
The wife blamed him.
Yes.
Okay.
So Bill retires.
His official last day of work is August 31st.
You asked him why he was quitting, and he says, quote, there is really no logical next
step for me at DB after board appointment fell through, which is fine.
I lasted a lot longer than I thought I would.
Anshu hosts a lunch for him with about a dozen people.
He gave a little speech, toasted Bill for his work.
Afterwards Bill, you welcome to thank him.
It's a very nice thing.
You know it.
Anshu responds, you've made a very important contribution to this institution and to many
lives.
Thanks.
Let's stay in touch.
Would you kind of stiffen a slightly distant tone?
Well, it's meant for, you know, it's not like a personal note.
No, it was.
These are personal emails.
Oh, that's all I can say.
He turns 58.
Oh, this is the email I sent you?
This is stuff I've gotten from you, yeah.
That I sent you?
Okay.
The only person who's been sending me Bill Brooksman's emails.
Right.
I just, for never mind.
Sorry.
They plan to stay in London another year and do some traveling.
I'm getting into just some of that.
Oh, noting that they made plans to go to South Africa and then Iran the following spring of
2014.
Great.
Bill tries to learn a little French.
He takes some writing classes.
He prefers to get his driver's license, experiments in the kitchen.
He's enjoying being very lazy and unproductive.
He writes to a former colleague.
He finds himself drinking more and more.
Thanksgiving of 2013, he and his mom fly back to New York.
Bill goes to lunch with Saman Maj, who, you know, is net by this point a finance professor
at Yale.
And Bill complains that he's missing his job.
The mark is the adrenaline, the challenge.
He asks Saman, how do you manage it?
Don't you miss it?
And it, Maj says he's found fulfillment in academia and suggests that Bill finds something
to do with his life.
Instead, Bill remains very immersed, as you know, in DBTCA.
And it, which is engulfed in, like, rapidly expanding series of problems.
They don't even have a CFO.
They're kind of whitewashing these fed stress tests.
He pushes, as you know, your dad pushes a lot to, you know, take things more seriously
and, like, get up to speed.
That does not really seem to be working very well.
Like, no one seems to be taking it all that seriously.
And, okay, December 2013, you meet your parents for sushi.
And this is where we get into the U.S.
He asks you what your long-term plans are for all the music.
He says how much it would cost to, like, do it all.
And for a glorious moment, you think your dad's about to offer to bankroll all of them.
Instead, he asks how you'll support yourself when he's gone.
You ask, are you sick?
Well, I made a joke, too, because I didn't want him to think that I was giving a number to bankroll it.
So it's not exactly...
I'm not suggesting at all that you're like money broke.
No, I made a specific joke.
I said $1 billion, because I didn't want him to think that I was, like...
Anyway, it doesn't matter.
You say, are you sick?
He shakes his head.
Ola answers, your father is fine.
Right.
A week or two later, you and Beth go out to dinner with them.
That's when you give the Steve Miller band anthology and the record player, which Ola did not like.
There's a gospel choir singing in the restaurant.
Yeah, that's right.
Your dad had actually a really engaging conversation about pop music, which seemed out of character for him, but interesting.
Yeah.
At the end of the dinner, he hugged you.
This is an unusual display of physical affection and says, I love you very much.
Hand to a holiday card.
Enjoy the holidays here and we'll see you in January.
In front of the car, there is a picture of Daisy that Ola had drawn.
This little card is blue and white, except for the dog's red leash.
Huh.
Okay.
That month...
I didn't pick up on that.
Is that right?
Take a look.
Yeah, I did see it again.
It's the only thing that stands out in the card is the red leash.
It does, right?
Yep.
Do you have it?
Yeah, I send it to him.
I don't know if he sent it to me or if he showed it to me.
Yeah, he must have sent it to me.
I took a picture of it and emailed it to you.
Yeah.
Wow.
I didn't even miss that.
That's pretty quick.
Yeah.
Good catch.
So that month, one afternoon, Bill arranged to meet up with Martin Luft, who was his partner back in the olden days at Deutsche Bank,
the guy, the military guy.
Some people thought he was a special forces.
And they agreed to meet at Gales.
Gales, that big chain of little cafes and coffee shops in London.
Barely.
It was kind of a fixture in my neighborhood anyway.
And also in Chelsea.
And Bill shows up in his gym clothes.
He just came from the gym.
He's sweaty.
And so he's sitting in the crowded cafe reminiscing.
And Loat has been, he gave up on the banking industry and is kind of telling Bill about how he's just like happier than he's ever been in his life.
He's got like a small house now and he goes to pub quizzes and jogs and skis and just things are simpler.
Tries to get your dad enthusiastic about this new phase of his retirement.
And Loat can tell that Bill is just like dwelling on things.
And at one point he says to Loat that he's wrestling with a problem.
And he says the bank had done a trade with a client.
The client hadn't fully understood what he'd been getting into.
And now there's a big mess.
It sounded to Loat a lot like the Orange County.
Well, it sounded like that, but you're right.
That's very good.
This is three weeks before your dad kills himself.
He also says...
It could be why my dad asked for the Orange County memo again.
If this is looming on him.
Or it could be Monica DePasque.
Because that's really what this sounds like to me.
Bill asked Martin what he should do.
And Loat, who was not very good at reading people, could tell that Bill was like really upset.
And Loat had never forgotten a lesson that Bill had taught him back in their early days together.
There was a lesson that Reverend Jack had actually told Bill.
Which is that do write by other people, be honest with them, treat them ethically, things will work out in the end.
And so he told Bill that.
He said, I remember when I had a problem with this back in the early days of Deutsche.
This is what you told me and now I'm telling it to you.
And Bill looked at him, kind of stared off into the distance, didn't say anything.
And there's an awkward silence.
I think my father realizes his own...
It's the word fallibility in that sentence.
His own premature...
What's the word?
Juvenile understanding of morality.
I mean he recognizes his...
It's the word.
It's a perfect word.
It's escaping my mind.
Immature understanding of morality.
It's very do write by others and they will do write by you.
He's learning more and more is not true.
It's a lot more grayer than that.
I think it might be simpler.
I think his whole life is understanding that less, more and more.
He is the moral center of everything and he has always been.
And more he learns, especially after his father died, who was the...
Mr. Moralistic, the pillars of the family and everything else.
He realizes that this is a fallacy.
We're going to get into some of the stuff with his dad dying a little bit.
Just in my chronology.
I'm sure to hear Martin Lewis say that to him.
He sees his own hubris.
My take of...
It's really interesting.
My dad's not this deep.
I mean he's a very bright guy and he knows that something like this,
saying this is like putting a band-aid on a fucking...
Or maybe he's just deeply upset about whatever...
I mean, Loats take away from this.
A sword wound.
I think was that...
Do you get what I'm saying?
100% of what you're saying.
I'm not being dismissive when I say that.
It's really interesting.
I hadn't thought about that.
So off they go with the girls to Virgin Gorda.
But what were you going to say before you think...
I just think the simpler explanation, which isn't necessarily the right one,
is that...
But the one that was in my head is that...
Bill is really worried about a transaction or transaction
that the bank has done with a client that are now boomeranging back at them.
And he's worried about his culpability in that.
That's too simple.
Because what we know now is that McKaylee Faisola did this transaction.
Well, we don't know what's Monodiposki, by the way.
That's an assumption.
Well, I mean, what else could it be?
Look, we'll get into what Bill knew about Monodiposki.
Basket trades are over.
Library's over.
Well, in fact, hang on.
What else is going on?
No, they're not over.
Well, I mean...
No, hang on.
We can do this right now if you want.
In fact, the Monodiposki investigation was scheduled
to begin on Monday, January 27th.
Really?
Yes.
Monday, January 27th.
Yeah.
So what is that?
One day after your death?
It's the Monday.
Yeah, it's the day after.
Libor was not anywhere near done at that point.
In fact, what had happened with Libor is that a bunch of people had just been arrested
in the UK because of Libor.
Right.
And anyway, let's get...
We'll come back to that.
So you're...
Do you think that...
That means anything?
I think your dad was...
No, I mean, the investigation is starting on 27.
Do you see anything in that?
It's a hell of a coincidence.
It is, right?
They got into broken board.
But what we know is that Faisola handled this trade.
And my dad, we know for a fact that he went to Anchu...
Let's come back to that.
And he said no about this trade.
He said no.
And Faisola went around his back.
He went around my dad's back and ran Anchu's back.
He did not...
He did not go through the proper channels.
Faisola has a very different take on that.
And...
No shit.
He's under 16 fucking indictments from law.
And he's gonna...
Yeah, but that stuff is just nonsense.
It's not nonsense.
Well, because Italian...
I hear what you're saying.
Okay.
There's...
As long as I'm clear.
Okay.
You're clear.
But look, what we can stipulate here is that your dad killed himself.
Right?
We know that.
And we know that he was worried about stuff at work.
And so it's not a question of was he worried about stuff at work.
We know he was.
But you're saying he's worried about his own culpability.
And I'm saying...
I'm not saying that.
I'm saying...
Yeah, you just said that he was...
He expressed his worry about how culpable he was in whatever this trade may be.
And I'm saying that he's not culpable in anything, as we all know.
I'm not saying he's culpable.
I mean, looking back, again, hindsight, there's absolutely nothing putting him in any terrible
trades or any kind of money laundering schemes or basket trades.
I'm not saying he's culpable.
I'm saying he's worried he's culpable.
But he knows he's not culpable, because he knows he has done nothing wrong.
So that worries the paradox.
Well, we'll come back to that, because we know the way his psychologist...
What he told his psychologist and his doctor also.
Okay.
But we're going to come back to all of this.
I promise.
They go off to Virgin Gorda in the Caribbean.
They spend a couple of days at a resort.
And then go with...
During which, when Bill phones into a board meeting about problems with the Fed, then they
join Michael Morandy, his wife and some others, and the Morandy's 47-foot sailboat.
They swim.
They snorkel.
They drink.
They smoke.
They run up cigarettes.
They search boats.
They ask for a half-soaked cigarette.
They drink some more.
Your mom tries to convince Bill to buy a sailboat.
Bill kind of goes along with it.
New Year's Day, motorboat takes them to the airport.
Bill gets sick and pukes.
And at this time, a couple of your dad's friends who've been spending time with him started
looking, thinking that it was a little weird that they didn't...
They felt that they didn't know your dad that well.
They knew him.
He's a great friend, a loyal friend, like a brilliant, ethical, fascinating, but they
didn't know him.
They didn't know his emotions.
And some of this, I think, is probably just men being men, right?
Right.
This is something that more than one friend, very close friend, who I talked to said.
And they used words like, they didn't really know him.
Not an emotional level.
Yeah, but you know what?
Whatever.
It's just a bunch of bullshit.
Because everyone thinks they know someone.
And then when someone does something unexpected, like a suicide, you look back and think,
I never really knew the guy, because I didn't see that coming.
No, it's not that.
If somebody saw it coming, they could say, oh, I knew him well.
I saw it coming.
Fair enough.
Right?
No, I don't think it's quite that simple.
But fair enough.
I think it's quite, I think it is that simple.
They get back to London.
And they distance themselves from this person.
Oh, I didn't know this person, because I did not see this person.
They're not saying that in that context.
They're not saying, oh, I didn't see this person.
Of course, it's all in that context.
You're right.
I mean, I'm obviously talking to all these people.
Yes, in that context.
In the context of them having killed themselves a few weeks later.
Right.
But let's just leave it.
I hear what you're saying.
Okay.
Yeah.
Come back to London.
He tells Ola that they're going to New York for another DVD sale.
Board meeting.
They're going to do the wills.
He tells Ola that he has to meet with the feds when he's there.
That, I think, has been kind of mis-transposed.
And he actually meant meet with the fed.
Capital F.
Right.
Because he'd been having phone conversations with the fed.
Is this the Mark Stein stuff?
No.
That's not Mark Stein.
This is separate.
And this is, we'll come back to this.
So, I just told you, Monty Deposky has collapsed at this point.
Faisal, their criminal investigation is in Italy.
The Germans are about to start a big new investigation on Monday, January 27th.
Okay.
Friday, January 24th.
Anshu is in Davos partying.
The world is good.
My favorite line in the book is in this section.
And it describes the party that Deutsche Bank threw hours before your dad killed himself.
In Davos?
Yeah.
And I was there.
You were there?
Yeah.
With Anshu and his wife.
And it's a happy scene.
Anshu's wife really humanizes him.
Ackerman is there and making peace after this huge violent falling out.
Bald men's heads.
Bald men's heads shine with sweat.
Which I just obsessed with that line.
Party goes into the early hours of the following morning.
Is that your line?
Yeah, that's mine.
That's pretty good.
I thought that was Anshu's.
I figured it was quitting Anshu.
Okay.
A few hundred miles to the northwest.
Dance with sweat.
Bill and Alde go out to dinner.
I could improve on it just a little bit.
Bald heads men dance with sweat.
Bill and Alde go out to dinner.
It's a no.
And then for the final time he falls asleep.
And sorry, is that it again?
For the final time he falls asleep.
Okay.
Wait, what was the line before that?
I'm not reading it.
You didn't hear it.
There was no line before it as far as I thought.
Okay, can we take a break for a sec?
Yeah.
Okay.
This is in part one.
Yeah.
That was more an emotionally exhausting than I thought.
Okay.