So, she had a very, yeah, very small recital.
It's a big deal for her.
Of course it is, I know.
And she understands that when work comes up, I have to go.
But, you know, at the very least, what I should do,
like, you know, I should please go back.
And, you know, I got her a little something from L.A.
Oh, that's so cute.
I can catch her before she goes back to sleep.
But that's why I can't tell.
You know, I would love to come right now.
I'm seriously trying to catch her to the airport myself,
which I don't know if I'll make the flight,
but I at least want to make the effort to see if I can.
Okay, I see.
Well, if you don't,
you actually, once you're at the airport,
you're not too far from where we are.
Come here, like seriously.
Just come.
Oh, no, I appreciate that.
And then we're gonna have to, like, don't,
I mean, if you want, not, obviously if you want.
But yeah, there is actually traffic, traffic is back.
So, I don't know how long you've allowed yourself.
It's gonna be very close, unfortunately.
Well, okay.
Well, you know, you have a plan B.
It's easier, so.
At worst, I'll give you a call.
I'll tell you I'm stopping by, but.
No, seriously.
Yeah, do that.
You might not make it.
Sounds like you might not make it.
You know, right now I am sitting in a good bit of traffic
on the 405, so it may take a little while.
But I also wanted to tell you just about,
so we had a very good conversation with Val
and, you know, we got to learn some things
and he got to learn some things from us.
So, the other thing I also wanted to tell you,
which I told you on Sunday as well, you and Val,
is that there are some things that he may not be able
to tell you directly about.
I know you guys have a very open and honest relationship,
which is perfect.
I would want nothing less from both of you.
But there's some things that he's gonna talk to about us,
you know, with us and the things that he's interested in,
that you would not share with me.
Yeah, yeah, no, I understand.
Yeah, and that's just for everyone's protection.
That's mainly for you because if you know about it,
then you could become a witness and I don't want that.
You know, it's really, it's no danger to me
because it doesn't really affect me much,
but it's more like if you know about it too,
then if it's something that has to be testified, you know,
then when they ask, does anyone else know about it?
I think there's, oh yeah, I felt like, you know,
like, is it your girlfriend or is it wife?
Yes, I'm currently in this divorce proceeding, so.
Of course, yeah.
Yeah.
So anyway, so you know, I talk to my girlfriend
and then they say, okay, well, we need to subpoena her.
And then you have to be on the witness ban too
to answer questions, to validate some things.
And that's not good, that's not good for anyone.
Because your identity is out there and anyway, so.
I know, you can, oh, okay, no, no,
you can trust in me, I won't ask questions
and whatever he tells me, he tells me,
I won't torture him for that.
Of course, of course.
Okay.
And you have my number too, it's like,
what I was telling Val is that if you independently,
like say Val is out or something like that,
and you know, you think he says, oh hey,
I'm gonna go work with David,
you can call me at the, hey, you know,
is he okay, is he all right, and I'll tell you, of course,
like yeah, he's fine, he's safe.
And then if we decide to work together,
right now, I have to find something for him to do,
but it's nothing that I would directly
be working with him on, so.
Okay.
Anyway, we'll be on the witness ban.
He's a very talented man, he's got many talents.
Yes, I agree, I hear he's got a lot of talent
and lots of skills.
Yes, he's got a set, a wide range of skills.
Yeah, I know he's got a lot of talent.
As you do too, I'm sure.
No, not me, I've got a very limited number of skills
and unfortunately, I need help,
I need help from everyone to do the things we do,
so I appreciate Val's help going in to help us out,
so hopefully we can find him something to work on.
Right now, I'm gonna have to go back and ask some people
and see what they say and see if anyone has any interest.
And I told Val, and like I'm telling you,
I can't promise that we'll have anything
for him to work on, but he has my number too,
so maybe something else comes up and says,
hey, I've got some good information on this or that,
okay, and then we try to find a good home for it,
but up until then, it's kind of up in the air
unfortunately, so we'll see how things go.
Okay, and you're happy with your trip and your research
and what you wanted to achieve?
Yeah, yeah, I mean, my job today
was just to see what Val's skills were,
like you said, he's a very talented person,
he has a lot of good friends, a lot of good access,
so those are the things that my job is just to go and see,
and then I go up and write a report and I tell everyone,
okay, well maybe he can help on that or maybe he can help
on that, but like I said, I don't have anything personally
that I would work with him on because that's not my thing,
so anyway, that's my main job,
it's just to test and see how things go
and then they work out great,
and if not, you know, we still keep the line open
and you can always call him saying he's got more access
or he's got something else and we're good to go,
but yeah, and we need to talk about Marl,
I'm sure Val will tell you all the details about it,
and it is an unfortunate situation
he got like deep in the 70s because I understand
if someone was trying to take a child,
it is the worst thing that you can imagine,
it's also so bizarre, I mean,
it's the, here and see, the, you know,
I mean, there's certain situation that you can like,
well, you know, that brings that,
that will bring that consequence,
but that's not the case, you know, I mean,
there's certain terrain, you know,
you can put in terrain that the certain kind of seeds
that bring certain kind of plants,
and that's just not the case here,
there's no reason for that, and so,
it's very baffling, you know.
And so, yeah, I know, I know.
And I think, I mean, the best thing I can say is,
I know it sounds, you know, of course you wanna relax,
but the deep breaths when things get stressful
and things will work out,
will help you guys as best we can.
Right.
What I told Val is,
I know you guys fired your last attorney
because something was weird with that guy,
but hopefully, you're able to find a good attorney,
I'm gonna do some work to see if I can help
and find a good attorney,
I'll just give you, you know,
I'll just give you a recommendation,
but yeah, of course.
And then, but once you get a good attorney,
I think you guys will be in a better spot, so, anyway.
Hey, hey guys, sorry, hey, the other half of the cannoli.
I came in the room just now.
I'm eating your cannoli.
I was gonna save you a cannoli, David,
but I'm gonna eat it now.
Well, I think he might miss the flight.
Oh, really?
He might miss the flight?
Oh, dude, come over.
You should really miss the flight.
You might have half a cannoli.
Oh, trust me.
I would love to come over
because eating your deliciously,
you know, home cooked food is better than my carton meal,
which is nothing.
She's good, dude.
She's so good.
So, I would say I would love to eat with you guys.
I absolutely would rather eat than jump on a flight
and go hungry the whole night,
but at the same time, I think my daughter
hopefully will appreciate this one day.
That's the-
I mean, kids, you have, David.
You can just put one so far.
Oh, okay, okay.
Oh, cool.
Yeah, well, see how you go?
If the plane is not there,
you can't do anything about it.
Yeah, just come over.
You can crash upstairs to have an extra bedroom.
You have many skills,
but you can't-
Tell me, you can crash upstairs too.
That's of course not.
You can crash upstairs.
Yes, and we have space.
This is a big place.
Yeah, you can crash upstairs.
There's lots of space.
Yeah, yeah.
You're-
Hey, if something comes up,
I will give you guys a call
and they'll take it over over
and then we'll have a meal.
But right now, hopefully,
I'll be able to get there
and be able to be funny and close.
Okay, see how you go?
Let us know.
Either way, this house is yours,
and voilà.
That would be cool.
Okay.
Thank you.
Thanks, David.
Let us know.
Bon courage.
Merci.
Okay.
I'll talk to you guys later.
Hopefully, you guys have a good night, okay?
Okay.
Thank you.
Goodnight.
Bye.
Thank you.
He's a really nice guy.
He's like, you know,
I just want to tell you if Val does something,
he won't be able to tell you.
So, you can't ask him.
That's great.
Because he's like,
because we don't want you to be compromised.
Yeah, but what's going to happen to me?
She's going to think about fucking some people.
Like, you know,
let me talk to her.
That's part of the job.
And look, we know Val,
this is not what you want,
but he will be part of it.
Just don't tell her.
The Casanova spy?
Yes.
That's the title.
The Casanova spy.