okay so you the election comes around right in November you stay up all night
yeah watching in your so but were you in an Airbnb or in your hotel during the
election I I managed to get back into a hotel okay that's what I've got many
came in I had expedient points and so I was able to get a very good deal and a
very nice week okay where was something like 80 euros a night for a
beautiful huge two-room suite yes I do it's a Riverside something in the center
of Prague right where everything is hotel Riverside Riverside I have photos
I pull up all the photos it doesn't matter no we're going chronologically let me get
there I'm in Siena photo-wise so I'm just get the Prague Amsterdam so I did go
back to Amsterdam after that to see Julie after Siena and then I went to
Berlin did the thing with with Moritz then I went to got more drugs in
Nuremberg and Lugano then I went to Lugano do we pass up Lugano and we
didn't okay then I went to Lugano then I went to back to Nuremberg more drugs
from the oh it went to Zurich yeah I remember Zurich yeah that was fucking
scene too so we left out Zurich but Zurich was the whole thing and now I am
in Nuremberg back to Nuremberg now I'm in Prague okay so Airbnb and I stayed at
this hotel right in the center of town called listen Airbnb after the Airbnb
there's the drug bag
Novo Mesto Novo Mesto was one of them it really doesn't matter what the hotel is
called so okay so Trump wins you think yourself the whole world gone mad is what
you started to me Riverside hotel Riverside focus okay the whole world
gone mad yes and you start soon after that calls from reporters you've been
with over the past couple years wondering what if anything you have on
Trump including yourself did I yeah maybe and your quick search turned up
nothing okay so I mean all I did was search Trump yeah I had no idea what
understood okay so your mom as you said has cancelled her credit cards and
you're running out of money you decide to migrate south yeah so you brief time
in Athens where I saw Dmitri right we saw Dmitri and it also had trouble
lining up like acquiring drugs yes terrible that country was it's terrible
for prescription drugs okay then you move on to Rome had to get out of there
fast yes you move on to Rome you're renting a room in San Giovanni yeah
okay and then someone we will describe as Samantha Sheldon she identifies
herself as a reporter with the FT yes and said she's heard about him heard
about you sorry from another journalist and was interested in writing about you
in your story and so she flies from London to Rome on New Year's Eve well
should we say London I mean that's where the FT is based what can we just say
flies from a different country flies from out of the region flies from across
some water a body of water to Rome that makes the effort to fly from a faraway
country because we're giving it to me clues we say London and now it's all
in camera so thanks David well I don't know what's the problem with she's
identified herself as an FT reporter the FT is in London okay but we don't have
to say because it's just you there's many different offices FT there's FT in
Berlin there's FT in Nuremberg I mean not Nuremberg but another German place
there's FT offices all over the fucking world we'll discuss it later because we
discuss this person's identity okay so she flies to Rome on New Year's Eve you
spend the night wandering the city and you tell your story for it sorry FT in
Frankfurt not in Nuremberg but yeah sorry it really doesn't matter no it
does not just okay she you're telling your story walking around the city she's
recording that on her phone and kind of interrupting from time to time to point
out like ruined or church is kind of giving you a little history tour you
occasionally excuse yourself to the bathroom for oxy you end up at the
Colosseum right for midnight fireworks beautiful and you didn't spend New Year's
Day roaming as well and finally you've kind of developed a bond with her and
offer her a look inside your father's files she leaves Rome lies back to
wherever and prostitutes back in touch right okay so a couple days later or
few days later you leave Rome and head to Lisbon because a lot less expensive
obviously no I was sort of parted out I mean Rome was fun Rome was a good time
and there's a couple of things we missed with my others another FT guy that got
ahold of me forgot his name I had pictures of him he came to Nuremberg to
meet me for to look over some files I had about Monty Poskey specifically James
Schauder I said to TTR so when she said she was from FT Samantha Sheldon I thought
oh maybe it was from James Schauder that she got the information but she never
heard of James Schauder apparently so that was no that sort of made me more
comfortable worth of the FT and I've heard James Schauder you've heard James
like regular byline in the FT really yeah the odds of Samantha Sheldon work
at the FT and had not did not know a person like that is I would say
impossible well and so she told me so but that's what I had thought originally
that she did that's where they got my information okay so you're partied out
you move to Lisbon right you go to Lisbon you get another Airbnb room no
but remember this is there's a good stories here because I actually spent
time playing music live at the place called San Belushi like name of John
Belushi is a Italians love John Belushi so the name is bar called San
Belushi and they invite me to play every fucking every night it was fun and I
played and I jammed with all these great Italian musicians and there's a
couple of famous Italian actors too and I got a bar fights and right broke out
I was playing piano for the riot just for fun it's really high and there's
beautiful girl I think I sang her info too and it was fun it was a lot of fun
and then Landon starts calling me around the same time and Landon wants to do
the story this is prior to Samantha Sheldon showing up and Landon and I are
working on the story for Deutsche Bank and when it gets published in the
year's day I'm a bit upset and the Samantha Sheldon is aware of the story
being published as well be careful be careful
listen here at times Landon Thomas seems like a big guy knows what he's doing
it's upset with the story because it was not very well written this wasn't
exactly what I expected it was really it just sort of me under didn't have any
purpose so I was a bit upset with him about it I let him know I sent you the
emails I sent him he lied and told me that he had permission from Anshu to
quote from the note I said I would only give you the note if you get Anshu's
permission you need to just why don't you just get it from Anshu he's gonna keep
your permission but if he does not want to share with you personally I need you
to call him and get permission because I'm not gonna do it for you and he said
yes I talked to Anshu and Anshu said can you use selections from the note that he
left your father I said okay then go for it and so I okayed it and then the
story ran and then I hear from Anshu's people so we never okayed this and then
sent you this email too I got from Anshu's lawyers I'm not sure I think I
sent it to Vile sent it again and they said we did not okay this with Landon and
yeah but just in etc. just to play devil's advocate it's not I mean I have no
idea what happened yeah it would not be the first time that someone in the
situation of Anshu's people would have lied I'm not saying that is what happened
I have no idea but it's no but Landon backtrack said I didn't hear from Anshu
directly I heard from his lawyers yeah but they made it seem like it was okay
Landon that's very different than saying Anshu said it was okay and it's very
upset about it I wrote a whole thing I want to give it to the fucking editors
New York Times but I didn't cuz I wanted to spare Landon it's like it's a poor
landing I didn't want to destroy his I didn't want to get him in trouble I just
wanted to let him know I was upset so I wrote the letter to the other and just
gave it to him and this is why I'm upset I'm not gonna send it to anyone else but
I want you to know this is piss me off for future things that you did okay so yes
you go to Lisbon go to Lisbon you're renting an Airbnb room yes okay money
and oxy nearly exhausted yes what are you gonna do you call Sheldon I'm in
trouble you say but keep in mind Sheldon I've been talking like a couple times a
week yep yeah constant texting well this is much later right this is like this
is a maybe month it's less than a month well yeah it's about a month no it's
less than a month like it's probably three or four weeks later so you you call
her you say I'm in trouble I don't know what to do you need money you don't have
anything to your name other than your dad yeah I said at this point like is there
anyone you know that would be interested in buying this stuff like I can maybe I
could monetize yeah instead of giving everything away for free she calls back
she says she has an idea she called back in a couple hours says I have someone
who might be willing to pay he's looking for stuff against Trump right you say
great yeah some are watching inauguration at that point too and this
is 30 minutes later the inauguration is disturbing so I bring it up just to watch
this happening so you get off the phone with her half an hour
later it's a little after six o'clock your time in Portugal your phone rings
January 26 January 27 2017 3rd anniversary dead suicide so two years to
the day ago from today and it's Glenn and Glenn Simpson calls me and here this
is his laptop by the way still untouched well I haven't altered it I still
have his passwords down there it's the database that he created for my dad's
files and a couple of fake email addresses he made for himself he's got
like a 50 fucking Gmail addresses one called nada nada at Gmail what wait why
and why do you is this a special laptop that he had just for the purposes of your
dad stuff so it was it's like blank other than that it's like other than that
well I mean the key chain has passwords is house Wi-Fi and other passwords that
are relevant oh the trouble you could cause I know which I did not cause any
when I did not I mean I could have sold it to Russians or the Republicans just
truck grass you know I did nothing Marie now is using it for her to email
people okay so and incidentally just see we've all got a chronology story yeah
this is he calls you on the January 26 this is about two weeks after the steel
dossier was published by BuzzFeed yeah and so Glenn at this point is like
which I don't know man of mystery yeah yeah and I heard about it I was like oh
good I like this right yeah exactly it's other things I didn't know for sure you
know he seems like it could be a CIA guy man I didn't know what was going on yeah
Glenn sometimes comes across a bit mysterious yeah a little bit I mean
especially if you haven't met him so I mean just do my research on him before
for I meet him who's kind of like okay maybe he's a little shady I don't know
if I trust this guy sending me to some you know weird place in Texas because he
wanted to go to Dallas you wanted to go to me in Florida it's like
so what let's just hang on let's yeah let's take it so he calls you and you
guys have a quick conversation and he says what do you have on Trump and you
basically don't go into detail you just say you like tons of information about
all sorts of things in Deutsche yeah okay and I tell him I don't know I said
many reporters been asking me and I do it let me bring out the phone with all
and let's just pause it again and break it up