He shows you the tactics of what David tries to do, but he doesn't have the patience to do, because he picks topics that take four years to cover, and that's just, you're gonna fuck up, okay?
Yeah, yeah.
Unless you're like, you know, like Psy Hirsch, or something like that, right?
Psy Hirsch, he's not in that job.
Oh, he's great, you see? You have to have such discipline.
Oh, he doesn't have that discipline.
Okay.
Oh, you're saying you have that discipline?
No, I'm saying Psy Hirsch has that discipline.
To do a four-year story of this magnitude, right?
Okay.
He'll never waver.
So, David, thanks for this, I waited until 9 a.m. Tuesday, so the second thing.
David, thanks again for letting us film your interview with Valon Company.
Hats off to you for figuring so much of this out and framing a deeply human narrative around it.
I'm very much looking forward to, I'm basically saying I can play the Times game, too.
Right, right.
Fucking, you know, Page Boy.
Like, I am very much looking forward to fully digging the book.
I want to recognize you.
Oh, to fully digging the book.
Oh, okay.
I want to reiterate that I'll be, oh, I almost, I almost, when he was asking where the page
was, I was trying to find it.
And I was going to be like, hey, it's game 156.
I thought I heard you say, you almost, I think you did say that.
No, I didn't.
I think I thought I heard you say that.
I thought you didn't say it.
Someone, like, downstairs, you were saying, hey, who's got a copy?
I was like, yeah.
Then I shut up, yeah.
You didn't hear that.
I want to reiterate that I'll be fastidious in what makes the final cut and that will only
be the facts.
We will fact check, but this is much more of a portrait than an investigative piece.
So checking those facts shouldn't be overly burdensome for anyone involved, as we won't
be looking to break anything new, which is unless something new breaks, or focus on any
areas of dispute other than what we get on camera.
Your relationship with Val is one of many we explore with this piece.
We will continue to challenge him on his version of events and his actions.
I'll see you in a few hours.
But I also wanted to check to see if you're still open to a solo interview following the
daily taping.
We could do it immediately afterward, or later this afternoon's last evening.
We can work around your schedule.
All my best, Rocco.
Now, remember, he writes me back.
Let's see.
Within...
One minute?
No, not one minute.
Within 15, within 14 minutes.
Very fast.
Thanks, Rocco.
I appreciate your note.
I'm happy to sit for an interview, but let's see how and how long things go today.
It might be more sense to do it back in New York.
I also should check with NYTPR people.
Val made some pretty damaging allegations about me on camera yesterday.
He said that I had told a deseret that I would basically pay off Val.
He's only concerned with his business.
Pay off Val so that I could get a solo interview.
Right.
His business.
And he said that two of my sources, Tom Hayes and Tamiq Fad and both have expressed displeasure
with how I've handled their stories and relationships.
Nothing about this is the story writing of me.
The thing about their stories.
I checked with all three of them.
They did not, having said this to Val.
In the cases of Tom and Tami, they did not, having ever spoken to Val.
I'm attaching screenshots of their denial so you can see for yourself.
I'm not planning to raise this with Val today because I don't want to escalate things unnecessarily.
But I hope you will treat this as a clear warning that Val not only is seeking revenge against me.
That's his word.
But he is spreading false information.
Please tread carefully.
If you are considering Arion and Val's allegations, please let me know.
And I can give you contact in for Tami, Tami, Tom, and Odessa.
But then he sends me these texts, right?
And one of them he asks for permission.
One of them he asks.
What do you mean?
One of them he says.
And I share this with the producer.
Oh, you see it.
To whom?
Oh, he sees the screenshots.
Which is interesting.
Yeah, this is not kosher.
This is actually wire fraud.
No, I understand.
Pretty sure it is.
Because he's two-party consent.
Yes!
He's sharing screenshots of other people.
That's right.
And then I said to him, you're in two-party consent state.
You said that?
Yeah.
And he goes, you remember that California is a two-party...
And then later on he goes, oh yeah, because California is a two-party consent state.
Like, I'm basically telling him.
No one's ever done it.
No one's ever challenged.
Like you said, no one really comes after you just with a will.
But in the times, parlance, if you make a reporter look like a fucking idiot,
they're sending you.
But he thinks because I'm a reporter.
But then he goes and says to show it to you.
The dude who's fucking leaking on.
Right, right, right.
Okay?
So that's just chuckle head city.
That's funny.
So Isha's...
That's what you were doing with that day when you came and showed us, yeah.
You get it?
Yeah.
That's when you said I've got some news.
Yeah, yeah.
And I didn't want to do what he told me to do, right?
Because then I'm just as...
He was trying to do two things.
He was trying to...
He didn't know what I was going to say the next day.
He thought I was like on your side or whatever the fuck.
He thought you were my crew.
He kept seeing this in the text.
And the first thing I say in the microphone.
I'm not Val's crew.
I want to make it really clear.
Daily show, I'm not Val's crew, right?
Yeah, I remember.
I heard that.
So if he fucking says that on the daily, I'm going to call up their almsbudsman
and I'm going to fucking ream his ass.
Val's crew.
I'll shut up with his own film crew.
I'm going to call him up.
I'm going to say, well, we'll talk to him.
I said, guess what?
You got 24 hours or I'm leaking some video that makes him look fucking horrible.
Which video?
The fucking M-[Redacted] or something.
Oh, leaking.
Like a 20 second clip that makes him look...
Or when he leaves, right?
I don't mean come on.
And then I'm going to say...
You're leaving good, leaving good.
I'm going to say, what do you want?
I'm going to say I want a letter to the editor that I get to write her a column
about this fucking experience and then we'll really...
Oh man, I wanted to do that too about my experience with him.
I think they should have.
How could you do that?
How could you tell him to go about doing it?
Who did he talk to?
He fucking twist their arm to a pop set of sockets.
That's the only way to do it.
Because you said something.
You're right.
But it would be better if I did it because I think it's fair.
And you need to write your own book.
We've already talked about that.
I don't know how to beat that horse.
So I'm saying, you see what I did.
Wait, who did you get permission from?
He got permission from, that's a good question.
Because whoever you got permission from, he's actually scared of.
The rest of them, he's not scared of.
He's not scared of Dessa.
Because remember, Dessa was the only one that wasn't on signal.
Or maybe, wait, wait.
You're going to care less about Dessa.
Wait, and he text her at 7.52 a.m.
That morning.
That morning, it must have been.
And I don't have the time.
Why would he text her that early knowing she would get back?
He's sending me signal?
No, no.
He must know that she was, because she's in Saudi Arabia.
So he knows that.
Why else would he do that 7 fucking 30 in the morning?
Jesus.
She'll cut you out of this quicker than you can fucking say.
The shopping arrangement was to tie you up while he went and got his own.
Wait, what?
Yeah.
It works.
Shopping arrangement is worthless.
So time me up while he goes and gets his own thing.
With who?
I don't think he's gotten it yet.
No, with Adessa.
Because that means Adessa is complicit.
No, Adessa can't do both, I don't think.
No, but she wanted to time me up.
No, because she could do work with David.
David.
But she, they spoke with her.
They spoke with David behind my back to get their own deal.
That's what I'm saying.
To have their own deal with David.
With the agent.
With the agent, right?
So the agent's the cutout, right?
No, with the agent.
The agent is the cutout.
Oh, the cutout.
Who then allows to have her hands clean, right?
But that's part of the course in Hollywood.
You can't complain about that.
The reporters you can complain about.
But that's just, you gotta be a shark.
And David's not a shark.
He's a squid.
Like, you know, I see exactly what they're doing.
It's amateur hour.
And the agents are gonna walk away with a bunch of money.
That's who's gonna win.
Not them.
Because remember we had the problem with the agents from CAA?
Remember we had the agents from WMA or WM, whatever?
The agents from CAA and WME.
Yeah, go ahead.
They are as good.
They are like smart FBI agents.
Right.
With an unlimited bank account.
Who can do whatever the fuck they want.
Right.
Stay away from agents.
Remember the guy?
Yeah, no, you're right.
But they said, we don't want to work with Val because apparently there's some sort of vendetta at Valhouse with Andrew Durecky.
I don't want to be in the middle of it.
Is that true, though?
Do you have a vendetta with him?
No, no.
You just kind of falling out with him, right?
No, I wanted to get back in with him.
So I said, get Andrew a copy of this.
Put it on his desk.
I want Andrew to do this.
Once he sees that it's a packed, complete copy.
Yeah, but is he capable?
Andrew?
Oh, he's very capable.
Okay.
It just takes forever.
That's my problem with that shit.
It takes way too long.
But we don't want to live in that world anymore.
I know, I know.
We did when the Jinx came out.
Yeah.
Is it slow?
It's slow.
What the fuck happened here?
Where?
Data needs.
I don't know what that means.
Wait, so who got permission?
Tom.
I think it was Tom.
I'll check, but I'm almost positive.
But as you said, he only cared about him.
And Tom gave him shit.
Yeah, he did.
Tom gave him shit.
I wish I could see the numbers in these.
But he said to give them to me.
Yeah.
But the problem is, if I give them to you, again, it puts me, he's trying to trap me into a situation
where I do something like that, or he can discredit me.
Well, you decide camera.
What?
You showed it to me.
I showed it to you.
On camera?
Yeah, yeah.
But if I were to go and get the numbers, that he wouldn't give you, if I went and got the
numbers from him.
What numbers?
He gets up for you.
Oh, they're phone numbers.
Yeah.
And then I gave them to you.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
And he's held them off from you for so long, he's going to say, well, Rocco leaked it.
And that way, the circle's complete.
You know who really wanted the numbers?
FBI.
They called me and asked me for...
Why can't they get the fucking numbers?
You kidding me?
I don't get that.
They asked me for Tammy's number.
Well, no wonder the Trump's taking the shit on the FBI.
They're fucking stupid.
They can't find a number?
I found Tammy's in the fucking number.
I don't know if it's right.
I've been calling her.
They wanted, I guess they wanted an easy route.
Number?
They wanted an easy route.
They said, can you get me Tammy's number?
They wanted to see if you knew their numbers.
No, they said, I said, I don't know the numbers.
I said, but David obviously knows, as you know.
So I will ask David.
Do you see if you knew the numbers?
No.
I said, no, no, no.
Just listen.
Let me finish.
Sorry.
I said, I will ask David.
I said, David, I kind of need the number for Tammy.
He said, why?
Well, you told him why.
No, I didn't.
I never told him why.
I said, well, look, there's this whole thing, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And you know, I got a whistleblower friend at Deutsche Bank and he's interested in knowing
if you can cross-reference some of his data with the data of Tammy's.
He goes, well, you know, okay, if I can't give you her number, but you know what?
I can give you the lawyer's number.
Here's the lawyer's number.
That's it.
So I said, I went back to the FBI.
I said, FBI, I'm sorry, this is the best I could do.
And to be fair to David or anybody, you can't operate as an extension of law enforcement.
That's the worst thing a journalist could ever do, because you'll never gain your credibility back.
Right.
And that's what it is.
And in that instance, that's what it is.
No, but you got worse.
What happened was, because I didn't even get the number, one of the FBI agents called
up, called up the lawyer, sorry, called up the David Enrich directly.
How did they get the number from me and said, hey, we would like Tammy's number.
And then everyone in the fucking New York Times flipped out, flipped the fuck out.
And then that's why they included the FBI in the story.
So the FBI called us looking for him.
And then they said, basically, he called the, the FBI ended up calling the lawyer.
David calls me and says, oh my God, you never even guess what just happened.
It's the craziest thing in the world.
You know that guy that the FBI you're working with?
He just called me.
I'm like, no.
It was funny.
I couldn't believe it.
When you told the story tomorrow, that's what you told me.
No, and then, no, but that's because then the next day, the FBI, I called them and was
like, dude, what are you doing, you guys?
I could have gotten your number just like waited around a little longer.
Why did you call David?
Because now you're going to be in the story and I'm in the story, right?
Because I'm the one with the connection here.
And the guy's about, he apologized, but I'm so sorry.
We fucked up.
No, it's funny, it really is.
He said, I'm so sorry.
Fuck that.
We shouldn't have done that.
We should have just let you do it.
I'm so sorry.
I just couldn't wait any longer.
I wanted to try and get it myself.
Why the fuck is the FBI so interested in these people?
In this story, in this particular?
They're not.
They're interested in the Starz reports.
And that's when you...
Because David had no documentation.
That's why I kept bringing that shit up.
He did have documentation.
No, he didn't.
He has nothing.
He doesn't.
What is he doing?
He's calling down.
He's just the fucking word of his word and Tammy's word.
And they think that's enough to have a story.
It is for a book, unfortunately.
What?
It's for a book.
It is enough to sell the book.
No, but it was the article that...
No, you're right, you're right.
Read the article with Tammy.
There's nothing.
You're right.
No one saw it.
No one has it.
Tammy supposedly saw it.
That's why they questioned if she was credible or not.
Yes.
Do you think she's credible?
Yes, she's credible.
I think she's credible, too.
But I think David is when it's not credible.
He's the one that's writing this up in his spin without any documentation or anything.
Because he got so deep in that there was no way out.
Yeah, when he got all the way down there, he was really excited and he came up back with
nothing.
No reports.
Long paper work.
David, David, he's got it.
He's got something.
It's fraudulent.
I'm going to press him on it.
Press him?
Fucking hard.
I'm going to say, we're talking about this a lot.
We're talking about this a lot.
Because it's all I care about.
That's where dispute, when I put the pen in it, that's exactly where dispute is.
And all the rest of the shit's noise.
Where are the fucking lenders?
I'm trying to get them in.
I know.
I don't think we're going to get them, right?
I'm going to try.
But if they're fraudulent, it's just as important and weird as if they're real, right?
But we don't know if it's really fraudulent because only Deutsche Bank has said they're fraudulent.
Only Deutsche Bank has said that.
That's what I'm saying.
But they could be fraudulent because the Russians signed off-room with dead money that isn't
real money and not real fucking lenders because they don't have the right to lend through
Deutsche Bank.
I'm going to bring up a good point, but what is fraudulent to them?
What is they saying is fraudulent?
Because in my head, fraudulent, in everyone's head means, oh, someone faked the document.
Well, that's ordinary.
That's not fraudulent.
Well, that's-
Fraudulent would be the Russians signed off on them and weren't officers in the company.
Oh, that's interesting too.
Just fucking recording everything, huh?
That's interesting too.
Yeah, that's just the thing right there.
That shit.
I have it set.
When are you going to turn on me?
I'm going to turn on you.
I just don't want to make sure you don't turn on me.
Dude, I don't-
You're a journalist.
Look at my history.
But you're still a journalist.
Understood.
And I haven't had very good luck with journalists.
I see that.
But I also think-
Marie, Marie.
I'm trying to give you- have you ever had a journalist tell you that I think you're
just approaching- you're trusting them too much?
Have you ever had a journalist tell you that?
No, I did.
No, no.
No, so that should tell you something.
But you're an ex-journalist.
That's a good thing.
I'm not an ex-journalist.
Dude, I took a chance with you.
Don't worry.
Well, you did take a chance.
If I thought you were- I wouldn't have had you.
You wouldn't be here talking with me.
What I'm saying is someone gets your shit and like, you know, like, fucks me.
No, but okay.
Oh, no, no, I wasn't gonna get my shit.
I don't think I've said anything.
Anything I've said right now, I would say on a daily show.
Dude, I didn't-
I didn't-
I actually wasn't supposed to.
I wasn't supposed to record.
I actually accidentally did in it.
But now, oh, hey, could think maybe you could read those texts for us?
Yeah.
I mean, not like-
I'm not recording or anything.
No, we read them on camera.
I don't care if you're recording.
It's very easy.
Yeah, just for ourselves.
Because you won't give us the other things.
So I'm gonna-
I'm gonna give you shit.
I really want to listen to day one of the fucking date.
This is my-
It's my bounty.
I took a risk, too.
You know, I didn't know if that guy was gonna walk out or like, you know, I spent a bunch
of money on bullshit.
I know, I know.
You didn't.
Yeah, but you-
We're all taking it.
We have to.
We're trusting each other.
That's the way we have to do it.
Yeah, and-
And you're trust-
I wasn't sure and I-
No, and then I spoke to you on the phone and I was like, no, I think he's good.
Yeah, you didn't.
But first, I thought you were crazy.
I was like, I think he's crazy.
I am crazy.
No, I thought, you know, he thought you're like a madman, up the streets.
Because you know what I thought you were?
I thought you were stalking me since 2014, actually.
Why?
Because I thought, you know what, this sounds a lot like the guy who said he was from Vice
in 2014 during the Sony hack.
He said, come down to LA and hide in my basement.
Dude, I-
Listen to me.
There was a guy-
I didn't tell you this yet.
I was in the room-
It was you.
I was in the room with Seth Rogen.
Yeah.
And his partner, Evan.
At the fucking lot.
Yeah.
When the shit went down, I got the only interview with Seth and Franco and all the people.
That's good.
And it's online.
Yeah.
And then they pull the movie.
And I get a call from Seth and he's like, dude, they're fucking canceling the movie.
Because I told him they're gonna cancel this fucking movie.
He's like, how do they do that?
I said, I don't know.
But then I'm driving and I see them taking the poster down.
I'm like, this is like Nazi Germany.
What the fuck is going on?
Yeah.
Go over to the fucking thing.
They're smoking tons of weed.
And I'm like, guys, first thing's first.
I like, I like marijuana too, but you need to put that bong down because this is some fucked
up shit.
Right?
Yeah.
And they got on the phone with Michael Linden and listened to it all.
Michael Linden.
And they fucking.
I sat next to him at the dead Andy Drecky's screening of the Jinx.
I sat right next to him.
Didn't know who he was.
That day I was looking through his inbox and posting it all online.
Anyway, I'll read you these texts and then I gotta go.
No, okay.
Come on.
I'll do it.
So what was the end of your story?
So, you remember the interviews based on Vice's shit, right?
Wait, on Vice's shit?
We went to North Korea, right?
Oh, was that really?
Yeah, and they called me up like two years before the movie came out and they said, can
you hook us up with the guys that went to North Korea?
We'll pay them.
We need research.
Okay.
Franco was writing for me at the time.
Right?
So, man, that really ended weird.
Franco now does AA speeches all over Los Angeles.
Does it really?
That's his redemption?
I can email him right now or text him and he'll fucking call me.
He'll fuck to anybody.
Tell me who's the sponsor.
Who won't talk to me now is Seth, though.
I didn't do anything wrong to him.
They just said...
Why?
Because they basically Hollywood said, we can't have rock'n'roll in this shit anymore.
Why did you fuck with them?
Well, because Vice was a golden ticket for a lot of people.
Why?
I don't know.
I'm still not asking that question.
Why anyone thought that?
Yeah.
Now it's all in the Wall Street Journal, so I don't have to convince anyone.
Read this so I can tune this out.
Here's the Tammy text.
Thank you, David.
Just got your book.
Can't wait to read it.
Congratulations.
And that looks like it was from a few days ago.
It doesn't say the date.
Today, 5.33 p.m.
So that would be the first day of the interview following the interview, right?
Actually, the interview again.
I hope you like it.
This is David.
Just so you know, I'm in LA right now with Val Brochement, who is filming a documentary.
She isn't true.
Told me it wasn't true.
Rocco Castoro is filming a documentary.
Rocco doesn't want to be a credit.
I don't want the credit.
He's so Hollywood.
I do want the credit.
And, you know, it's also a discredit.
The whole discredits it if you're shooting a documentary on yourself.
Hey, hey.
A documentary on themselves?
What are you, a fucking rapper?
Yeah, I mean, come on, dude.
It's true.
I hope you like it.
Just so you know, I'm in LA right now with Val Brochement, who is filming a documentary
set on a camera that you're really unhappy with me and how I treated you.
I don't know if you talked to him or told him that.
But if you do feel that way, I'm so sorry to hear it.
As I told Val, I have the utmost respect for you and everything you've done.
And I have tried hard to treat you well.
And I've done anything wrong.
I sincerely apologize.
Which, let's be clear.
You didn't say that.
No.
The reporter said that.
And I clearly said, I did not speak to Tammy.
Who is Val?
Question mark, exclamation mark, question mark, question mark.
I do not know this person in question mark.
And then like the, ooh, like the face, the emojis, right?
Tammy.
And then David says, he's the son of the DB executive committed suicide in 2014.
She says, I honestly have no idea what you're talking about.
Question mark, question mark.
Okay.
Like almost at the point where I'm like, does she know Val?
I do not see the email.
That was my first I was like, does she know Val?
But no, she's just, that's how she talks.
I didn't send emails there.
She doesn't remember.
Okay.
It's fine.
He might have been lying.
Don't worry.
I do not know him and I have never had a conversation with him.
Period.
I believe you 100%.
Don't worry.
It's unbelievable.
People are weird.
Can you please call me?
We have the footage.
You didn't say it.
He said a lot of shit, but you didn't say that.
Hey, Tom.
This is Tom Hayes.
So he suspects that you just don't remember what just happened and you don't have video
cameras.
No, he's drunk or some shit.
No, but sending it to you.
He wasn't planning on sending these to me.
I forced him to do it when I sent him that email in the morning.
Oh really?
He panicked.
Why?
Yeah, why?
Think about it.
He was in the WALT in here the next day and I don't know if he was either, he probably
wasn't going to bring these up because it would escalate it, but this was his backstop.
I was in.
And I said, that's my motherfucker.
Do you remember when he left?
When he left, he said, he said, remember about tomorrow there's going to be a big announcement?
Yeah, and he didn't make an announcement.
Nothing happened.
He said, Tammy was in.
He wanted me to be his dildo.
Yeah, to make the announcement for him.
And I said, you're the dildo, bro.
Sorry.
Because he says, hey Tom, I was meeting today with Al Brochement and like this is, I have
no problem.
This is how I'm going to talk on my daily show.
Yeah.
You know, I'm just going to call journalists, dildos and stuff because they are, and this
is ridiculous.
Like, hey Tom, I was meeting today with Al Brochement who's involved in Deutsche Bank
Sider and he told me, as we're being filmed for a documentary he's doing, once again,
Rocco Castoro is doing, that you and Sarah were very unhappy with how I treated you in
the book.
I don't know if you've talked to Val or told him that, but this is how you feel.
I am very sorry.
Who is he?
My mom was.
This is Tom.
I didn't realize you would use so much about her.
That caused problems between mom and Sarah and this is, he went to jail, right?
Yeah.
14 years.
That caused problems between mom and Sarah, but they always hated each other.
My honest view is that it was a bit hyperbolic and that Japanese Libor is not linked to retail
products at all.
I mean, this guy has really valid points.
Certainly not credit cards and strident loans.
I think you conflated USD and, is it Japanese Libor?
I also failed to look properly at what triggered the investigation.
It's low balling and what the rules actually weren't as is the case, but I can't expect
you to read a book for the defense, which is interesting that he says that.
You can't read a book for the defense.
He's basically saying, you need to be salacious, I get it.
You wrote it in the absence of all the fresh evidence.
He's also saying he didn't help me.
Yes.
Well, he hedges that later.
So he's fair at least.
You wrote it in the absence of all the fresh evidence we now have in new witnesses.
That's interesting because he wrote it without that.
He could have included that.
The book wasn't even out yet.
That's true.
He wrote it at a time when I was considered guilty by most in the book, at least caused
a review of that narrative.
That's where he's fair.
I know that because of all the mail that was sent to me by complete strangers, which
again is like, what mail, like the book's not out yet.
So I guess what he's saying is mail that while David was doing his reporting, they mailed
him saying, hey, I'm sorry, this happened to you and that's the only thing I can imagine.
Sources and friends of his?
I don't know yet who David was calling, right?
That's the only thing I can think of.
And Sarah Deffo wasn't happy with it.
Maybe he heard from Andrew Verity, who's the FT reporter who you know.
He contacted me.
That's the guy.
Holy shit.
Andrew Verity.
He contacted me on Twitter.
He wants to talk to me.
One more.
I have, look, I have things for him.
Well, that's the view.
Maybe you should talk to him now.
Fuck, yeah.
Good thing you regret this thing.
I did tell him that I thought the book was too light on the BOE and the treasury rule
on this.
I only discovered Mom Knew Tom Scholar.
So much was only just discovered Mom Knew Tom Scholar.
So much was hidden.
So Sarah hates him.
That's the one.
That's why I said the wife.
I said that on camera, the wife hates you.
Yes, he did.
I did.
I said that positively.
Bar the RBC section that you never spoke to me about.
Their narrative was wrong.
RBC section?
So don't worry if you even worry.
I have no idea.
So you got something wrong.
RBC section.
It is.
Risk, uh...
Risk something.
Strangely, I like you, David.
Risk break up.
This is the weirdest text I've ever read.
Strangely.
Strangely, I like you, David.
But as you say in your book, this guy's actually fucking great.
Sometimes friends aren't friends.
And, you know, that's what Barrett was going off about.
It's good.
Friends.
Because he learned the hard way, right?
That's true.
He's saying what you're saying.
Yeah.
Hopefully, in this occasion, I do get it.
Wait, when did I say that?
Well, that's what you said to me.
You said David was your friend.
Oh, I did.
And you can't be friends.
You can't be friends with journalists, Val.
You can't.
Yeah, you're right.
You know what I mean?
You can.
I'll tell you this.
And the problem with David and me, for me, is this.
He used you for sources on other stories, then you thought of him as a friend, which
that is kosher in certain regards, where if you've used a source and you like that person
and you want to be a human, you know, so I thought it was, I thought we were friends.
So I called him a friend.
I called him.
It was the first story that he called me.
He used you.
No, he didn't say this.
We were friends.
And then all of a sudden, it became his best interest to not be friends with me and to
use me instead.
And then that's what happened.
But you can never be friends with your sources.
But see, and the difference is like, I can shoot a film about you.
How do you not be friends if you're five years and talking to me?
Oh, shit.
You're a human, right?
That's why you don't take five years to report something.
You make a fucking documentary.
That's why you do it.
Like, I'm not joking.
Like, I don't buy this bullshit that people are like, well, I'm a print journalist.
Well, then you're fucking a dinosaur.
Like, you have to do all of it.
And it's really important because this proves it.
This fucking, you know, regurgitation is better shit, right?
So it's like, strangely, I like you, David, but as you say in your books, sometimes friends
aren't friends.
Hopefully in this occasion, I do get it.
Maybe I'm wrong.
I'm not sure if Sarah wants us to talk.
To be honest, I'm confused.
He said, thanks, Tom.
For what?
And he said, for your response.
Oh, that's okay.
And it looks like, it says today, so it looks like that was at five.
That was right after the interview, so he was fucking furious about that shit.
And then the next day he wrote and said, thanks, Tom.
Oh, that's okay.
He said, if it is okay, I tell the TV producer that you're not unhappy with how I've treated
you.
Otherwise, I'm concerned they're going to take valid his word that you aren't happy
with me.
What the fuck, my, he does not fit, there are cameras there, I don't have to take you
at your word.
Why is he texting?
Why is he showing you this?
I don't know.
It's ridiculous.
You think I expected to get this back 10 minutes after I fucking e-mail, but I knew
if I waited the morning that whatever trap he had laid, I just ganged it.
So weird.
Or if he didn't, then it was fine.
Yeah, I can't talk.
It says, I was talking to the TV producer that you're not unhappy, now I'm a TV producer
obviously.
Otherwise, I'm concerned they're going to take valid his word that you aren't happy
with me.
Yeah, I can't talk to him, but isn't that guy someone, someone who's dad died?
He said, yes.
And then he, Tom says, the producer or Val, which he's like, I don't, I don't want to
laugh at that.
He's confused.
But then he says, I'll level with you.
But then David says, the producer, right?
Yeah, I can't talk to him, but isn't that guy someone's who's dad died?
Yes.
Tom.
The producer or Val question mark, I'll level with you.
This is still Tom.
The producer.
Oh, and I would see what he's saying.
He's saying, will you, can I, who, who should I tell?
Right, right, right.
Sorry, that's my mistake.
You can show him this part of the chat, but then they talked about something else.
This one was the only one not on, you don't remember, these are on signal.
So a text screenshot is one thing.
But if I'm texting on signal and I have it auto-delete and you do that, you better be
fucking ready to rumble.
From my perspective, if you better be ready to fucking rumble, I'll wait 10 years and
I'm going to get you.
I texted your stuff to Barrett.
I don't give a shit.
Barrett's fine.
That's because I didn't introduce you to Barrett.
It's like, here's this guy.
I sent Barrett all my...
I told him, I like him.
He's a pretty good guy.
He talks a lot.
You know, but I think he knows what he's doing and he appears to be saying, honestly, I like
him.
Thank you.
That's what my assessment of you.
I think Barrett realized that we know a lot of the same people.
Once I told him that I was commissioned to write We Are Anonymous, which is Parmi Olson's
book and he's in it, and how meta this was and that I wanted to commission him before
he went to jail, but we just didn't get to that point.
And I know different people, Del Cameron and Daily Dot people and all these people.
And I have a deep understanding of anonymous.
And we talked about how that morphed into Paul and my Paul right.
I need to finish this and then maybe, you know, I just don't throw me into it because
I don't want to like walk.
I got thrown into some group to give a day that was like, cuck, what was it?
It was like, no cucks allowed part two or something and I was like, what the fuck did
someone put me in?
It was like some fucking neo-nazi meme shit.
And I'm like, dude, someone's trying to set me up or something and I just said, fuck all
you Nazis.
And I left the grid.
Hi, I guess I hope you're doing well.
I mean, this is again, you know, this is one for us to hear this.
I hope you're doing well.
I'm in LA recording.
And this is 7 52 a.m.
So that would be the next morning.
He screenshot 9 24.
Okay.
So you got to remember that he screenshot this after I wrote him.
You know what I'm saying?
Because this was his big news.
And then he said, oh, wait, I can use Rocco.
Like he like, right?
He thought he could be a step.
All right.
Look at this.
And then he says at the end.
Well, you're, I can't remember if he said your friend.
He said our friends, our friends, our friends have some stuff to tell you in the master
interview.
I don't know if you caught that.
I did not.
Yeah, he says it to you.
That's why I didn't tell you.
So wait, wait, what?
He says our friends or something.
I'm not.
It may not be correct.
Something friends.
It doesn't say your friends.
I don't think the world will be real fucked up and I'm going to hit him on that.
You know, I'm not going to hit him on it, but I'm going to complain.
And be like, you know, David, if you talk about this again, you know that I'm doing this
independently, right?
Like, like I didn't know that you've known down for four fucking years.
Like you are in five years.
You are in that seat.
I'm not in that seat.
I got in and I got out and I got you on camera.
I'm not your fucking friend.
So don't make me your enemy.
And, you know, I'm going to basically be like, how would you like it if I fucking said,
Oh, Val's got a story is right.
Val's got a story is right.
He's got a New York Times reporter.
He's writing it with a New York Times reporter.
You wouldn't like it at all because you did everything within your power to make sure
that no one could say that.
So we know you wouldn't like it.
And, you know, go to Mark Thompson and ask him about me.
Ask him how dangerous a fucking am with the media.
Like, you know, go ask him and then go ask him.
Yeah.
The pedophilia.
He was good.
Pedophilia.
He covered up at the BBC that came out two weeks after he started at the Times.
Anyway, hi, I hope you're doing well.
I'm in LA recording a podcast interview with Val and he's filming a documentary.
He said on camera yesterday that you told him that when you and I met in NYT at NYT.
Yeah, that's like, you didn't say at NYT because you didn't know they were at NYT, right?
No, they said outside in a cafe.
Yeah, but you never brought up.
He's bringing up that he's giving up the fact that she met him at a New York Times.
He got confused though.
He's not doing that on purpose.
No, but exactly he's giving up something.
I told that if I got a film deal that didn't include Val, it would be fine because I would
just throw lots of money at Val and he would be pacified.
Is that true that you said that to Val?
And this seems a bit...
Set up.
Yeah.
I'm not going to say that.
Hello.
But...
Very much.
I'm going to say this in the text.
Right.
Screenshot it, right?
Because this isn't the morning.
Right.
I know.
Okay.
I told you I got a film deal that didn't include Val would be fine because I would just throw
lots of money at Val and he would be pacified.
Is that true that she said that to Val?
I have no recollection of ever having said anything like that to you or anyone else.
That was David.
Odessa says, I never said that.
No, I would have never said that.
I don't remember talking to you about that.
Or Val.
Dot, dot, dot.
That's it.
You got a problem with this Odessa woman.
I don't know who she is.
I'd love to stick a fucking camera in her face.
She texted me just when we walked in the door.
Well, don't do it now.
Because.
Do it tomorrow.
Make sure it's there.
Oh, okay.
I've got.
Okay.
We are going to go today.
15th, February 15th.
What's that?
I don't know.
We're heard from him.
Who's that?
David.
No.
I will call him Monday.
What we're doing is...
You're going to call him tomorrow?
Monday.
It's Sunday.
I don't know if it's Sunday.
You're going to call him tomorrow.
Do you want a camera?
Oh.
If you want to do that, we can do that.
Yeah.
And I probably...
I got that reversed.
Look, I was saying if you want to ask one camera.
Oh.
If you want to ask one camera.
To call him?
And ask him for the reports.
After we talk to someone.
I think they could...
I don't know.
It's up to you.
Otherwise, you know, I do want to talk to some other people.
Okay.
And if I have to go to the New York Times to interview him.
In Andrew.
That's when I'll ask.
Okay.
So, my own documents are the key to all of this.
Fragrant loan documents in my point of view.
And I'm talking about in terms of what I'm covering.
But I also think in the larger story.
So, the only way I can manage to do this in terms of the way I can understand it.
Because I don't understand why David walked out.
There's multiple reasons why I could have walked out.
We'll go over it with you.
So, we're going to go over it.
And I normally wouldn't do this, but I'm going to do that.
Because I don't know what transpired.
I need context.
And I'm going to ask David.
For the same context.
Okay.
And I'll go over it with him too.
If he needs to.
But he has a recording.
So, I don't take it.
Thank you.
That's correct.
The question.
So, did I miss you saying you're going to go to New York to interview him?
If I have to.
I mean, he said, you know, I asked if I could interview him.
He said he would.
But maybe it would be best if we do it back in the New York Times building.
With the PR team there.
Or at least maybe he didn't say with PR team that he's going to check with the PR team.
I actually would like the PR team there.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I don't really have like 10 questions.
Right.
I need you to help me decipher some of this.
Because the relationship between you and David and what they're going to edit out most likely.
Because it doesn't make sense without context.
I need context on.
So, that's to me why this is a, you know.
Another thing.
You have your own issues in the New York Times.
No, I don't.
Really?
No.
I think until there's evidence that, no, I said other women had issues with the reporting
that she did.
A lot of women.
I don't know.
I'm confused.
Yeah.
That's separate from this.
And that's like, I'm not going to bring that up there.
No, of course not.
I'm just.
I mean, like every New York Times every day, like I think most people do.
They won't ban you.
That's what you're saying.
They're not going to ban you from venturing.
I don't mean if they do.
I hope they do.
I hope somebody bans me.
Everything like, you know, like why not?
But so yeah, we're going to review this because I need you to help me decipher.
Okay.
What went down by David left some things on the first day, which I don't think they're
going to air much of.
They pretty much said that.
Did they?
Oh, they said like they said M-[Redacted] being there was an issue.
Maybe that's the makeup.
I don't know.
Nobody is going to.
That's that's that's just talk.
Nobody knows yet.
Nobody knows but when are they supposed to air?
I don't know.
This is March 18th or a little more possibly, but that's what gets the problems in March
18th.
He said the guests off the top said you heard the conversation.
That means there must be another story coming out about fc.
We don't know because you can't say that for sure.
But you said that he would tell the story of NFC from the book.
So there's a couple possibilities.
Okay, okay, okay.
Is that the way he presented the thing to us, he said, it will start with David and Barbados.
David and Barbados?
Who started with David?
Who started with David and Barbados?
That's what Eric said to us on the phone.
Eric, who?
The producer.
Oh, what?
No, and the guy, what's his name?
The fucking guy from the dating.
Why would he be in Barbados?
No, it's not Barbados.
The name of the guy that is the David podcast...
Oh, Barbaro.
Barbaro.
Well, the arm is here.
Well, I...
You're thinking, oh my god, John McAfee.
I'm thinking...
No, I'm not thinking John McAfee.
I'm thinking Barbados.
That's another thing.
That he will introduce that.
Yes, yes.
But we don't know for sure.
We can say a lot of shit.
You know what I said David wasn't coming here to talk about?
David.
Yeah.
And then he said a lot of bullshit.
How many did he say?
He wants two videos.
Listen, nobody knows until the footage is put together.
And you have to understand, like, here's my thing.
It's like, I want to shoot you listening to whatever they put together for the daily.
So whenever that happens, I got to send Ellington over here just to shoot that.
You know what I'm saying?
We can report it.
We can do it here, Kevin.
Yeah, but no, I need to have it the same.
Like, I'm trying to up the standard for this kind of shit, you know?
And another thing I thought as I got to tonight was cancelled is that if we do the podcast with Scott, you should be there.
Well, I wanted to film it, but I just had a miscommunication on the phone with you.
I really thought that you guys didn't want us to...
I think we wanted a break, which I totally...
I mean, the crew needed a break, too.
We didn't need a break.
That's my miscommunication.
Then I totally...
If I would have...
I had him booked.
I'd rather than be here right now, but it's fine.
It's actually worked out.
It worked out.
And then while we're...
I have some questions, so I'm going to stop this when I do.
And that's why we're doing this, because I don't understand some of this stuff.
Okay.
But...
Because I need context for your and David's relationship.
Okay?
Now, hold on.
Hold on.
Let me pause it.
Oh, wait.
There's even going to be a volume through this.
You look fantastic, though.
I look like an idiot.
Come on. Here you go.
I got it.
You look so hot.
I'm going to go with 1964 Southern...
No, you do.
That's why you look cool.
You look so hot.
I'm just outside.
You guys should be handing out flyers in Baptist Southern Louisiana.
What the fuck?
That's kind of fun.
Is there no volume?
Because this is going through this now.
1964.
I'm just telling you, I'm good at this.
Thank you.
What?
That's all you need to say.
Thank you.
You said pretty sweet.
Yes, sir.
No, I don't.
Thank you.
All right.
Stupid.
It's not working.
Oh, wait.
I mean, him next to David...
I don't think it's going to work through the sound, maybe.
I think I have to put it through here.
You can't air drop the sound out.
Oh, can I air drop it through there?
Oh.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, there you go.
Yeah, I used that.
I built a mirror in Samsung.
I think I made it in Samsung.
Oh, that'll do it, too.
Well, I had it on that.
I had it on a mirror.
Oh, you did?
Oh, maybe it's the other one.
The only worst case scenario which I'm afraid of is that they won't play it.
Yeah, exactly.
Do you think that's possible?
I think it's possible.
What's the code for Apple TV?
I'm sorry.
It should show up on your phone somewhere.
Let me see.
I'm just going to hit...
Apple TV code.
I have to bring up the app, right?
I don't know.
Because I think it's going to play the sound through the TV.
No, you don't need...
That's because you're going through the Apple TV.
No, I've just tried all the different outputs for sound.
Yeah.
For some reason, I don't think the HDMI is carrying it.
Or try Bikki TV.
Bikki TV.
Yeah.
That's the Apple TV.
Can I try the other...
Let's just play it through here.
Can I play?
Here.
The whole point is the sound.
I want to hear how we did the sound.
Yeah, but...
I don't have the sound.
I don't have the audio.
This is not Eric's audio.
This is from the onboard mic on the camera.
Gotcha.
That's terrible.
Oh, we just plugged the speakers in there.
Yeah, yeah.
If you have an output, yeah.
That works.
Give me the...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, shit.
Do you have that...
That kind of plug?
Mm-hmm.
Good.
Bill Maher.
I miss Bill Maher.
I love Bill Maher.
I've got him recently.
He did?
What'd he do?
Just like...
What'd he say?
What the fuck?
What did he say?
He didn't challenge Ben on the show
the last time he was on.
Sometimes it's just too high.
Bill Maher?
Bill Maher.
Is it who the guy is?
Headphone.
Sometimes it's too high as well.
Is it 10?
This isn't working.
Oh, I need this.
I need a headphone.
Here, I got it.
I have it, I have it.
I think that's the...
No, I got it.
That's your aunt.
No, no, no.
Okay.
They should have plugged in.
They might not be plugged in.
Is it not plugged in?
Yeah, here we go.
I think they have to be powered.
Yeah, it's not plugged in.
Oh, okay.
Yeah, yeah.
Bill Maher always the same people coming on.
I know.
So it's like, okay.
But, you know, I love Bill Maher.
You can't...
I want him to go on Bill Maher.
Yeah, what's his name?
He'll get us on the show.
Okay, and I have your word.
You're not going to leak audio.
This is for reviewing with me.
Because I know you're recording.
Okay.
And I'm taking that chance.
But I am...
On the type almost, on my son's...
And I...
Wait, just can you stop bouncing stuff on your son's life?
That's ridiculous.
On my life.
Thank you.
Fair enough.
Because I mean, no one hurts you guys if you do it.
Okay.
Ready?
Please.
Marie, Marie, can you just stop and eat?
I am, I am.
Good grief.
Both of you.
Gosh.
At least you make me laugh.
You guys are hilarious.
All right.
Was it funny?
Yeah.
It's not funny.
I'm just going to have a look at the court record.
Go ahead.
There you go.
Damn, it's live, Sarah.
Ah.
Sounds like you're plugging in your guitar, Val.
Yeah.
It does actually.
By the way, those amps, they're good.
Yeah.
Apologize?
That's right.
Work it out.
Sometimes apologies went down.
I mean, let's put this in context.
You...
He just apologized to you.
And I think we have that, but it's on a different card.
Okay.
Well, I want to see that.
Well, we have it.
Literally, he says you apologize, and we switched.
Like, it has two cards in it, and it switches over.
And I couldn't find...
Like, I would have to scrub through all the shit to do that,
and, like, it would have taken me another hour.
Like, it's just because it's at the very end,
right before the end, and I didn't know where it was.
Damage is done.
There's irrevocable damage.
It's really difficult to...
It's really difficult to just sit there and say,
Oh, what a lovely apology.
Thank you.
Listen to me for it.
But no, when lives are ruined, because what David did was...
It's called a character assassination.
He went on, and he tried to assassinate him.
He tried to murder him.
Now, I have been ruminating on as to why for many, many a day.
And I came up with a few ideas.
The one being the one I think I already brought up
was to discredit me so that you can take this book
and say, I did all this to myself.
You know, and if I ever jump up and say,
Hey, that's not true. I did this.
And then you can just, oh, that's just drug,
that's just drug addict Val.
Don't listen to him.
He's the credit card-thieving guy
that's out for, that would sell his own fucking father
for a movie deal.
Oh, you fucker.
I just can't believe you went that low.
I still can't, I've never really bothered you.
Incincidentally...
But I don't let me go on a tangent.
I'm sorry.
No, I'm cutting you.
No.
Incincidentally enough.
Because it's annoying.
I wasn't really pissed off.
No, it was good.
You went through my head.
You were really pissed.
I had the thought.
Oh, please, both of you are joining me crazy.
You're talkers.
The two of you together.
Oh, and you're not a fucking talker?
You're just pissed because you can't, you know,
talk over brother-in-law.
There's a question.
So I say something.
I went to the jump sign.
Please, look at me.
It's a big one.
It's a stereo now.
Okay.
I was so angry.
I had the thought that you're standing up
and punching me in the face.
No.
I was thinking about that.
And then I thought that was a bad idea,
like you're saying, obviously.
Because it was on camera.
I was that angry.
Like, I don't even fight.
I don't even fight in the light.
And you know what it is.
So I was 23.
Did you fail?
I felt it.
No.
Nobody wants to work with you.
Nobody does, right?
No.
I get to...
When I read you and David,
and I remember you saying the article
would change your life.
Oh, God.
How many times did you say that?
The article, your life's going to change.
Oh, make me a star.
You're going to make me a star.
I remember that...
Yes, you did say that.
That was funny.
Thank you.
And then...
Marie, what happened to all your friends?
I've been humiliated at school.
I mean, people don't want to...
You know, I was mad.
They don't want to come here.
Is that true, Marla?
I'm really sorry to hear that.
He said that.
Yeah.
We've had a...
You don't deserve any of this, Marla.
Yeah, but that has nothing to do with the whole conversation.
Yeah, but...
It does, Marla.
Yeah, it does, but...
I do.
And I'll tell you what.
If someone had done something that I felt harmed one of my kids,
the reaction I would have would be vicious and angry,
and I would do anything that would protect my kids.
So, if what you're saying is true,
but has affected his life,
I would have a very horrible reaction to it.
Well, that's why I'm in a horrible reaction here.
No, I get that.
I hear you.
Okay, you have a horrible reaction.
I don't feel any sincerity, but...
Well, part of it...
Can I just say, Marie, it's a little rich to say,
I'm not showing enough feeling when you blindside me
by having a camera crew here to record it.
I'm being very careful about the facial expressions I use,
being very cognizant of the fact that there's a camera recording this.
So, you see what happens here?
So, it's really you. It's Huey Hayes.
And, Roko, I must tell you,
there's something very important.
Three days after the article was published,
I called his wife,
and I told her all four consequences
in my son's life,
in Marla's life and my life.
And she says, oh, really?
He's in a valve like that.
I said, do you know since that article?
And you're referring to the...
To the article and drug addiction and mischaracterization.
I said, good question.
Had your husband yelled at you at the...
Or yelled at Val?
That was later.
PTA, okay.
I thought that maybe had happened already too.
No, that was...
You're going to teach your conference.
Can you imagine?
And so that he pretends to be surprised
is even more alive.
He's known that since October.
And there's not nothing.
Nothing, nothing.
Even I called his wife because he didn't know my text.
He would not answer my text.
Nothing.
I said, David, what you've done is affecting my son.
You are a father.
Why have you done this?
Do you know that I'm...
Val is not alone in the fucking desert.
You know?
In the vacuum inside it, right?
Yeah.
But he...
He knows.
So this is also important to put this...
I don't know, somehow we can explain that.
David pretends to...
Oh, this is new information.
Is that true?
He's like, of course he's going to do that.
He's trying to look good, right?
So he's going to take the...
Generally the opposition is stronger to him.
So he's going to go with the flow
in the sense where he's just going to say,
if you start agreeing with us...
Right now it's not...
It's advantageous for him to give in a little bit, right?
But what's strange is that he is now attacking you.
You're saying, well, that's rich coming from you.
Rich means, like, that's bullshit.
Like, how hypocritical.
I am hypocritical?
Yeah, it's calling you hypocritical.
Why?
That's what...
Every time you talk, you're working so much,
and he flips out, you know?
You see, it's something about you that you're like...
Not about you, sorry.
It's about...
Is that you?
Like, you know, personally or something?
Well, it obviously is me.
Yeah.
No, no.
Because they're rich doing...
It's something, yeah.
I call it bullshit.
You do.
But there's something that he's always...
Yes.
Because he didn't see this now.
So he asked the other day,
no, it doesn't matter what has happened.
It was terrible, and that's...
Well...
So why...
So I am making...
I was lying about...
I know.
So you think I don't know?
So I'm making...
You're driving nuts.
Yeah.
But...
Let's compare with me.
It's just my prisons.
I think so.
Yeah.
And you look...
Because we talked about it the other night.
Something about women.
He's the only woman.
He's not good with them.
He's got, you know,
history with bad behavior, you know?
So, yeah.
And he says I'm being rich like I'm...
No, rich is not critical.
Right?
It's not what being rich means in America.
Okay, wait.
That's not on me.
That's on you guys.
I forget this is a girl, right?
Well, look, I did not trust you.
I did not trust you.
That's fine.
And I'm not...
The camera's here, and I've...
Can you hear that just one more time?
I don't know what he's saying.
He says he's being hypocritical about it.
Did I hear it for you first of all?
In English?
I would have...
But remember this.
This is why also,
I feel that this is disingenuous
in that he says that the camera crew
have got a camera crew here.
And I've told him three times,
I'm not with Val.
I will leave.
I offered to leave,
which jeopardized and risked me with you.
Like, you could have walked because I said that, right?
But there was no other fair way to do it in my eyes.
I'm just putting it in context.
But remember, Rocco,
is that if he says Val, you buy a camera crew.
That means that it's something he can use against me.
If you come independently on your own,
he can't use it against me.
Exactly.
That's why he says to you,
as much as Val's...
Right.
He incriminates you.
Okay.
Right.
So, okay.
Not incriminating.
It's just like,
something he can use against me.
You can't say,
Rocco came up independently on his shelf,
but you don't.
You do a thing.
Which is what happened.
If he says that,
it doesn't sound good, right?
No, right.
All right.
Let's hear it.
Very horrible reaction to him.
Well, that's why I'm not in a horrible reaction here.
No, I get that.
I hear you.
Okay.
You guys are in a horrible reaction.
I don't feel any sincerity, but...
Well, look.
Part of...
Can I just say, Marie,
it's a little rich to say,
I'm not showing enough feeling when you blindside me
by having a camera crew here to record it.
I'm being very careful
about the facial expressions I use,
being very cognizant of the fact
that there's a camera recording this.
And that's not on me.
That's on you guys.
I forget that there's a camera, right?
Well, look.
I did not trust you.
That's fine.
And I'm not...
The camera's here,
and I've given my permission for the camera.
They're not here for you, first of all.
Well...
They're doing a thing about me,
and you happen to be part of my life story right now.
Is that so?
Okay?
It's not...
I only bring up the camera in the context of,
if you feel like I'm not exhibiting enough emotion
or senior sincere,
that's probably a something...
That's not what she's saying.
I'm sorry.
And that's it.
And I appreciate it.
No, I felt it.
He made me...
I didn't appreciate it.
I felt it.
I think he meant it.
He said sorry.
I think he meant his apology.
I just don't think he understands
the gravity of what he's done.
And I think this is why I wanted him to know.
I want him to see it.
I want to show, not tell.
Okay?
The fiction is one major thing.
Her friend, my Marie's friends,
I mean, could you really call them friends, though?
I mean, could you call them friends?
No, Marie, could you call them...
No, no, no, please.
I mean, these people are terrible anyway.
Yes.
You know, fuck them.
But it's not that.
It's Marlo.
Because this is a...
You have two kids, so you know it's like
going to school, having play dates,
and kids playing with other kids, right?
Yep.
You know the parents interact with each other.
It's a social thing.
Yep.
Right?
So when a parent is ostracized,
the kid is ostracized.
Yeah, I definitely know what you mean.
And that breaks my heart to hear that.
And never before that.
But that is a direct consequence of your act.
Well, that makes me feel awful.
Well, I'm glad you did.
It makes me feel awful.
Look, the...
But I have a few choices.
You can do something about it,
but you cannot do anything about it.
What would you like me to do?
What I would like you to do is I'd like you
to rewrite this problem.
You'd like me to rewrite the article?
Yeah.
Well, that's not really the way we roll.
I mean, I don't care.
I don't care how you roll.
This is what I like.
You ask me what I like.
I would like you to...
I don't know.
I'd like you to keep going.
I'd like you to rewrite the article.
I'd like you to make a statement.
A...
Marlo.
Because this is a...
You have two kids,
so you know it's like going to school,
having play dates,
and kids playing with other kids, right?
Yep.
You know the parents interact with each other,
so it's a social thing.
Yep.
Right?
So when a parent is ostracized,
the kid is ostracized.
Get money from Ray Van.
Yay!
Sponsorship.
You know, I was on a boat with McAfee,
and he stole my Ray Vans.
He wouldn't give them back to me,
and he said the same fucking thing.
Really?
That's weird.
And Ray Van was a sponsor,
so I'm sure they enjoyed it,
but it never aired, so...
What's your status?
We'll call Ray Van.
Yeah, I...
I definitely know what you mean,
and that breaks my heart to hear that.
And never before.
But that is a direct consequence of your act.
Well, that makes me feel awful.
Well, I'm glad.
Who is Nengar?
You're right.
It makes me feel awful.
I am...
Look, I have a few choices.
You can do something about it,
or you can not.
What would you like me to do?
What I would like you to do is
I'd like you to rewrite this properly.
You'd like me to rewrite the article?
Yeah.
Well, that's not really the way to do it.
I don't care how you roll.
This is what I like.
You ask me what I would like.
I would like you...
I would like you to rewrite the article.
I would like you to make a statement,
a public fucking apology.
Not on Twitter.
Make it a little more public than that.
Well, Val,
I would like you to go over your own fucking article,
or forensically like I did,
and say this is where I was wrong.
This is where I was right.
This is where I apologize for it.
This is what I've done.
I would like you to say,
you know what?
I was careless with people.
I was careless with my source.
I was careless with my friend.
I was careless.
I fucked up.
And I didn't think about
how this would affect other people.
I didn't realize that I, David,
had a voice that few people do.
And that's the New York Times.
And this is not just a rinky-dinky paper
in the middle of fucking Swaziland.
This is the New York Times.
And to put a character assassination piece
on the front of the fucking New York Times, man.
There's a lot of power.
And you wielded that power,
very carelessly,
out of your own self fucking interest.
I disagree with that last one.
Let me finish my sentence now.
You wielded that power against me
in a very selfish way.
And carelessly.
Because you were angry at me.
You did not consider the effects
that they would have on me, Marie,
and Marlo in our lives.
You were just filled with anger and rage.
And you took it out on me.
And the best way you knew how,
I said fuck that.
I got him out.
New York Times.
But you didn't consider how that would work.
You know what?
What's frightening means that you did consider that.
And you knew what the consequences would be.
That's what scares me.
And that's why I had to double down the others.
And this is just part one.
It's your imagination at school.
We went to...
Sorry, that was for vote here.
No, I'm sorry.
We went most recently to a parent-teacher conference.
And my future ex-husband
starts quoting you and asking Val to leave.
Yeah.
Screaming at him in front of everybody.
And he had to leave.
And he leaves half the time with Marlo.
He couldn't stay.
How could he stay?
Well, the New York Times was wrong.
I'm going to leave.
The New York Times?
It must be true.
Yes.
That's what we get.
And Dragon Age and all of this.
He's been going for a long time.
You don't know what I mean.
What we mean is that you're a part of the New York Times.
You're a part of his life.
Which means you could also be famous.
It could also be cool.
But just don't think about others too.
You're in the New York Times.
Because because you're part of his life,
the council is you.
You're right, Marlo.
Think about others too.
And you are right that it's really important to consider
and remember the power that the Times wields.
And especially when it's writing about the things that people...
You're right.
But David, there's a power in there.
I know what you did to me.
I thought it was just a nasty thing between us.
But then I asked around a bit.
And that wasn't the first one.
Nobody was surprised.
No one was surprised.
I asked around.
And you're not very well-liked amongst journals.
It's fine.
Oh, it's because you're so smart.
Sources.
It's because not only because of...
Well, the fellow journalist, what I heard recently,
he seemed to...
One said, you brag a lot about your stories.
Which I thought, okay, so what?
So I moved to David Bragg's big fucking deal.
And then he said something more like,
well, he would steal stories from other people.
I mean, he would get a lead that one guy would get.
And then he would come in and snag it.
And then sort of say, oh, but I'll give you the first byline.
I'll give you the first word.
And then he'll take it back.
And I'm like, okay, so fine.
So there's some under...
I'm sure...
I don't work in this business.
I don't know how it goes.
I'm sure there's sneaky stuff that happens.
Everyone's out for their own best interest.
And they want to get their stories out there.
I get it.
David's an ambitious guy.
And I respect that about you.
You're ambitious.
And then I hear a story about a woman who came to you.
And, oh, you found her.
I'm not sure which one it was,
but she was your source for sexual harassment suits
or sexual harassment things going on at some major bank.
And she came to you and she trusted you implicitly.
And the way you wrote the story was in favor of
the accuser, of the man who sexually harassed this woman.
And she was decimated.
She was decimated.
I've never written a story about sexual harassment, I think.
Are you sure?
What?
Not at the New York Times.
No, I've never.
Not once.
But before the New York Times.
Nope.
Never have done it.
Well, let's bring up the thing.
You want to do that now?
Yeah.
Let's bring it up.
Okay, look, Google...
Google...
I don't want...
She said not to say her name.
Is her name Lauren?
I told you, I'm not saying her name.
Is it for names Lauren?
I can tell you what your...
No, Lauren.
Tell me.
There it is.
Absolutely not.
You're saying...
I'm not saying...
Please can cut out this name.
I'm not going to play a guessing game with this.
If you guys want to...
I'm asking you.
If you will cut out the name.
Yeah, yeah.
So tell me the story.
No, I'm not...
What happened?
Absolutely not.
It's your chance to defend yourself.
I'll take my chances on that.
If you guys want to make an accusation of...
I didn't make the accusation.
If someone were to make an accusation, they're welcome.
I am relaying information to you.
I have...
Relay away or don't?
I just did relay.
Okay, well that's not...
What you said is not true.
So what's your side?
I've never written a story about sexual harassment in a bank.
So your facts are obviously a fundamental problem.
No, well you seem...
They're facts.
You seem to know something about this.
And they know you very well.
If you...
You said the name and then...
Is that the right name?
Yes, that's the right name.
I'll tell you what happened.
And more than one source.
Is the right name?
Okay, yeah, I'll tell you what happened.
I was an editor on that story.
There's other people who wrote that story, not me.
And they didn't like the story.
They thought that she didn't get the...
They thought that Victor, the alleged perpetrator,
got more sympathy than she did.
Right.
That was very...
Was that?
Yeah, it certainly wasn't at me.
Because that's really interesting.
Because he said he didn't write the story, but he was the editor.
And being an editor is choosing what comes out.
Right.
If you say that...
Right?
Oh, you're looking at it again.
So, okay.
An editor from the story.
There are other people who write the story.
Again, that's his classic thing.
Blaming others.
One small.
This story.
No, I'm not...
What happened?
Absolutely...
There's your chance to defend yourself.
I'll take my chance on that.
If you guys want to make an accusation...
I didn't make the accusation.
If someone wants to make an accusation, they're welcome.
I am relaying information to you.
I have...
Relay away or done?
I just did relay.
Okay, well, that's not...
What you said is not true.
That's interesting.
He thinks we're accusing them.
That's really weird.
Okay.
No, but he backed us on that.
This is one of the things I really need context on.
What do you mean?
So, I don't understand.
Because we have the footage of you calling the other reporters.
Right?
No.
I'm going to have to call him too at some point and see what, you know, to be ethical,
what we can use there.
Okay.
Yeah.
Even though we asked him.
We did not.
But it's different when...
He didn't know that it was me publicly disseminated, right?
Okay.
You did ask him.
Technically, you're correct.
Okay.
Have you not come again?
Yeah, I don't want to come again either.
Can you just...
I have to talk to a lawyer and see what the laws are on that.
Because if I put it out, it might be different.
That's all.
If we say you're being recorded...
Doesn't matter.
Okay.
I'm just going to check with the lawyer.
They will know the answer.
It doesn't matter.
If it's a yes, then I have things to consider.
If it's a no, there's not a discussion.
Are you okay?
Because it's the one way...
No, no.
We're careful.
It's okay.
Listen.
It doesn't matter.
It's not a law thing.
Because often...
He's saying it's not a law thing.
It's about...
No, it is a law thing.
It's a camera thing.
I can check first if it's a law thing.
And if it's not, then yes.
There's like a...
Why are you saying it doesn't matter?
courtesy thing.
It doesn't matter in the context of this conversation.
Because the conversation...
It matters in the context of the film.
I want to put that in there.
So, so you're clear.
She said it was us two in New York.
He said it doesn't matter.
We're asking for it.
This...
Whether or not I can include that in the film,
doesn't matter in the context of this conversation.
What he told you matters.
What he told you, I don't...
Not quite clear on.
What did that reporter tell you about this story
that you're referencing with David?
Okay.
You were there.
I know I was there.
I don't understand it.
How could I...
Why did I get the recording?
No, no.
I've listened to the recording too.
I'm asking you like what...
I still don't fully grasp.
First of all, I grasp what the reporter said.
What I'm not grasping is why you said he thinks you're accusing them.
Cusing him?
Because I see that.
We don't know either.
That's what's interesting.
Because he's so guilty.
Because he's so fucking guilty.
But he knows the story you're referencing.
He gets it in a second.
We blocked.
We did not know anything except what we just said.
We said, you were there.
You heard it with us from...
I know, I know.
I'm just...
That's what we know.
That's it.
There was something about a girl on a story.
Okay.
For a moment he was at the Wall Street Journal.
A girl, he would use as a source about a sexual harassment case.
That was at JP Morgan, right?
Morgan Stanley.
And Morgan Stanley, okay.
And he used her as a source and he told her that, you know, it's going to be about her
a terrible ordeal.
Defending her.
He writes a story.
The story takes sympathy for the accuser, the man.
The bank.
The Razor guy.
And the bank.
Which again...
She's upset about that because he totally flipped on her.
She's pissed off at him.
He flipped on her.
That's all we knew.
We didn't even know her name.
And he gave it...
He just fucking gave it away.
Made it.
And Matt refused to give us her name because they're friends.
Because they're friends.
And Matt...
Okay.
That makes sense, I understand.
Here is Matt, Matt's colleague.
And also Matt is now in New York.
But when this happened, he was living in London.
Right.
Okay.
All makes sense.
Thank you.
No, no.
What's the point?
There's a second possibility, actually.
Second possibility is this couldn't have been.
Another story.
Clearly fucking different.
Yeah.
I think it's the same story.
That's...
I'm think, but you're right.
It could be.
We should ask Matt if the name is...
He might not tell you.
Because he looks so angry.
You're right.
He's so angry that you're putting him on the spot.
Yeah.
He got red, too.
His face blushed.
David thought...
He doesn't know what to do.
He's stuck.
Yeah.
He's like on the trial.
But he went straight to accusations.
Yes, that's what I mean.
The other trial.
That's a show of guilt.
Yes.
That's interesting.
Because we were just asking a question.
So what happened?
Yeah.
We just...
No, we weren't just asking a question.
I mean...
We were showing that there's history.
Oh, pattern.
The pattern of inferring sources.
Yes.
But I think this and Eric looking at that must be fucking on his head.
Eric, the...
But what did you think we were accusing him of?
Of...
What did you say?
Of burning a source.
Sexual harassment?
No.
Of not defending a victim.
When you accuse somebody, you accuse them of something.
A crime.
Yes.
Accusing that he didn't help the source.
How is that a crime?
Accusation.
Something is severe.
No, that's not severe.
You're accusing me of, right?
You're accusing me of...
Robert, what could it be?
I don't know.
Let's go backwards.
I think I'm going to say it again.
I did, I did.
What?
None of the New York Times.
Okay.
I do have to...
I'm just kind.
You know, I respect that.
Hours.
I'm just...
And then I hear a story about a woman...
And we have...
Look how much time there is, right?
One hour, right?
One hour.
Okay.
So I...
Over there.
Recording.
Who came to you...
And...
Oh, you found her.
I'm not sure which one it was.
But she was your source for sexual harassment suits or sexual harassment thing that's going
on at some major bank.
And she came to you and she trusted you implicitly.
And the way you wrote the story was in favor of the accuser, of the man who sexually harassed
this woman.
What?
I've never written a story about sexual harassment right back.
Are you sure?
What?
Not at the New York Times.
No, I've never.
Not once.
But before the New York Times.
Nope.
Never have done it.
Well, let's bring up the thing.
You want to do that now?
Yeah.
Let's bring it up.
Okay.
Look.
Google...
I don't want...
She said not to say her name.
Is her name Lauren?
I told you that.
I'm not saying her name.
Yeah.
Because if her name is Lauren, I can tell you what you're referring to.
You're saying...
Please can cut out this name.
I'm not going to play a guessing game with this.
If you guys want to...
I'm asking...
We will cut out the name.
Yeah, yeah, I'm confused.
So tell me the story.
No, I'm not...
What happened?
Absolutely...
Defend yourself.
I'll take my chances on that.
If you guys want to make an accusation...
I didn't make the accusation.
If some of them are making an accusation, they're welcome.
I am relaying information to you.
I have...
I don't think you think so.
Relay away or don't.
I just did.
I don't think you think so.
What you said is not true.
So what's your side?
I've never written a story about sexual harassment in the bank.
That's my side.
Okay.
So your facts are obviously fundamentally wrong.
No.
They're facts.
See, you seem to know something about this.
And they know you very well.
If you...
You said the name and then you said...
Is that the right name?
If that's the right name, I'll tell you what happened.
What happened?
It's the right name.
It's the right name?
Okay, yeah, I'll tell you what happened.
I was in a...
I was in...
ochita at the time.
Something like this.
But it's the right name.
Okay, yeah, I'll tell you what happened.
I was an editor on that story.
There's other people who wrote that story, not me.
Thank you.
And they didn't like the story.
They thought that she didn't get the...
They thought that this is the...
Or the alleged perpetrator...
Got more sympathy than she did.
Yes.
That was why I was pissed off.
Yeah.
And then certainly, it wasn't me.
Right, the story there was.
I had nothing to do with the reporting or writing of the story.
by the story by the way but there's but look this is journalism is hard Val and
we get things wrong we do I do personally journalists do all the time
and we it's an imperfect craft and you're gonna be able to find I'm telling
look for all the corrections I've had no you're gonna find some bad ones I'm
showing you a pattern okay I don't care about this corrections this is a
better because there's another person tell me my pattern to talk about her
lips what did you tell time you told her I'll just summarize because you don't
know what I'm getting at but do you tell Tammy that you know you will take care
of her that you will not you will keep her from the the wilds of other
journalists you will have this tension you will you will be more hands-on as
someone to protect her from what was the the repercussions of what was going to
happen right because only David could do this because David is the savior here
come and save the day and make your life let me tell you what I don't know
what you've heard or who you've heard it from but obviously I'm and I don't
even know why I'm responding to them where you just being big but I'll tell
you because I Tammy did something the Tammy did something that's very
crazy I tracked I've heard through the grapevine in Deutsche Bank's Jacksonville
Florida offices there was a woman who had voiced concerns about Trump loans or
Trump transactions and Kushner transactions and had then been fired
as a result of raising those concerns I tracked Tammy down down over a period of
weeks I convinced her to go on the record
because I have it you don't know but I have it on audited because at the same
day I was talking to the FBI they were here so and you called let me let me
just if you don't mind I don't actually I just don't know why you're telling me
it's something good and I know it happened the Tammy agreed after quite a while
spending time with me and talking to me to do something very courageous which was
to go on the record she agreed to a photo shoot and it to and she agreed and
decided after talking with her husband after me talking with her husband this
is something she wanted to do it was extremely risky for her to do extremely
extremely courageous and that I mean that's the story that's like we spent
what must have been hours I think talking about the follow-up what the likely
follow-up would be from this what the implications would be how other media
would be pursuing her how Trump supporters would be so important because
this is also what I'm going to ask Scott about tomorrow and so my record
she agreed to a photo shoot and it to and she agreed and decided to meet and
she's Jackson, Florida about to meet the source I'm very excited about it because I
haven't you don't know but I have it on audited because at the same day I was
talking to the FBI they were here so and you called let me let me just if you
don't mind I don't actually I just don't know why you're telling me something
didn't happen I said I know it happened the Tammy agreed after quite a while
spending time with me and talking to me to do something very courageous which was
to go on the record she agreed to a photo shoot and it to and she agreed and
decided after talking with her husband after me talking with her husband but
this is something she wanted to do and it was extremely risky for her to do
extremely risky extremely courageous and it that I mean that's the story that's
like we spent what must have been hours I think talking about the follow-up what
the likely follow-up would be from this what the implications would be how other
media would be pursuing her how Trump supporters would be supporting her how
long and she's a very different version of the version says that she felt
unprotected she felt that you left her out I find that very hard to believe but
and she certainly has never communicated that to me she's communicated
something to you differently look Tammy is a courageous strong person and I feel
like she wants to speak for herself I totally respect that I'm not really
interested in communicating with my three I am the point is I'm bringing
showing you a pattern here okay tell me about Tom Hays no Tom Hays let's talk
about Tom Hays yes about you are the most intense about you are the most
intense longest lasting active source relations ever had Tom Hays is the
second longest and second most intense Tom and I talk regularly and he regularly
yes this is what I meant she said the most intense longest lasting active
source relations ever had Tom Hays is the second longest and second most intense
Tom and I talk regularly and he regularly yes when I met you said we
don't talk at all only to the lawyer I said why yeah that's a bit of a thing
well I don't know no I'm actually honestly what is that there is what does
that mean because yeah when you met yeah he said what I remember I was in the
apartment in Culver City I remember walking through the how long ago since
this is 2018 and I was walking through all the dirty clothes on the floor picking
them up David came in still we can help Tom because you give him some of the
Deutsche Bank files to show that he because I was still reading the book in
the middle of the audio book of this library book and I was like oh dude this
thing about Deutsche Bank we can give him a good lawyer or Tom all the files that
we have and they can help them reduce the sentence and he says well I don't
think that's gonna work I said why so well we don't really talk anymore so why
what happened instead of that of falling out he said the wife doesn't like me at
all Sarah yeah yeah that's what the text referred to that's what the text
referred to yeah okay okay that's what I need clarity up yeah and I said well
what I said when I get into impossible to talk to my I can only send an email I
can't actually comment so I'm gonna I probably will call I can't guarantee it
he said David said to me that I cannot call Tom like because it's only through
a lawyer because as he's in he's in jail so through a lawyer I get an email the
email it goes to the lawyer the lawyer then communicates Tom somehow you still
in jail I don't know if you're sure to look it up but I think you got it
since reduced by from 14 years to seven years so yes that's still me in jail but
I can call and I remember yeah I know David told me he would give him his
contact he's probably giving the lawyers contact we'll see lawyer yeah call
it's texting Tom I'm gonna say I want Tom's contact you want to hear oh yeah
yeah you said you're giving Tom's contact yeah I'm just telling you I get
them from what I'm gonna do and this is dog twice there's a the proof twice
because I also asked Val how can I contact Tom and he said we come because
David had it falling out okay they're not talking but why did you want to
contact and here you look at the files because yeah I had a Deutsche Bank shit
and I thought I could get a sentence reduced we can show that he how we help
here though because the Deutsche Bank hold on Deutsche Bank trader was doing
more illegal shit than Tom so Tom wasn't he was taken to fall for all these
other guys doing shit and Tom just didn't care David told me like Tom didn't
carry like Tom's out to destroy the world like he's a really care like he's in
jail so how can I care he's in fucking jail I know he's telling me like Tom
is an autistic like savant sort of thing and that he's out there and he wants
the whole world to burn down not just the banks it's like what it didn't make
any sense so he just shot down the idea of helping me helping this guy I could
have that was when they were in the falling out yeah since game regain
contact no but doesn't we don't know the truth it's a falling out either way
David said that no I said here's a bunch of shit let's assume let's go by as
well don't know the point is what it's more important now I realized that
because imagine if you're in jail and some writer decides your life for you
he's like fucking Davis decide no this don't give it to him it's not even give
a trot well there's a lot of steps that would have to be proven but it's
hypothetically could happen but also the point is how David interacts with
his life yes how hard is it for me to give him a bunch of files and David
hand those files to the lawyer it's not difficult especially when you want to
supposedly help your soul right so it's like what the fuck he refuses he didn't
well there's a fine line I'm not saying that you got it wrong or right I'm saying
that the only way to really know is talk to Tom and say you know you're talking
about different things on what we're talking about is this did David have a
falling out with Tom and did he then regain access that's the question that's
for you that's your question my question I don't have a question I'm just I'm
pointing out I'm a member of realization that this happened okay that prompt
can I interject because I am now imagining how many people I've reached out
to David to talk to Val and how many times has he blocked that communication
the way he did for Tom Tom and I are in regular touch he Tom is a
complicated person and it look Tom was another courageous person who is I feel
like I've done right by if he wants to say something different or if his wife
Sarah wants to say something different I respect for both of them but I
stand by my handling of Tom Hayes I certainly stand by my handling of Tammy
McFadden the situation you're referring to on this story I edited with Lauren is
I also stand by my handling of that although I recognize that that writing
with sexual harassment is very hard and it's very hard and you know what and I'm
not saying that's what happened with Lauren but we make mistakes the New
York Times does the journalist do I do there's and I honestly like part of the
that of this it feels a little ridiculous to me is that I can own my
mistakes you know I make mistakes in my professional life my personal life we
all do yes and yeah well and I'm owning that so I don't feel like that's
other than mine and say anything you've made a mistake with you said you stand by
the story with Lauren you said you stand by the story with Tammy and fucking Tom
too and Tom's 14 years in jail now does your help look I think you're presenting
you a pattern that what you're talking about is great but it's irrelevant my
point is that there's a pattern of people there was your sources that said
that you they've been left out high and dry to hang because of you and they do
not have kind of things to say about okay and you have co-workers that say not
that specifically they just more address the ambition and you're sort of wanting
to put yourself in the story this is this is my favorite response when I said
talking about David said well and this is most politically correct response I
get well David has his own style which I respect greatly but you know I just I'm
not I'm not it's not my style to put myself in this time it's not my style
to put myself in this time thank you that's all I have to say I can't tell
you anymore let's talk again that's what I got and I have almost respect for my
colleagues if some of them have issues with how I've done stuff they have not
expressed but they're definitely in terms of dependence and you were in the story
more do I mean isn't this story you wish you were the store now I think it's
exceptionally awkward for the general but you make yourself the story they're
changing well in this one me and my whistleblower and this one I definitely
did it's in the town you're in my whistleblower like you own me yeah
yeah sorry I've been trying to say something about Tommy also I think it's
interesting that I think you've got a question
you think of the golden yeah and oh God yes somebody you've been working with
if I'm correct me for long for as long as you work as well and it seems like you
vote a piece about Tommy based I don't know whether proof of what you were
recording but what to me was striking is that you have worked with Val for so
many years it was basically second wife and it's provided with all the
document all the receipt all the proof that you needed and that was not enough
but Tommy told you something and that was enough in her word that's exactly
brilliant thank you yes yes oh but tell me it's great and I'm no reason genius
you know why because that is exactly right you go down the floor you talk to
Tammy you come back with no documentary evidence nothing at all but her work and
you publish that and the world listens to it's like oh well it's a New York times
it must be true I come to you with hundreds of thousands of fucking
documents and futile documents you're fucking futile all right and then you do
this to me and you discredit me but let my documents and speak to themselves
well that was a fucking asshole but the documents are speaking to themselves
sometimes and then you have absolutely nothing with Tammy you come back with
these stars reports alleged stars reports you don't even think about
Susan Scarrett you probably didn't think about it right now
Susan Scarrett is the one that fucking has me fucking David think about you
could have gotten them from there but no it was enough for you to get a word from
Tammy and then spin it as he did into this big huge story which Tammy ended up
suffering from and still does today she didn't want all this publicity she's
one people howling here she's a lot like anyone into this with her eyes wide open
that's what she there perhaps she did but the way I mean again she's not here
Tammy did something really courageous and took a lot of personal risks and I I
can't tell you the admiration I have and you know what Tammy was here saying
something to me saying to me what you were saying she said to you I guess like
I would have a very different reaction I these I have I just have the utmost
respect respect thank you we all respect me yes thank you where's my
respect and my courageous I have a lot of respect for you are you are where is
that in this story show me waiters it don't tell me fucking show me where is
it in your profile my I don't know where it is if it's not in their values should
be I have respect for you I have a lot of respect well it doesn't feel like me
please please please he does he gets it he gets it it's David do you understand
what's going on here do you understand what we're trying to tell you yes it
seems in a way I'm being targeted by you and you target me now I could there's
millions of little we've been armchair psychology just for a long time and I
took it back to the beginning when I first met you when you're stalking me
for about a month and a half and I kept saying no no no back the fuck off until
I until I was at David Grant David Grant I said I mean you don't you don't know
this about Florida to you but I said David Grant I said David I don't know
anything about journalists you're the only journalist you're not even David
Grant at the time was no longer a journalist he was the he wrote lots of
easy now he's a superstar writer but at the time he was willing to help me
because he knew journalists you know deal with them I said there's this one guy
that's fucking driving me nuts and David Enrich or Enrich they called you
Enrich still at the time because they pronounce it the proper German German
but sorry that's just an old joke you're supposed to laugh I'm not finding
this amusing I know it's great for me though but anyway please so I said David
can you get this fucking guy off my back he's driving me crazy he's sending
letters to my mother my little sisters I mean that everybody is he's bothering
us can you help me with it and David says yes of course let me let me do my
best but David Grant is a timid kind guy he does not like to confrontation and
he didn't and he feels pretty bad about it but he didn't come he didn't get you
off my back and you kept pushing and he kept pushing and he kept pushing and
then you called one day and he said Val I'm gonna write the story whether you
like it or not you can say something you can give me some documents you can tell
me some more about your father's relationship to Anshun or all that shit
okay or I'm just gonna publish one of the fuck I want and I was like you know fuck you remember this
conversation and then I hung up and then you published Bill Brooksman kills
himself amid anxiety and fear into library bro library bro right at the
time I'm like what the fuck's a library right I don't know shit about finance I
taught myself finance probably last five years okay at that time I didn't know
what the fuck I was talking about it took me a few years and I really should
have thought through a little bit better but I didn't but I was such a fool at
that time but that was exactly the time you were writing your book on live or
exactly at that time yes it was because you at well you want proof of three
months later you're asking me I'm writing a book on a library Val do you can
you search these documents to your father's father's right you wrote me a
list to search for specifically a book no I'm thinking Jesus did David just use
my father's name to promote his book on live or that's what I'm thinking and I
couldn't believe it I started writing a book in the summer no one knows why
anyone kills themselves what gives you the right to say this is why Bill Brooksman
kills himself what gives you the right to say that's not what that article said
that's what the title says literally that's what the heading said
read it who's got it
we're looking at the internet
it's not everyone's fun
okay tell me what's
I would like you to know who the
by-lines are on this article
take a look
well tell you
my name is on there and I'm not sure it is
it's the 4th of 4 by-lines
okay library Brooksman
I'll show you
and my dad has nothing to do with library
and you know that
so this is important to you because you don't know
yeah I need context
so he when he wrote this story
I was a Sausalito I remember
and David
he was the one calling me
no one else did no one else called me
he was constantly calling me asking me to comment
asking me to comment I said no no no
and he says well I'm gonna publish it tomorrow then it's your last chance after a week of this
said no it's nothing I can't
no comment the story comes out
and it says written by David Enbridge
and Jenny Strasberg
had a third thing
let's look it up right now
and now he's saying oh I'm not the only one
yeah so he's trying to blame someone else on it
and it's clearly him
and also his book was on library
weeks later
he would say hey look up these things for me
I'm writing a book on library
look up these keywords in your dad's
files
see Brooksman
suicide
um
this is the library
this is the keywords
it's not Deutsche Bank
executive dismissal
library fixing is conspiracy
no no
it's uh
here executive who committed suicide anxious
admits Deutsche Bank probes
that's what's in the title
executive who committed suicide anxious
he said it's not in the title
Deutsche Bank probes
former top banker was involved in investigations
he felt abandoned by his colleagues
by dogs
that's what he said in the book
he keeps up that same thing
Jenny Strasberg
what does that mean?
nothing
I'm just wondering if that was his excuse
my name is last on the byline
so it's um
it's not really me
like the sexual harassment
I was the editor
not really me
like Kenny
so Aika's on it and David Enrich
and um the first book is about library
and that's what he's tried to do
promote
use his source to promote the book
like Schrocker just said he subconsciously said
it was me
what?
that he subconsciously said yes I did
he did he said yes I did
it sounds like he said no I didn't
but we'll review that close to this
and by the way just so you guys know why
I thought about this comfortable
reviewing this with you
one because of David leaking the text to me
and I feel
I'm not a print journalist
and I'm not a um
of writing a book
and I understand how both of those things work
I'm shooting a documentary in this case
you're writing a book?
no I'm saying I'm not writing a book for this
and I'm not a print journalist
I'm shooting a documentary
and a documentary the great thing about it
that's as close as you get to real life
a representation
so the fact that he leaked me the text
and the fact that this is the daily's content
I'm not reviewing any other footage with you
I'm only reviewing this because I need context
and to do it like where I question you
like he would
that's a print journalist
that's not what I'm doing here
and um
yeah I don't like I'm gonna do a split screen
in some instances so
you know like old 70's movies
I'm gonna say I'm stylizing that
like that is what I'm thinking in my head
so like you dress like this actually makes
a big sense in that case
and not in a funny way but like you know what I mean
it's almost like you're taking the piss
it's like having without knowing
it's like you saying something
him saying something and then like boof
you know what I mean and it will pause one
I like that idea
that's actually an idea
that people cannot refute
I think it's like the one way
facts don't matter in a lot of cases
to at least convince someone these days
which is terrible but so it is
that sort of stuff well I mean if you put
even Trump saying you know
I didn't rape that baby
and then you have him raping a baby
people are gonna see him raping a baby
even his supporters are gonna say okay yeah
you probably rape that baby
sorry he's the worst example possible
terrible image man
Trump just raping babies
thank you for that image
I want to point out something else
oh really?
that after this first day
David is
sending you an email
to influence your documentary
well he did influence everybody
influences my documentary but maybe not the way
he wanted right?
yeah yeah
I'm not gonna do that
my job is
hang on when you are not being
commissioned by Val
right no I mean
Val's gonna kiss me already a couple of times
you know but he's pretending
that you are well of course
cause it helps him but I saved the daily microphone
the first thing I said is I'm not
you know I'm not Val's crew
I am my crew I asked you know
I reached out to Val and he said yes
go go go eat
how are you?
go here
are you okay?
oh no
no
yeah I think they
let me get them
I'm amazed man
you
okay
thank you
alright Steve's got some text
Steve's really pissed off
the reason he's going in
and the more she ignores him
the more
the more you ignore me
the closer I get
you got a lovely singing voice
look at you
we got jam
I forgot you played too
alright what's your jam
let me see this
what's your play
if you'll come back on
I'm gonna waste time
yeah cause I do have to go
what's the other thing?
wait Val hang on
there's you've seen
showed it to me
you have the documents
that his psychologist and his doctor
wrote to the coroner
that very clearly says that he expressed anxiety
about the library investigation
he expressed anxiety about a lot of things
but you chose library
because you were writing about library
right?
maybe subconsciously
maybe didn't consciously
explicitly this psychologist
in the doctor's report cite
the government investigations into library
is what Bill, your father told them
they cite a lot more than just that
but you picked and she is the one that worked for you
there you go
there's the title
executive is committed suicide
anxious amid Deutsche Bank pros
okay
former top banker is involved in investigations
investigations felt abandoned by colleagues
he's a share
Janice Strasberg, Dallas Turner
Ikenning
what does that mean?
well that means
the by lines in general
so the first by lines
the person who did most of the work second
so fourth is the most important
I have to give them appropriate time
because if I say to them
when is the daily airing
if you think it's mid-march
I'll try to figure out but I can't bug them till mid-march
I'll find out
I told you guys I wouldn't
proceed your airing
but I also said that if you didn't air it
all bets are off
so give me an air date and give me a final air date
and like I'm editing my film
I'm giving you a courtesy because really
I told you these were the stakes
what did you tell me you were from
where I was from?
do they ask you like what were you doing?
I'm starting a new company
I told them very clearly
I have my logos and stuff I'm ready to launch
we're going to call it scanner
that's good
it's true too
I have a contract in my clause
that says if any of this shit gets messed up
with the business until the new operating room is formed
that I control the footage
and I own it
it's an independent film right now
I know where I want to air it
and on my new platform
but I'm saying
I still have a few things to get sorted out
I missed what you said
right after that
15-20 seconds
he's saying something
maybe
subconsciously
I don't know
the psychologist in the doctor's report
cite the government investigations
into the library as what Bill your father told them
they cite a lot more than just that
but you picked and she is the one that worked for you guys
there you go
there's the title
executive committed suicide anxious
for top bankers involved
investigation
investigation is felt abandoned by colleagues
this is Sherry
Jenny Strasberg
Giles Turner
Ikenning
and David Ennerich
what does that mean
well that means
byline is in general
so the first byline
is the person who did most of the work
so fourth is the least important
so you were the least important
so why did you call me
and tell me you're going to write whatever you want
I mean I obviously never said that
but you're the editor right
at the time I was a reporter
you were not an editor at the Wall Street Journal this time
I think my title was European
banking editor but that was kind of like a reporting editor
so these were not your subordinates
you did not work for you
I think maybe Jenny
who's the first one named
Jenny is the first one
I stand by the story
we can just skip
you stand by the story
what do you think someone would read this
if they don't know anything about
you know how newspapers are
I don't remember
here's the question
he says
that he was a reporter editor
but his title was European banking editor
an editor writes the headlines
a reporter does not write the headlines
so if you're a reporter
a lot of times the reporter will get pissed
because the headline
is not indicative of the story
or they feel so
yes an editor writes the headlines
now there's some blurry lines there
but what I'm saying is if he was both the editor
and the reporter
there's no way around him knowing what the headline would have been
and that's something that
you know that's better for me
to talk to him about because I am an editor
and was an editor and I can say to him
how do you explain that because I know for a fact
in the New York Times
I'm sure reporters have influence
and perhaps your standards
well first of all what's your standard now
what's your public editor say about how you present
what the headline might be to the reporters
and sometimes there's so little time
between finishing the story and writing the headline
they don't get to see it
I don't know what your policy is
what's your policy
it's probably different with every case
but a lot of times
maybe they don't see it
they're just so antiquated
that the headline may be laid out
and the story is still there
and so they don't see it until it goes to print
at the same time I'm pretty sure they have a big screen
in the New York Times, I know they do
that every day the entire day
as the layout person makes the paper
you see it in real time
I believe that's the case
I know the screen is there and I believe it's in real time
Is that the Wall Street Journal though at the time
they would have a similar system
just probably not projected against the wall
the Wall Street is
what's that?
I was looking for this ashram
I know it's in my left the whole time
but you're saying
there's no way around it
he might have an explanation
but even so he says I stand by my story
so let's say you go to New York
and he says I stand by my story
that's what he said
the headline is important
and you know this as an editor
but the headline is usually that anyone
72% there's I'll find the number
72% is what they read
so it's very important
and as the editor and reporter
I need to know who wrote the headline
if it wasn't you who wrote the headline
did you see it?
and I have several points that I'm going to address with you
that I think
that will make this very fair
but the power and balance here
in terms of who's writing about whom
we know what that is
and I'll take that into account
I don't need to show you
this is it
they know this there's an empowering balance
you say it to them
there's an empowering balance in that relationship
for everyone that's a source
and a journalist
there is indicative
and that's what this show is about
it's about how are you portrayed
versus who you are and the truth is somewhere in between
and no one gets 100% right
all the time
99%
it's hard to get 100% right
he's right about that
but that's not an excuse
he's using it as an excuse
that's what I'm saying
I'm not
I'm not a place to blame
and blame is not a thing here
I'm not here to
blame anyone's feet
I know you are
that's why I'm filming you
the bankers died
and they read this and said
Deutsche Bank pros
what is the subtext
is your point that he was
a target of investigation to them
what is the subtext
target of investigations
and he kills himself because
of the library
that's what you're saying
that's what this title says about my father
it's fair
it doesn't say he killed himself
because of the library
but yes the most people
50% of people at the very least
are going to assume
exactly
that's the nature of it
and David just said he just gave it away
he doesn't know why I'm pissed off
so he interrupted me to say
do you mean because I wrote
he was the target of the investigation
I don't even know that
but yes that's part of it
he's guilt is saying
Valis thinks I'm
because I wrote him the target of the investigation
I'm going to talk about this stuff tomorrow
tomorrow is going to be a long day dude
is that okay with you
if Scott doesn't make it
look honestly it's not the end of the world
because there's so much to talk about
because that right there
the context of that
people aren't going to understand from the book
nor well I guess he gets into it a little bit in the book
but they're not going to understand the history
that you guys have had
and the first article
I'm not going to say it glosses over that history
he admits that I think he admits
I think it's fair to say
and I'm not saying this the footage will say this
and people have their own thing
Frost Nixon then just got Nixon to admit
he apologizes
why is he apologizing
well I'm not saying that
I have to get more clarification on why he apologizes
because him saying this to you
of course he's nervous man
and I do give him credit for apologizing
but as you said and we have you on camera
and so I'm okay saying this
but he'll apologize
so were you surprised by his apology
you at least expected it as a possibility
you said that
it's really interesting
this is the
anybody else in the room
reads this line going in naked
you've made your point pal
I disagree
but I respect where you're coming from
and I hear you and also I have never thankfully
been in a situation
as terrible as what you've been through
I cannot begin
to imagine the hurt
and the trauma
that you have experienced
I can't
please
why did you exploit it then
I certainly did not try to exploit it
how much money have you made off of me
and my father
how much money have you made off of myself
I don't think I've made
I've received what I would consider in the publishing industry
a relatively meager advance
and it's
there's healthcare
you have
$1.5 million house
we have
cars
that's what this is
you have cars
I have a toyota
2017 toyota scene at minivan
a proper job
so that's the thing about the minivan
it's important
I'm very proud to say that why
because at New York Times
there's a whole thing on him
having a minivan
there's a story about David Enrich
New York Times reporter owns a minivan
I shoot minivans all the time
I know
but remember the whole course
David wants to be the story
he knows how to do good
he knows PR a little bit
that's for sure
but remember what he was saying
he was a part of the story
he wishes he was being reported on
and here he is in the New York Times
and Maria and I saw that
he was like oh my god
he is the Hunter S. Thompson of Banking Reporting
yes
look
the point is that
he pushed someone at the New York Times
to say do a story about me
and here's how he got himself
into the story about him
immersion
what do you call it
it goes to show it proves my point
basically I'm trying to establish a point
like I said before he's trying to be a part of the story
and that means he's got to elevate himself
he's got power and control over the story
that he's writing that's one thing
he's got control over me
so he's going to put himself in this position
put me down here
dismissing me makes me a terrible person
and asshole discredit me
and then he got himself into a story
about him owning a minivan
a knife whatever the fuck it was
doesn't matter he was in the story finally
all his life finally I'm in the New York Times
story about me is what he's thinking
right I know this fucking guy
so that he comes out and says that
he thinks it's cute and funny because that's not meant for me
that's not meant for you
that's meant for his friends at the New York Times
that comment right there
Michael Barbaro and the guy that he's with right now
and everyone he knows in the New York Times
that's what that is for
that's what that comes for
and that's trying to get a laugh from his colleagues
okay well I don't think they're gonna
laugh at this
but I don't think that is anything to do with you
or your dad
well for the last five years because that would seem to be the focus
this book will bring you money
I know but I hope probably not
but that's what it's meant for
in his head he's trying to get that
after that I worked for free
how much have I made
you didn't know what I made
I've never really seen
I've never fucking had
how do you get per month
from this project
my father
my documents
other than $5,000
thank you
that's another thing
why did you say thank you
you know Glenn Simpson paid me $5,000
why did you say pay me one
I believe it says
that he paid me one upfront
the rest of the $5,000
he owed you $10,000
he only paid you half of that
that means he paid you $5,000
but you said you paid me $1,000
no I said
just bring the documents right there
it's not
okay here's the one
the other big thing
this is the other big one
I don't want to pick everything
let me just give you the other big one
the other big one was Dan Gold
you have the recording
I made of Dan Goldman
and I screamed at each other
why is this important
okay so in the book
yeah in the book
and in the article
he says that
Dan Goldman
that I approached Dan Goldman
first of all
and the reason why I approached him
is because he asked me to
I approached Dan Goldman
for money
is it give me money or you don't get these documents
did you say that
no never once
no I haven't
really I see it for money
yes you did
but that didn't even mean me
I don't go around that's the fucking thing
who wants to do for money
I'm gonna offer you money
Glenn yes Glenn said I offer you $10,000
oh I understand
I'm gonna give you $10,000
$10,000
and it's because
what's your name
I'm gonna ask Glenn
I know a guy that's gonna
you don't know the fucking story
that's all I was referring to
the point is
Dan Goldman said
this is at least coming from David
and it is true because later
Dan will back us up
David says Val asked Dan Goldman
for a job
and then they subpoenaed him
that's what he said
and in the book
and there's a bunch of bullshit
and then later when article comes out
and I'm pissed off
and I'm like what the fuck is this shit
and I'm like David fuck you asshole
how could you do this to me
you fucking piece of shit asshole
you totally scream me over
you know what I think I was very fair
and here's an example look I left this out
because I thought it would be just too much
there was a press release saying
Val Brooksman was trying to extort us
and then we subpoenaed him
because we would refuse
to give him any money
that's what Dan Goldman said
I was like what the fuck
so I go scrolling through my text
and I find the ones with Dan Goldman
and I see and I bring it up and I send it to them
the ones with Dan Goldman said
what really happened I called Dan Goldman
and I'll give you the fucking files
I think I already sent them to you
okay
in the Dan Goldman conversation I said
dude give me, I'll work as an intern
just fucking let me have some oversight
you don't have to pay me
quote you don't have to pay me
how many times do I have to say
you don't have to pay me
and David surprised oh Valash says
pay me
I was like what the fuck
and you don't know the thing now
the reviews are coming
every single word about him
is
the last one
which I think is the Washington Post
and the New York Times says
he has been extorting money
to buy drugs yes
what the fuck are you showing it
I'll send it to you anyway
so that's the text
Dan Goldman
and the real story is I was trying to tell him
I said no I just want some oversight
into my father's stuff
into how his emails are used
could misuse them
could use them to profit on
and take them out of context
and talk shit about my father
so that's what I wanted
and I said well fine well fuck you
and said well we can always subpoena you
I said well good luck with that
and I'm just a guy you're going to subpoena me
and you look like an asshole subpoena me
and also you went to go meet David
secretly
to inquire about his stories I'm going to bring that up in a minute
and David went
to the side of the point
but he said four months later nice to meet you
and then I'm watching shit flail on national television
and he's fucking up
he doesn't have anything and I know it
and so I look it's like a fucking
I feel bad I'm like I should help
so I call up
I didn't call it I text him and I can give you all the fucking text about it
I text him
I text Dan Goldman
so look Dan we go on to a bad start here
you know
look I have a couple things I know are going to help you
send it to you one of them is to breach your boards
for fucking sake
you're going to like it let me just give it to you
but the thing is I'm working with David behind
so the only way to make this look good
is if you give me no choice please subpoena me
you couldn't be fucking clear
if you subpoena me now
I'll be able to give it to you right away
and he replies that's a great idea
we'll do that on Monday
then the following Monday
you can see subpoena as me
I didn't have the text I said that
I didn't have the text
I didn't know you
this is a much bigger
this is important
I need those
I need those tomorrow
fuck
we have a lot to cover tomorrow
I'll have to come back
but we need some time in between
we need to process this start editing
and then I'll know what I need to fill in
because I'm going to have to come back and get another two days with you guys
but it'll be good because
if we really air it
we'd give it some time
whatever you need to do
you do it
I don't know
that
the fallout
if this was wrong
this is how I'll know in the film
if David's reporting was wrong
or if the loaned documents exist
I don't think
someone will find those documents
within the next few weeks
or in the next two months
and that person will be here
I'm saying it's going to put eyes on it again
so
the shake up from this isn't over
I don't think your story is anywhere near over
I'm really hoping it is
I think it's nearing the final act
I think it's about to get real
or maybe it just
goes away
but again
the point is that David has mistakes
I was mad at him
he just got the text
and he even doubled down
by sending a letter
I already told him
I have to go see
I say give me money
I want to go give me your fucking money
I won't give you anything never once that I come up
in fact what I did say
was that Dan I want to work
in any capacity to have some oversight
into how my fathers emails are used
because they could be abused by anybody
the context is important
I will take a job as an intern
you can pay me zero
I will work for free
I will fetch coffee
I just want some say on how it's used
say them to take
and in your book
not the book
but your fucking art profile
you say Val has been
extorting Adam Schiff's people
asking for money
trying to get anything he can
extort
somebody get him his work
right at the screen
sorry if I'm
saying something
but after that when you
printed it out
she said well actually
I have this letter from
David
wait
what am I looking for
David said
where are you
search extort
he doesn't say oh sorry
this is important because David
I was so mad at David I was texting him
I was texting him
find the section
I don't even know what I'm looking for here
this is probably the wrong story
tell me a fat story
listen
this was important
okay fine
maybe there's some
I can't remember
remember how angry I was
yeah
I'll never forget how
do you remember what you
copied and pasted
just let me finish
my sentence you might remember
you copied and pasted a press release
for Madame Schiff's people tango
about me
you said
something akin to Val
look how kind I am to you because I left this out
yeah that sounds about right
what did they say
it was an on the record statement they provided
I don't remember it was maybe
they had used the word extort is that possible
I don't remember
but I do have it and you have it in your emails too
it's a paraphrase because I didn't
my email might take me a while to find it
I didn't want to spend an hour
I'll give it to you and I'll give it to you as well
they said
what was the fuck I can't remember now
Val Brooks who came to us trying to get a job
maybe they didn't use the word extort
to extort us
and get money from us and we said no
yeah right so look Val
look how kind I was to you to leave this out
we subpoenaed him because
we didn't want to stand for his bullshit
or whatever it was
and so I'm like what the fuck I'm reading this
and he said look Val I'm so kind I didn't put this in
and then I said David something you don't know
and I sent you the text
and you said that you had basically
after the anger phone call
with him and with you and Goldman
that you would basically
I believe that you had
Marlo
please
don't kick him
I believe that
you had basically invited him to subpoena you
that's exactly right
that's what I did
Goldman after we had
you didn't stare with me just to be clear until after the article
that's right
because I didn't know that before
right but I let you know about it
so what happened was
Goldman I got a huge fight
and at the end of the day I said well you fucking subpoena me
then you know that's all
okay then I will
we don't talk for four months he isn't subpoena me
I look around and I see Adam Schiff
wavering on television he's not going anywhere
and I'm thinking you know what
maybe I can't help I'm feeling bad now
like no I have this one
document I know will help and this other one
maybe it will help
so I said I send him a text which I
you have copies of
I said look I'm really sorry
maybe we can work something else out
the thing is I'm dealing with the FBI
I'm helping them and I think it would be better
if you subpoenaed me
because that way I can tell the FBI I had no choice
and there are these two documents you're going to need
one is the breach report
and another one was this other thing
I can't really quite remember right now
but again it's in your text
and that says Val
yeah it sounds like a great idea let's do that
okay and then I was subpoena
the next following Monday
immediately and then I said thank you
and I gave him everything I could
and I said the FBI guys
they subpoenaed me so I'm sorry
there's nothing I can do about it
and so I gave it to him and that's how it worked
and then I showed you that story I told you
and you did nothing
you didn't take anything back you didn't write anything
you did nothing
I'm sorry
he did subpoena you
the way you frame it
in the story is not
can I start understanding you correctly
you're upset with me
because I didn't include
something that you deliberately
you didn't do your homework
you didn't do your fucking homework
you didn't do your research
you didn't talk to them you didn't get the truth
if you had told them dad he's not going to lie to you
you know dad
he's a douchebag dick
but he's the truth he's an honest guy
and he's respectable
he's respected for his honesty
and his prashness
and he would tell you the truth and you had to ask him
but you didn't
or maybe he did but left it out
just to be 100% clear
and I know this
I know this but just so the camera knows it too
you could have provided that to me
in real time
as I was writing the article
before the article ran
and you chose for whatever reason not to
you agree with that
I mean that's a
that's a good way
that's a good way about David's friends
things
that's a good example
I'm glad we got that on camera
that's a good example how you do this
here it's a little nasty to say that
because oh you knew I was writing
after people blah blah blah
well this article has been
edited for so long so
suddenly
you ever check if he did it for your narrative
or maybe he did but left it out
wait I don't know
just to be 100% clear
and I know this
I know this but just so the camera knows it too
you could have provided that to me
in real time
as I was writing the article before the article ran
and you chose for whatever reason not to
you agree with that
I mean that's a
that's a good way about David's friends
things
that's a good example
I'm glad we got that on camera
that's a good example how you do this
here it's a little nasty to say that
because oh you knew I was writing
after people blah blah blah
well this article has been
awaited for so long so
suddenly
a year and a half
you let me on for a year and a half
and what I wanted to say every three months
it's going to happen next month
next month it's going to change your life
but the point was
that as a response to your anger
was like look I got a letter
from these people and I believe them
right
and not you after five years
right after I never lied to you
and you heard the text
I mean the voice mail
yeah I thought you didn't have the truth
right there
you told a different story
can I say the word lie is that extreme
can I say the word lie
is that applicable here
can I say David's lie
I think that it just shows a trait
of character and choices
and it's just very concerning
irresponsible
yeah it's concerning
yeah well you guys
listen and there's more David
no no excuse me
please calm down David
listen David
remember when you met with them
in New York remember
sorry they came out to meet you in New York
goldman and global
remember this meeting
all I'm going to say about
I'm going to say one thing about them
I'll just say up front
the one thing I'm going to say about that meeting
other than that it did happen
is that they asked
from my opinion on you
and they gave me specific authorization
they put that part on the record
your credibility and if you had good stuff
so that's do you remember how pissed off you got
after reading that
that phone call because I said what did I say
I said what the fuck are two
lawyers from Washington coming up
and inquiring about a source
a New York Times writer giving up his source
why are they coming up there and why are you talking about me to them
I was livid about it
and then you reacted like I was the asshole
for bringing it up because that looks
really bad lawyers coming up
from DC to New York to talk
to a writer to inquire about his source
that's not really
the way I would characterize
okay well you clearly thought I was fucked up
that's quite clear
is anyone else think that's fucked up
is this normal behavior there's it
because I'm accusing him of giving up his source
lawyers in Washington
me the two lawyers
Dan Noble and Dan Goldman come up from Washington DC
and they ask about me
they inquire about your source
and he told them all about me
and he said to them
that Vau was difficult
so it was difficult
all that shit and he asked Dan Goldman
what he said and then
he said it was difficult
you think Dan Goldman will tell me the truth really
I think he will
well he's gonna spin it he writes down the truth
we have it though
okay I'll send you the recording
that's another big favor
but this is a big one because you can get fired for that
why is that sitting downstairs
or is the editor in chief advice
hey editor in chief advice is that fucked up
you asshole bringing me in
he's not gonna say anything
but he's giving me the truth
but he needs to fuck up
David you burned me slanted me
you fucked me over
you left me out to dry
you did whatever you could to get ahead in your world
you used the fuck out of me
you used my father's emails
you used me
you could and you ran with it
and there were consequences to those actions
Tammy may not be fighting back like I am
Lauren whatever her name is
probably not and poor Tom Hayes
he's in fucking jail dude
14 years of jail
he's not gonna fight back and he's autistic too
and that was kind of an easy target wasn't it
you know about just
I am a grieving
son my father killed himself
I got a screw loose I'm sure
I've got my own problems
yes I enjoyed oxycodone
okay yes I enjoy drugs
and I like to party I like to have fun
and sometimes I think I'm funny enough
whatever but you took advantage of me too
you did
sorry for that one
I'm sure you're so sorry
I feel that way
I love that non-apology apology
I've already given a full-throated apology
for what I am actually saying
fuck your apology
and listen here are consequences to your actions
apologies words don't mean shit
actions mean things
my father how many times have I told you
what my father told me
how many times it doesn't matter
what people say you want to know
you stand with someone you look at what they do
don't even fucking listen to their words
do you remember that how many times I told you
you told me that a lot of times
so right that's what I'm going by right now
and look what you've done
which is what you said
and the problem is your words
they have a platform
okay they have a huge
powerful platform
a terribly fucking sword
that you yield
and you care less of it
and not just with me
but with other people care less of it
and you don't give a fuck about that
you only care about your next project
and what you're going to get
and what you can take from me
and what you took from me
I don't think I'm going to get that
no
so what do I do
do I do the forward
in my life
and forget all about it
you know my style
you know me a little bit
I would say that isn't your style
you'd be correct
now I feel like let's take a break
I'm ready
what else do you have to say
what do you think
what do I think
why did you come
what do you think
what you're going to get out
and what you can take from me
and what you took from me
I don't think I'm going to get that
so what do I do
do I do the forward
in my life
what are you planning on doing
what do you mean
be transparent
what are you going to do
I need to organize this in my head
you don't know me yet
that's what I'm asking
you think I'm using this
in some sort of thing
I'm asking you
I'm telling you
we just need it for it
so I know what the fuck I said
so if I'm attacked
I can remember what the fuck I said
and I can remember what the fuck he said
sometimes in my head I mix things up
well there's a lot of shit
I don't know if David said
like the word for example
I fucked up with the word extort
like I was sure it was in his article
but it turns out the word extort was in
Dan Goldman's press release
fuck that one up
the word that he used
demanding money
something similar to that
but anyway I just want to know this for my
my own stuff
and we like to
I like to listen to the recordings to figure out what the fuck
cause I get caught up in the moment
I don't remember it all
I don't understand some of the stuff
in the context
talking about it without a reference here
it would have been kind of impossible
I know yeah so I'm trying to give you that too
at the same time
and I'm going to send you the article
yeah we're sending all this stuff
and we're going to send him the recording to Dan Goldman
cause I have a decision to make
I think I definitely will go talk to David
if he'll let me at the time's office
because there's certainly
a lot of stuff that like
I don't have a checklist
of stuff that we will go through
that needs to be fact checked
and like you said
people get everything
with the questions
well
there's gotta be like 10
that's pretty easy
is that my style
you know me a little bit
I do know you a little bit
is that my style
I would say that
you'd be correct
good well let now
I feel like let's take a break
do you want some water
I'm fine I'm ready
but if you want to take a break
can I get some water
you want to yell David
you can yell David
I'll give you some
what else do you have to say
what do you think Dan
it doesn't matter
what do I think
why did you come in
what do you think
I'm good thank you
you guys
do you want some water
I know how
thank you
let's really talk
I don't have information
from this guy
well you can
I think we can cut around with you
I'm gonna ask
so you have more to say
the reason we came out here
you were gonna want
to rip into me a little bit
and obviously
that is your prerogative
so you have a massacist
no Val
because honestly
now it's not a massacist
it's a sense that
you have a great story
and I want to share your story
with as many people as possible
and there's no better way to do that
than hearing it straight out of your mouth
and
this is your opportunity to do that
so if you want to move
my opportunity
do you have the way you frame it
to my opportunity to do that with you
you're giving me such a big value
to me in this opportunity
it's not me
do you see how I could pick that up
as offensive
not really honestly but yes
I understand
I'm not trying to be offensive about
I'm just honestly trying to
if you would like
to tell your story
the place I would like to start
is offering you
I would just like to hear you
talk about your dad a little bit
and tell us who was Bill Brooksman
we'll get there baby
we'll get there
now right now I'm a little upset with you
and I need to air this
grievance with you
it's very important for me
I can tell
why you wanted me to talk about your father
I'm very curious about your intentions
I'm thinking why is he coming
do you mind if I just cut that
this was a story
that David didn't
pitch it to us or anything
I found
I was really intrigued by
the more I read about your story
we tell stories about the news
yours is a perfect example
of that you have an incredible
story that we're able to tell
and people understand
what's happening in the news
and so that's
my goal here
is to get the story from your mouth
the more that we get from you
of your own story the less that we have to rely on David
to tell it
I like the sound of that
Marlo please
Marie please
that's a great
I can't even hear
sorry Eric
just to give you an idea
we're interested in starting from your childhood
learning more about your relationship with your dad
and hearing about
your quest to
get some understanding about this thing
to have it in your life
David's here
David as the
reporter who's done most of the reporting
until this point
so with
you writing the profile
so what did you think of
you didn't even know about me
yeah I mean I was intrigued by
your story
I just thought it was compelling
knowing how writers write
and how this industry works
in the New York Times as you read the story
you're like oh this is a bit on the negative side
right
I had the same thing
I don't know if I feel comfortable
making that judgment
let's pretend this is the answer
okay so let's say I felt this is a little negative
maybe it's a bit more one sided
than I thought
maybe it would be good to hear the other story
yeah I mean our whole goal
is for your voice to be
if that's the truth to me yes I would be happy
yeah yeah I mean it absolutely is
I can tell you that 100%
okay so with David
you know I don't
I'm just a bit upset
yeah I'm totally upset
and I feel used
and it felt like I was
I feel like I was fucking betrayed
when he was there
you know I called you a friend
and I will never do that again
so
no I don't need you
to be my friend
well we're not friends you're
you're not a journalist
I can't count the number of times I've said that to you
okay and I can't count the number of times you said
oh I'm gonna see you a friend
this is what friends do
fuck's sake David
oh my god I know so many other people
it's just your
I mean I know you're on the spot
and it's tough
and you're being attacked
and your defenses are up
I get that and I'm taking advantage of that too
I'm sure you know this
this is a part of my revenge
okay this is a small part of my revenge
but
I am upset and it's very hard for me
to talk about something dear to me
this is my father
what I feel like this person
is going to
sabotage take it from me
rip it and abuse it and pervert it in some way
you know I know that now
since it's on the record there's no way he's going to be able to get away with it
but I still don't feel
safety
I felt before
you know
generally I love talking about my father
but now right now
I think maybe we should
maybe save it for tomorrow
I mean if that's two or three hours later
I can't
we just need to save some time
of course
we have two days that's why we wanted to take advantage of that
so
I mean if you feel like we can be better
like the air is more clear for tomorrow
yeah just some time prior when we breathe
that more goes to the corners
have the coaches
have the water in their faces
and so we come out without guns
yeah
I mean so do you feel like
you've said what you needed to say
today
Ray what do you think
do you remember
is there anything else you wanted to say
I have this much on
but I don't know
no no
because you're just affected
just as much as I was
remember it wasn't just me that got
screwed over here in fact
it was a lot of people
so Marie do you have anything to say please
no I just
I mean to me it's just
as I said
I've known both of them
the same teacher
I just want to say
I need to talk to his father
actually
use this
against me
very
intensely
on his favor of course
and
I will not
hear the end of it
every time I have him on the phone
or I see him
or you see him
it's another set of
humiliation
I've had people come up to me
saying
our children are friends
but I think it's best
we start being friends
so I had a lot of friends
in LA
I don't have them anymore
I mean
this guy is a bad guy
I mean this is another person I know
and I was saying that
I mean I think
even Allah would not believe it
like she would not believe it
Allah is the only
Oh sorry
and that's
to me it's like
I'm kind of a pessimist
and he's an eternal
optimist
and it's very
charming but
I was always careful
and just you know I don't say everything
way to day
and these and that
I would always tell her
I trust David please
trust me that I trust him
you know me
he's okay
I said over and over to her
and everybody met
you were like the greatest
I was crying
and if somebody had something bad
several times
but David
anything that had to do with you
and like
like his life
and
to him
you guys were working together
I know it's your book and he's not a writer
we talk every day for like two and a half years
you gave him
so many answers
so many information
and in the book it's like
lovely little acknowledgement
I mean come on
wait sorry I didn't press the last one
you acknowledge him
but oh yes
it does relationship
very nice
I do think it's great
he changed the
I read it
wait hang on
you haven't seen a draft of us
oh I've seen
how's that
I don't know
I mean I just
I
there's
did you really think I wasn't going to
get a copy of the book
you know
did you really think I would let this slide
I think the book reflects really well on you though
and it
I think
I don't know if you've read it
I've told you I've read it
around to him
I read it myself
then I read it around because
it was too painful for him to read it
so
yeah I can imagine these are like
really painful events for you
it wasn't that it was you
you can still see it in the book
like what
like what in the book
I know I'm a
meandering sort of
idiotic
asshole that you're hopeless
these were hopeless
and I had to go down all the time
careless with people
and really I was mean to my mother
yeah for
for Allah
yes it's terrible
you couldn't stop yourself
then sending me money to him
he doesn't do anything
he couldn't handle the money anyway
I'm not sure how
my guess is you got a hold of a book
a version of the book that was sent to
and Roxanne
probably
no no
yes you do
so that's what it doesn't make sense
that's the secret
but you get what I'm saying
it doesn't make sense
with how he's claiming
you never said that to Odessa
Odessa's saying she didn't say that
but she leaked your book
oh yeah
she has no clue
well then you know what
there you go
I'm just saying
the fact that she had the book
I didn't tell you
I understand
actually his moral
made him hesitate until
the very very last minute
because he was
I mean even last night I had an argument with you
is he still defending you
yeah I can't believe I caught myself defending
I said you were right
you were right
it was like instinct to just defend it
I said no David it wasn't
well from whatever it was the guys
the people who don't have a stake in this one were the other
and I very much do have a stake in it
obviously you guys do too
who don't know you
who don't really know me
and have read it think that
they have a very different read on
every time I see a review
I don't see my name
I don't see my father's name
I see a blurb that says
David's exposing Deutsche Bank
stay tuned for more Deutsche Bank
and more terrible things
and I'm supposed to be the main character right
you're a main character
you're a dad or probably the main character
that was a mention of us
and why am I not on the back of the book
where's the description
if I am such a main character
tell me about it
the banker's son
was not the original title
that was the title I started with
but that was what I got
regret telling you that about me
because I told you at the time
that that was definitely something
that we were toying with that might not happen
but I'm just looking at actually the back of the book
where it's described as
father-son drama
it's
it's very much
about you and about your father
I don't think anyone
is my name in there
we're on the back of the book
we're just there with the index
we're just a main character
but usually they would be in the description
so this is what the book's about
we had an agreement
did we not that the book was going to be about my father
and my journey mostly
over the course of the last five years
of what I've discovered
through my eyes
that's definitely the bulk of the book
that's also what you pitched in New York Times
because you sent me the
what the pitch that you sent in New York Times
and you sent me the pitch that you sent to our colleagues
and both of them said
okay that the book was about me
and my father and the journey that I've been through
and I told you back through my eyes
okay that is not what I read
well that is a very different book
I'm not sure what you read Val
but the I
look let's just let the book speak for itself then
because I don't think
any person
who reads that book will possibly
come away with agreements
except for the fact that you are not
by name
you ignore your dad I believe
it's prominently mentioned by name
on the jacket of the book
right and if
the tables return we should be a bit upset
honestly if I was just in this
to have my dad's legacy
every time you say I'm on the side
of the word honestly
if I was just concerned about
my dad's legacy and I read this book
I think I would be pretty
pretty content with it
and what did I say earlier on
I said you did a good job with my father
and respected him
and I was appreciated
so let's not lose sight of him
no I didn't lose sight of him
but me it's another story
I do have to defend myself too
and I talk all over
and I refuse to
and I'm not going to let it happen
and this whole thing right here
who is this benefit
wait one way please
what's this
the day the podcast
who does it benefit
does it benefit me or you
you have a book to sell
it doesn't matter
it's not the same days your book
it's coming out but this benefit too
what does what mean
why do they do this then
they can't say that they're promoting the book
they can't say
it benefits one of the writers
but he said this is not coming out
around the release of the book
he's lying
it's an obvious lie
it's a weird lie because everyone knows it's not
if he said mid-march though I'm saying that the release date
the book is released February 18th
that's very soon
I know because
I think they are going to be in mid-march
so I'm wondering if he has another story
yeah but imagine you have a book coming out in February
then you have a relance
a rebound
of promotion
I get that part
but I've never seen the Times do that
without something in tandem in the paper
and I've checked and that's every episode
of the Daily has like a
unless it's like a
political rally or something
yes the last time you did it
with a different podcast there was the story about the Hitch Bank
and I was commemorating and he promoted the book
we didn't say anything about us
so he already did one right
okay so maybe you're right about the rebound then
yes of course
I just feel like he's going to have another story
it's possible we'll see
he'll just copy and paste from the book
he's going to do the same though
he's going to do like the first one
what are you talking about
first person, immersive
I apologize
that would be fantastic
it's going to be the same month as my book
this benefits you David
this helps your books
arguing, it's fun
readers will listen and they'll say oh my god
Foul's an asshole or David's an asshole
whatever but the fact is they're talking
about it and they're like oh let's see
about this book maybe we can find out more
alright so maybe the book isn't
good enough or interesting enough
and so maybe you need this little fiasco
to help some bookstores
who knows I'm just
I'm not saying it's true I'm just spitballing here
maybe this is going to benefit you in that way
maybe you said let's go out to California
and have Foul yell at me because this can be
critical to see
maybe no you mean this
yes maybe I can get Foul again
you know put him in his place
I mean Foul's a no good dude
is it
idiotic drug addict asshole
I mean whatever the fuck you've said about me
you probably
didn't do any research
or doesn't care
he's probably going to wake up to you
he's always David coming today I forgot all about it
and then you can do whatever the fuck you want
I predicted there's going to be a camera failure
he didn't he said 10%
you're right that's true
I predicted there'd be a camera failure
I said no he didn't he said there'd be a 10% chance
because you're right I did
it's good if you got him
I said
do you want to know how I describe you to
strongest man
I was like were you talking about it
he's like yeah we were
because the daily always does that stuff
we're in the car we're arriving at the Vogue Schmidt's house
like I asked him if we did that
and he's like yeah yeah we did that
so I know that I know they're going to include it
but they kind of have to include me asking them
too if they're going to talk about
the film crew you know like
so I hope they give me some promotion
that's why you need to look
intelligent, articulate
charismatic and charming
where is that in the profile
why is that not in the profile
I get to think that some of those words
feel like are in the profile
it's not
not one compliment or nice
everything a pejority
we went through friends with every single fucking word you wrote
you didn't say one time
I don't think that's true
did you read what we sent you
we went through it word for word
can you show me one nice word
can you show me one time Dini said
if you just told him I'm sure I can
okay do it
I don't have internet
I'm not walking to your house
ladies and gentlemen of the world
the wifi password here is
Olive Airplane 370
I'm not allowed to have your wifi thanks
that's the smartest thing you said on that
you want to have the air flow
on your device
I'm happy
I just realized that was good
now you have the Russians
you have the Russians don't you
I'm happy
he probably
he probably completely
didn't do any research or
doesn't care he's probably going to wake up and tell you
it's Dave you're coming today I forgot all about it
and then you can do whatever the fuck you want
I predicted there's going to be a camera for you
you're right
that's true
do you want to know how I describe you to
strangers
intelligent, articulate
charismatic
and charming
why is that not in the profile
I usually think that some of those words
are in the profile
it's not
not one compliment
or nice everything of the choreo
we went through friends of the every single fucking word
you wrote
I don't think that's true
did you read what we sent you
we went through it word for word
can you show me one nice word
can you show me one thing you said
I'm sure I can
I don't have internet
you don't have internet
ladies and gentlemen of the world
the wifi password here
is oliveairplane370
I'm not allowed to have your wifi
thanks
that's the smartest thing you said on that
you learned the article on your
on your device
I'm happy
see that's funny
it's only funny when it's on camera
what were you saying
there's tennis in this picture
you say you describe this
these time words
this is how you describe me
that's not how you describe it to the world
maybe in private you say this
this is the world
this isn't just
Ricky Dinky's spot in Swaziland
like I said before
or even a regional paper
or just America
this is the world
billions of people
and you're careless
you fucked up
and you will pay the consequences of that
whatever that looks like
you know
and I'm angry
obviously
so
I would love to talk about my father
but I can't do it
we should come back
tomorrow do you think
there's a little earlier
we can do like noon
maybe 11 let's try for 11
I don't have to do it 11
so there's
I could do
that's probably the best
yeah
we don't want to take up your whole day
we don't want to try to
are you taking up more than a day
well Eric hasn't done anything
no
it's taking up five years of my life
well actually David's only taken up two and a half
but yes
I think I can do another day
okay so let's find for noon
tomorrow
okay
I mean do you have any questions for me
that you want to
I didn't really do any background
I mean just about what we want
from you or what the hopes
for the story are
basically
we
we generally don't show people
our list of questions but the thrust of the story
is your childhood
your relationship to your dad
how you came to understand his role
at Deutsche Bank when you were young
obviously when you were talking about
your suicide
you discovering that
and then basically the thrust of the episode
is you trying to figure out
or trying to get a satisfactory answer
a satisfactory as you can
for why he killed himself
and then along the way
we're learning things about Deutsche Bank
and about things that are in the news
do you have that certain in you
sure
okay
this makes sense
this makes sense because he says they have breaking news
so this will be
you'll be one of many characters that are
around the book but
it will probably be a second wave
what do you say? there'll be a breaking news that
somehow this podcast fits around
where do you get that from?
because he says your breaking news is short
what does he say?
I ask him do you want some breaking news as well?
yeah sure
I think you may
but also before you hit play
why don't you get Scott some breaking news tomorrow?
well before any news breaks
the reason what we said to him
you think all of us at the Georgia
we didn't say one nice thing which is true
we went through it word by word
and then I said didn't you get what we sent you
because you probably don't understand what that is
so we went through it word by word
and we wrote everything out
like what is mischaracterization
what is accurate and what's inaccurate
and we sent it to him
and to Nick Summers
and his editor and other women
which I guess is on another
the one you didn't bring
the part you didn't bring
it must be all in there and when we talked about her
yeah I remember that
so we'll give that to you too if you want it
and how much time before
they came did you send to a week?
right after the article
not to the daily though
you sent it to
and as a people
I thought you were sending it to the producer before he came
no no no
David is not that for three months
after the article
was published in your times
we went through it and we sent it to David
and his editors
yeah and that's when you had the call about like oh technically
yes yes yes
okay I understand
we're trying to get a satisfactory answer
as satisfactory as you can
for why he killed himself
and then you know along the way
we're learning things about Deutsche Bank
and about things that are in the news
do you have that statement?
sure
I don't know
but I'll give it to you
can I say anything to finish?
I'm sorry I've interjected too many times
and stopped myself many times
we've had many conversations
many
and you put me
one time in the book
I'm only in three pages
in the book
and the only quote I've decided to use
is a negative quote which I don't even
think
I've said
I know exactly what you're talking about
and of all the things
I've told you about
that's what you've decided to put
everything
the first day I met you at that cafe
in New York
beautiful things about him
and our meeting and everything
and at that time
some red flags really came to my head
because you said
well you're the first person that has
so many positive things to say about
and I was like
oh that's odd
first of all
why would you say that to me?
if it was true
why would you say that to a woman
that is telling you about
that and she's enamored
I mean that's
disturbing
and over
the last two years
I've told you so many good things about him
and you've only chosen
one sentence
that says
nothing about our relationship
or about who he is
and I've given you some insight about
him and his personality I think
you have Marie
a lot of our conversations have been off the record
no that's not true
really? are you saying our conversations
have all been on the record?
when was the last time we spoke?
I had not
your email after mine
it's like obviously we've been chatting
and obviously you
putting all the
negative things in there
that makes you also
Marie if you want our conversations to all be on the record
that's fine but they're not right now
and you should just
is that why you decided
of all the conversations we've had
you've decided to use
a quote that is negative
about how?
I don't think the quote was negative about that
what was the quote? something to be effective
right when you first met
he sleeps all day is depressed
I thought the quote you were referring to
is he thought that
sleeping with his mom's best friend
was a good way to get back at her
you told me that
that's another bullshit
I read the book
that's in the book
no it's in the first part of the epilogue
I read the book
you're referring to this
well the book hasn't been
David we went through the different versions
you added just a few paragraphs
it's exactly the same copy I have
in the epilogue
I'm in the epilogue
in three pages and
one quote that you use for me
and that you know with what it's by me
is the negative one
I think it's all good
she's saying she feels like you
I understand what you're saying
you just represented her
my feelings please
you picked only negative things to further your agenda
of feigning a negative fortune
is what she's trying to do
I shared my feelings for you
and you didn't use them
I mean there's only one sentence
I think it is
clear when you're living with someone
and you're in a serious relationship with them
that you love them
no it's not
yes it is
and you don't show
I don't
so it's
you're saying the reader who can read between the lines
when the only quote I have
is a negative one
but she really loves him
I'll let the book speak for itself
I think that based on the feedback I've gotten
so far from people who don't know you
they think
frankly I haven't asked about you
but they think that you come off pretty well
you're complicated and you're flawed the way you are
but they think you come off pretty well
and if
you've actually read the book
that's being published as opposed to whatever you've looked at in the past
exact same book
well I don't know, I can't answer that
you don't even need to, it doesn't really matter to me
there's
the version of the book that is being published
which
all I can say is I stand by it
I'm proud of it
and I think it reflects you
you're a protagonist
along with your father
you're probably the main protagonists
and I'm proud of it
but it wouldn't have happened without you
I'm really really grateful
for
the work you provided for
to help you provide it
and
yeah and it honestly
it pains me to
this is not a pleasant afternoon for me
I was just not intended to be
it already it pains me
to know
the anger and grief
that you guys are feeling toward me
and this afternoon
not toward you that you have caused
you did it
you caused this
you were careless, you caused this
okay
these are the consequences
part of the consequences
it affects
other people
it affects me of course
and then it ricochets
and it affects Marie
child's life
and I feel awful about that
okay well mission accomplished
do something about it
no there's nothing
look
guys I am
part of what we're doing here is the solution
to this we want you
in your own words
to essentially tell your story
it's a compelling story
it's a story that I think belongs fully unfiltered
out in the open for the public
and we very much want that
that's something that service the daily
can provide
with your help
that's we're not coming in here
with any tricks of our sleeves
and
we're eager to hear
your story in your own words
and that's what we're trying to say at the outset
before we started all this
we want you to be
we want this in your voice
so
let's try to say those words are you
you've only interviewed him for two years
I've been interviewing him for six years
or whatever
okay
alright you guys
thank you
okay so what's the plan
12 o'clock tomorrow
okay
alright
you're actually right
can you guys
ask him
as long as we're still rolling
I'm not gonna
oh no
there's more
I'm sure there's another car there
what is the question
like 50 minutes to just transfer that
I got what I could man
what was my question
another one
another one is
these are other ones that were on there
what did I ask
I don't remember
do you remember what she asked
I don't
if you
if you base your book
on fraud
I have a life
the most important part
is when he's downstairs
oh right
I don't have the downstairs part
wait let me see that
the recording was upstairs
thank you
I gotta go meet someone
can you give me that
no
it's a 50 gigabyte file
any of the shit
so starting the late nights
I gotta go
it doesn't sound like you have to
anyway it's been I appreciate you guys
thank you
thank you so much
I'll send you
an audio
I love that
thanks
that was it
I gotta go man
drink the booze in here
no I'm not bringing the fucking booze in here
no I gotta keep my life
separate from this shit man
we can have fun
I leave Wednesday
I got some shit to do
okay go
I did what I could
we were gonna go out with you
I'll see you tomorrow
believe me
we'll be here tomorrow what time are you coming
thank you
what time
10 30
okay
but
you know
I got a lot of clarification from this
I wanna talk about it tomorrow
cause now I know what to ask
cause it's too overwhelming to know
what to ask
a dispute because now I have to go to David
and I'll make the same deal with David
if he wants to watch over that footage
cause I mean they have the audio
but you know what I'm saying
I think it's only fair
because that's how I wanna question him too
two or three things that of my
you know of the way I'm looking at this story
and again what I think you need to
what I'm focused on
what I'm gonna keep asking you and him
is about these fraudulent pink ones
because
Tom Bowers
um
and particularly now that we know that he was evicted
and um
you know depressed and
helped him
I got him calling his report today
but he helped him
was he getting divorced?
did you guys say I had to call him?
yeah from Scott
did you get it?
no I didn't see it but I saw you tweeted
did it have anything surprising?
I'll tell you tomorrow on the camera
okay
yeah
yeah so you
I mean actually I think this was necessary
it was
it was and that's the thing
if it wasn't recorded by them
and I understand
that you didn't record it
and that's that you know it's not
we do need to like I need to look at that with you
because I don't I would have not caught
I wouldn't be able to describe
the things that I need to
ask questions about because there's such
is there something that I don't understand?
no
not at all
okay
I'm just gonna go home
there's not a footage of you and David
chatting in the cafe
I wish
I thought the camera would follow him out
no I told him to stay on here
if I follow them out like I'm kind of creepy
you know I'm already kind of creepy being here
obviously
one saying when David showing up
I was a little creepy you know I'm like
I told him
I told him I'd leave
you were talking documentary
well look
you know the good thing
the case of that is like
I could have called I had three choices
I could have called David and went up and said
hey I'm doing this doc and Val
Val doesn't want me to tell you about it
and then I wouldn't have anything to shoot because you tell me to fuck off
I could have
you know I asked you
you're not gonna tell him and
the third way is when he comes like
you know
call his bluff I guess
he didn't even have to
he wanted to mic up
so I'm glad that it worked out that way
well I mean
he wants it on record obviously
we also did not
it was going to happen
he thought he could win
he had no idea we'd get
buried
David's ego there is very arrogant
he thought he could win
of course
he thinks he's in the right
he thinks he's a trap
he doesn't think there's a trap
he's a trap
well I mean I didn't want it to be a trap
he could say get the fuck out of here
I think it's interesting I don't think it
I think what comes out of this is
you know he'll sell maybe
a couple more books
you have your story told
and you know
how can anyone be all that upset about it
either way everyone gets a little bit more of what they want
hopefully though
there are some of these loan documents
and there's a whole different
story
that's kind of what is needed
to happen at real time