hello hello hello Tim yeah Tim how you doing all right how are you I'm shitty
man it's like you threw me under the bus I didn't ask for you under the bus two
things okay first of all I didn't say you have a chemical dependency problem I
said you admitted to previously having a chemical dependency problem wow that's
that's very different than what they wrote did you see what they're doing
day yeah I did I did that's night and day yeah and then secondly I wanted to
reach out to you but I can't I mean it's it's it's it's like obstructing the
justice type of thing is it because I called about what's his name the
Bowers it was it was no what's a virus no Bowers Bowers remember when I called you
and I got Carmen and and and jammy and and you guys are gonna call me back in
five minutes and all this information I had no ideas Bowers was even dead and I
called you telling you about Tom Bowers and the David Enrin's relationship and
he had to learn about it yeah yeah yeah no you never call me back I said emails
and calls I hear you I hear you that's on that's on that's I'm not throwing people
under the bus but that's on jammy and Carmen we were trying to we were trying
to divide and conquer yeah I mean we're drowning yeah and you've been doing
thank you for everything you gave us and my my response to them was hey can you
guys manage what Val's giving and I'll manage the other aspects and I should
have been on top of them or more I apologize one other thing that I mean
now that now that the cat's out of the hat and that he sent that report the
other thing I did mention to the gentleman was hey listen I was in their
house and I'm not at you know I'm not a an expert in you know in child services
I think but you know he appears to be loved he had a dedicated you know nice
child friendly living space I mean he has his bedroom up there yeah he loves it
man and I'm so thank you thank you how come that does not come through on here
how come they changed your words perverted and I don't know you said he
talked to a guy Sabah is a woman she says she's looking directly I spoke with
I spoke with a gentleman in the FBI or DCFS the DSF DCFS she says you know what
no I spoke I spoke to a gentleman but I think there was a woman conference in
but she didn't do any of the talking with the gentleman that did that most of
the talking so that's completely taken out of context your words I mean yeah I
think so and they certainly didn't say they were gonna generate a report and I
would have liked to have read the report she's a man I'll show if you want to
I'll send it to you man it is outrageously bizarre yeah like our lawyer we
got a lawyer that's fucking expensive man for this and you look at this he's
done this 10,000 times at this district you've never seen anything like this I'll
say I will take from the limited experience I've had I mean in New York I've
made obviously I've made arrests and whatnot and the circumstances surrounding
in those situations were horrendous and nothing was done and in those
circumstances I've made referrals I called I called an agent out of Los
Angeles an agent out of Houston that I know that deals with this sort of stuff
and they asked if you would be okay if I forwarded you there forwarded them your
information they might be able to help okay all right one guy's name is one
guy's name is Kevin I need a pen hold on Marie by the way Marie is here and
Tim how are you good how are you Mary here let me write this down sorry you
said what's it actually David David Ho H.O. David and I don't know I don't know
the LA agent's name but he told me that he knows somebody in LA okay you have a
number so can I give him I'll give him your number perfect okay so I'll wait for
David okay all right I'll do that now and then yeah I wanted to call you I
couldn't but and I do think some of that was taken out of context and I'd be
happy to you know how you could fix it you know what you do we need witness
statements so people that have been if that have seen Marie and I and Marla
together and just saying that we're normal good people you know from what I've
seen Marla is happy he's well-fed my god man this listen to buy there's a
bipolar woman living next door and Steve is the is will not let her divorce
Steve has been like doing I can't will do that getting into too much he's been
it like just obsessively trying to get me out of her life so he can keep her
after 10 years of being separate and trying to get it so he's using this
bipolar woman she says I have 50 cell phones okay she does I'm not even
making that up I'll send you her statement 50 cell phones Marlo is foraging
through the garbage in a barefoot and wearing only shorts to find food after
after midnight right says that Marie is also dumpster diving for furniture and
clothes what does it say what does it say it's crazy out there shit man and
these people at DCFS are so incompetent they can't see tell
when they're talking to a crazy bipolar woman yeah it escalates because Steve
feeds her and all this comes from Steve and two friends of Steve's that say
that we're drug addicts from 2018 18 right yeah see in France where is he
Steve is here he won't go anywhere close to Marie he's from Australia but he's
still here in the police he's like 20 minutes away you cannot leave versus site
he hasn't had a girlfriend in 10 years like look the basic gist he had a
aneurysm in his back which left him paralyzed from the waist down in 2004 he
has a catheter to go to the bathroom he the guy has he can't no erection he has
not had sex in over 14 years right so that that will erode someone's brain and
Marie has seen it escalate lately so what she did during coronavirus because
he got so scary for her that she decided I'm not gonna give Marlo back for the
next three months so I'm gonna keep him now because they don't have a custody
arrangement so she kept him for the last five months yeah and she's scared a lot
of people around here but not to do you know good and that's good it's good to
hear because she was terrified what's gonna happen and this is his retaliation
calling DCFS four times in a row four times and they come in here and then at
first like if you read the report you'll see everything's great for the first 14
pages and all of a sudden we're the worst people in the world and there all
right but if you could write a witness statement Tim that would and that would
be a clincher that would be so fucking valuable and helpful for us from coming
from you especially all right yeah I don't think a problem with it I had to
bounce it off of my legal folks I mean it's already it's already my concern would
be disclosing our relationship but I think that's already out there I don't
think that I don't think it would be a huge issue okay let me also understand
your information to the to the agents out there right now and if you don't
hear from them in the next couple of days circle back to me we'll do all right
two days if I don't hear from them we'll circle back we would circle back David
Ho is the name we're sorry Mary would you say I mean if you don't want to talk
about your affairs and what you did with Val you can just say I can satisfy that
these people are not abusing the child yeah and they're not yeah our relationship
doesn't matter as much as what your your perception of our the relationship is
Marie and myself and Marlon yeah we're feeding him this food in the fridge he's
got his own room he's happy kid you know yeah okay all right all right circle
back in a couple of days we don't hear anything all right Tim thank you so much
thank you I'll send you I'll email you two examples of the witness statements
we've been getting from our friends so you just have like an idea of what it
looks like okay okay sounds good actually thanks again thanks again yep
yep bye