going okay great okay so we were just getting into your parent your arrival in
the United States and so 1982 Ola and Alexander get divorced yeah you go to
live with your dad yeah and then I go through some of the frankly like awful
memories you have so we've got you him your dad taking you to a horror movie and
you were so scared to be puked in the aisle Halloween what was hell oh that
was the movie okay we've got your dad collapsing on the floor yeah frothing at
the mouth like what the fuck was it and then we've got you guys ending up in
the selection army homeless shelter and it which we've found together in those
documents you got from Cook County and it one hot day in May of 1982 the juvenile
court takes custody and it you know I'm just quoting from the court filing
saying that you're neglected and that the miners parent does not provide the care
necessary for the miners while being citing the mental and or physical
disability of the parent noting that the court tried to track down your mom even
running a newspaper ad in Chicago Sun-Times unsuccessfully and it turned
out that she was staying in her mother's apartment which is just like a few miles
away and so off you go into foster care which is like I'm not just doing this
with a camera but it's that like on the scale of the pain associated with your
dad's death which is worse like how does that come how does that these memories
compare to that memory I mean well these memories are few and far between but
they're not pleasant yeah I can't even imagine
okay so now we switch back a bit to Bill's narrative and it he goes to
Northwestern he goes to business school Northwestern did you exempt all this
speculation about my mom yes okay should we say it for fun it's not necessary
um man that fun
okay so he gets a job that by the way was that shank I'm not since I'm not using
that one good it was it was like one of the people that was in his circle at the
time college friends I can't remember if the guy went to college I remember it was
just in that circle okay I mean he said it on the record but I'm just since we're
not you said it on the right yet was it verified by anyone else no okay um let's
see okay so he graduated from business school gets a job of continental Illinois
which is one of the biggest banks in the country at the time and this is where he
really gets in derivatives and it's a blah blah blah I spent with derivatives are
81 this is let's see what year is this yeah this is 81 or 82 and so this time
derivatives were pretty much a sleepy tool used by a few banks by this it was it
was like becoming a kind of an expanding lucrative niche for lots of banks like
mortgages no it was well they were starting to one of your dad's
innovations and I'll look kind of getting out of order here and that's fine
okay was well let's just wait actually I'll go through it and of it so one day
your dad it's actually a little unclear exactly where your parents met but
there's the leading theory that I've heard it's a party what was that I can
always know the story of the party what I've heard from more people is that he
went into the Stanley Corsac store for some reason and met her I think this is
after this party maybe that's the way I remember the story you see you remember
the story being that they met like at a mutual friend's party yeah okay and then
you went to see her at the store a few times oh that's interesting so okay well
in any case the they became a couple they got engaged in 1983 and in March of
1984 Reverend Jack officiated their wedding so we go through some more of
your like not very pleasant foster care memories here which we don't need to do
unless you want to which ones I want to okay sure I'm happy to if you want to
sure okay so and we talked about this a little bit yesterday there's this
wonderful photo of you and your dad together in the I guess in the social
workers place and you know you seated together on the carpet and there's a
game and I just physically describe you guys and there's like a big pile the
brown leather jacket on an orange sofa and a small pile of black and white
photos that I guess you guys were looking at together maybe back from your
time in Ukraine but a picture of him on a it's really tank right he sent that to
you didn't wasn't that was after he disappeared that wasn't I think so yeah
I mean my memory is foggy yeah yeah and then he had sent me a photo of him on a
tank and a toy tank and a canteen Israeli canteen like a army canteen right but
that was after he disappeared I think so so there's another very painful memory
about you're in the basement of the social workers office with a bunch of
other kids you're bickering over the rules of connect for yes the door at the
top of the stairs opens all the kids stop what they're doing someone's name is
gonna get called and that means their parents are there for a visit and you're
not just a visit to take yeah your your name gets called you run up the stairs
your mom's gonna be there maybe she's gonna take you home and it's not your
mom it's Helen the social worker and she's there to inform me that you're
being assigned to a new family did you talk to her no I didn't I don't even know
she's still alive yeah this is a long time ago
I remember her she was in very nice it's kind of short long blonde hair nice voice
Midwestern very kind person
okay and she would take me from one home to the other whenever leave one she'd
always take me and drive me I remember always stopping McDonald's cuz I love
McDonald's he doesn't love McDonald's at that age every kid yeah yes she was very
nice get some more water but yeah go on sorry okay so we kind of shift gears a
little bit here for a while that stuff's not related to you guys so in
early 1984 Edson hires Bill at Merrill and yeah which is right as continental
Illinois is about to collapse so it's fortuitous time so he was poached yeah
he was hot Edson hired that's an idea so how did Edson meet him they that's a
little unclear actually how they met they were both working in Chicago banking
for a while they're both at Connell no Edson was at Bank of America okay anyway
your parents moved to Short Hills so it doesn't want to know about two pots are
sick I know it's okay just to give her a quick text I'm just we can just keep it
rolling okay um don't make you go on yeah she says a casual pizza place or
something more upscale like manual at LA what do you do mine I mean what do you
want to do is it nice yeah they're paying and let's it's unhappiness ours by
house in words yeah yeah is it would be open run seven
no oh yeah yeah she's gonna do it yeah great okay okay it sounds fine so I'm
accustomed to dealing with no I did I want to meet him but yeah get rid of
him I'm curious to meet him okay wait there wait hang on hang on they're gonna
pay for this I don't know they haven't said we're paying so should I just say are
you paying yeah yeah say if you're paying that sounds great with like a
smiley okay yeah I'm assuming you're paying smiley yeah or Roseanne is
depends he's paying I'm not coming from oh I see that's when he takes me to a
restaurant it's always like Donald well we're just talking about the reality is
always looking down smiley face sounds great depends he's paying exclamation
smiley face sometimes just a lot easier to write smiley face than to actually go
find the emoji for smiley face David I are working right now I'll just let her
know I'll just stay she's okay all right let's keep going here okay so shortly
after they arrive in Short Hills they decide that they want you yeah and it
takes a while but by Thanksgiving of 1985 all is granted custody of you you're
nine years old by this time I thought that was 1984 it's 1985 she initiated
proceeding in 1984 but it was not until 1985 that she got you back those fall of
85 yes Thanksgiving and it so I'll look at some counseling at the request of
Jersey social services and it gets the family you guys get a caseworker who
comes and visits and the caseworker notes that you have lots of toys in a
very nice bedroom and what you want you tend to get and that you're having it's
caseworker said what I want to get not in those words but yeah that you get lots
of material possessions however you're having it's taking a while for you to
get like to open up emotionally to your parents understandably you're starting to
give hugs and kisses but you're also insisting on calling them by their
first names your parents quote C Val is testing their authority and commitment
to him she noted at one point when quote when confronted with a parental
demand Val tons ask why and repeatedly asked the question to every
explanation offered Bill grumbled to the caseworker that you quote occasionally
cut corners in the completion of tasks but the caseworker says happily that
the difficulties encountered have been dealt with adequately and with
increasing skill for all concerned the predominant attitude is that of
optimism remember having to call it so many people dad so it's like everyone
wants me to call them dad and that's interesting yeah so what do you mean the
foster family yeah every foster family it's like call me dad okay you're not my
dad but we want you to call us me dad and her mom so he's always dad and mom
and every time it just it gets to be too much after three homes so yeah so after
yeah I remember my mom saying you have to call him dad call him dad okay dad dad
so he just sort of got into the you know the pattern of doing so but yeah I
remember that was a big issue it's these notes that the case worker left I mean
when you go through foster homes every foster family wants you to call them mom
or dad for in my case so it's just it's very awkward to have to do that and once
you get comfortable calling someone dad then you're going to another home you
have to call someone else mom and dad and as a kid it's very confusing yeah I
can't even imagine and then you sort of let it go after a while okay this is mom
and dad and you don't think about it but then every time you're taken out and
put into a new situation it's you know and look I yeah I mean and I think it's
probably completely normal that yeah reunited with your mom and the
stranger who you've never met before like you're not in the middle of my dad I
mean we sat in the back of a Volvo in Chicago when he told me that we were
gonna move to New Jersey and he was getting married to my mom and what I
thought about it well you didn't really ask now I don't think that's right
because I remember this is a gas station because my mom went to go to the gas
station and I was in the car and that's my dad took the time to talk to me so you
met him in Chicago yeah because you were still in foster care and they had
moved to New Jersey before you were out of foster care yeah so it must have just
been for a visit I suspect that they were there interesting okay that's good and
we went out and there was a couple times we went to Maine and I flew for
Thanksgiving that might have been the year before 1984 where they took me from
foster care to Maine for Thanksgiving and then I met all those bad whole family
there and then I went back to foster care I remember this okay that's good I
didn't I didn't know that okay so Bill at work
he is Merrill is like just out of control in those days coke in the
bathrooms strippers on the trading floor and your dad by those standards is a
complete nerd coke on the bathrooms in the Maryland yeah yeah that sounds about
yeah not that your dad was partaking but the answer he was really of course I
don't know that it's not the impression other colleagues had of him at the time
and he was described as a very nerdy kind of flabby and unathletic the last guy
you picked for a sports team maybe not at work but maybe afterward there's the
stuff about you know he twirls his pen when he's nervous which I also do and the
eyebrow tugging which is everyone who you told me about
let's see but look he's just like a he's kind of math skills bordering on the
savant and brilliant and yeah it's a great method for multiplying three
digit numbers I remember I can't remember his should remember it but I was
trying to explain it to you once a year ago you know you have like a 367 times
492 the way you broke it down and do it in your head was brilliant that's crazy
I've realized not that long ago that I have actually no idea how to do like
multiplication like that anymore yeah no I did back in school they like yeah
division either yeah division is terrible so I have confidence finance
editor of the New York Times baby it's okay so he became not only like the math
wiz around there but was very he was kind of like a creative engineer and was
cooking up all these new types of derivatives that and back in this is
kind of like a transitional point in the finance industry at this point where
derivatives originally were conceived of I know you know but as a way for like
businesses to protect themselves against risks like interest rates change in or
dairy price if you're an ice cream company you know you want to hedge against
yeah exactly and but this is a point where they were also becoming like
gambling devices basically and so yeah at this point yeah they were credit
derivatives I mean credit derivative no not stuff like of that major but like
gambling version well interest rate swaps which were the one of the things
that your dad really pioneered worse in the they're in the infancy insurance
against against well that's what I'm saying it was it was both right I mean
the swamps were very good for clients and that's kind of the way your dad
manufactured them and the purpose they had but they were also the reason this
became such a lucrative business on Walter is in part there was a lot of
trading going on around them and so your dad when people realize that you can
make you can make money on these on the bets against bats yeah exactly huge
thing right so I've got a bunch of people here talking about the role your dad
played just how creative he was like what an instrumental role he played one
of his colleagues from back in the day who I'm not naming in this but he's a
guy who rose to the very top of Wall Street yeah says quote because of people
like Bill but maybe none more so than Bill the derivatives business went
mainstream in usage for investors as well as corporations financial
institutions and government agencies so he was really in the development of the
swaps market what your dad pioneered was one of the very most important things
that changed the finance industry over the past 40 years so Edson loved it
making a lot of money he and your dad actually once sat for an interview
together with the Chicago Caribbean this is in 1992 and they've got it's kind of
hilarious because Edson you know gregarious and charismatic is like such
a character yeah just palette Edson such a character you just kind of you know
like hamming it up kind of with the reporter and like all these kind of
like nice quotes very smooth and then your dad says his quote is we simulate
40 interest rates in yours every night it is a brute force simulated hedging
strategy it's a just like you know it's such a nerd yeah he plays a straight guy
to Edson yeah he plays a straight guy to Edson's Joker Laurel Hardy sort of
that's a good way of thinking about it and they're becoming as you know like
really good friends and the fan like you know that's it was a great great guy I
don't tell you I'm sure I told you I'm like everyone tells me that it's a great
great guy someone told me this anecdote I mean let's not get into the Edson
stuff he's that's just gonna derail us here oh no it's here it value it's two
o'clock right now yeah and we've been doing this for like an hour and a half
and a lot of time we're on page 28 right now everything else secondary to this
we're on page 28 of a 350 page book okay so if we continue at this pace we can
cancel dinner I mean it's fine just keep going I want everything Edson is you
know who Edson is your dad let's talk about how you how you have processed the
he is charismatic he is he is someone charismatic gregarious impulsive and needs
someone by his side to reign him in absolutely and who is that person that's my dad correct
and a lot of things say your dad apart and obviously his math skills the kind of
innovations with derivatives but one of the biggest things is that he is like
he's not a threat to people and he knows how to ask questions and he really wants
the answers he doesn't want to trick you he's got very correct yeah and he's got an
ability to listen also to hear but Edson are my dad your dad yeah okay there's
which is not the norm on wall street right like there's this is a place
while it's like filled everyone's trying to bulldoze well it's like well it's either that
it's like the it's kind of the kind of vaguely sociopathic personalities sure and it's these
socially maldraught like math nerds right who can't and your dad fits someone in between
yes exactly he's an early quant yeah but he he had human skills he didn't and that's normally
a lot of the quants are kind of like mildly on the spectrum and I don't well well you know you've
worked with a you know Tom or Todd Tom Tom um uh everyone in banking wants to make money but
there are different degrees of avarice one of Bill's colleagues and friends would explain
Bill was on the low end of that spectrum yeah um uh um there's a great anecdote
this isn't really involving well it is there's a guy named John Bright who is a particle
physicist at Merrill well he's a risk manager at Merrill he is a particle physicist by training
okay so Merrill was higher okay uh well they were they're higher in creating a halogen collider
thankfully no um but he was a risk manager and he was obviously very smart and he routinely would
say tell Edson's traders no we can't do that for this or that reason right and Edson would just
lose this shit and just erupt and we're like we'll fire you and Bill repeatedly would intervene
and save his job and say that's his job no no it would save John Bright so the risk manager who's
about to lose his job he's Edson's angry that the guy want to prove the trades his team wants to do
Bill intervenes and protects him saying that he's right um uh
talk a little bit about the Russian-Turkish baths and um vacation together in Maine
yeah he loved us but that place the baths yeah um and in Maine he told because he lived in
Rangeley and he bought a place down the street right in Brooklyn right yeah and Edson's kids
your parents is kind of a cool cultured couple uh in part because Allah seemed to derive pleasure
from tormenting Bill just kind of playfully uh I mean I don't know how playful that was uh
maybe um uh let's see Allah converts from Judaism to become Protestant yeah
for the parties she threw parties for the party oh for the parties well she would also throw
parties and she threw a great party she always was very good at that um people who went to some
of the parties would say that each time they went there they would notice that the dining room seemed
to have changed colors yeah and there's another party where um my mom's a very gifted interior
yeah she I mean that's what there's one party that she specifically put gold leaf all over the
ceilings uh which made quite an impression um okay so you at this time are having some troubles
it sounds like um the one person described how you had it I mean there were just stories going
around about what had happened to your actual your birth father right and you had told someone that
you had discovered him dead of a drug overdose again this isn't like you're in like fifth grade
not dead this is the way this person remembers it um uh there's a point in also in fifth grade
where you briefly ran away from home as this person recalls it this is one of your friends
in fifth grade yeah Pat um Patrick Gorman yeah he's got it all wrong okay does he what happened
I never ran away from home what's he referring to and I never saw my father dead of a drug overdose
so I he's referring to no no he's not saying no this wasn't just Pat by the way this is someone
else as well there's um it doesn't matter let's I know it's important I mean I never ran away from
home um what's he referring to he's referring to when I was going to be sent to Rocky Mountain
Academy then I thought we had a plan of uh breaking me driving to Florida to live at my
friend's Florida house and stealing the car and driving all the way to Florida but it was just
a bunch of talk and no one never did anything and instead I got on the plane the next day and went to
the SUWS in Idaho and then from there I went to Rocky Mountain Academy he's saying this is in
fifth grade though and that was not until like your what junior and senior year of high school yeah
this is much later he's saying this is happening in fifth grade yep I ran away from home in fifth
grade I mean not for like a long time but like there is he just got his brief um he ran away to
my friend's house possibly to spend the night there it's not a deal let's move on that was
strange um and um and I remember you back I'm recounting the wonderful tale of you your dad
taking you to work at Merrill and you were about 12 and uh he's introducing you around and one of
poor colleagues comes up and says oh I could see the resemblance that was funny and my dad I looked
at each other and just laughed yeah that's what he and and Bill told the colleague there was an
inside joke and tried to kind of make him feel better about himself um and um and so
so okay um
I've talked to a number of people who perceived
feel like they noticed at the time uh that there was much more warmth from your dad to your sisters
than to you okay um my sisters or babies or kids well this is by the time we are getting a little
bit older at this point um uh I don't have a specific year but this was probably when you were
like 12 or 13 or so yeah my sisters were yeah they were young they were there's a lot of warmth to
my sisters when you're kids and babies and children there was everyone had warmth to them
yeah everyone has warmth toward little kids I agree yeah um you can't uh
I'm not making much effort I'm saying I'm trying to qualify warmth from the 13 year old son to two
two babies it's very it's a very strange statement that someone would make at that
a couple of people made that statement anyway there's it's a perception thing right and like
it's not necessarily a right perception or a wrong perception okay so you're at 13 if I've
got this right you were sent to Dublin school is that right um yeah okay uh and you were kicked out
after a while for smoking yes and having weed is that the first time I was kicked out for smoking
on the charlotte's right and then the second time I was kicked out for smoking weed yeah okay um
and um and you all the time had like asked and that weed came from uh the writer what's his
fucking name again this is blank the other writer that's always pg o rork pg o rork's weed yes
um he grew it in his in his backyard in uh peterborough or let's see a joining town
exit Dublin I think it's peterborough that's where he lives okay for some reason he liked to have
high school kids hang out at his house and smoke weed it's a very strange guy yeah that's strange
yeah it's very strange okay so um
during this time you kind of periodically asked like why you had been in foster care yeah and
what I've got here is in particular your grandmother so all his mother yeah giving these kind of like
vague and not very convincing explanations about something about drinking bad milk yeah
something about your birth father's hospital I remember I went to the hospital um and my
grandmother we said it was from drinking bad milk and I remember being in this cage because
I was a kid so they had to put you in a crib but the crib had a top on it and that was like the
most claustrophobic crazy thing ever and I'm like screaming and yelling trying to get out of this
fucking cage and the nurses would come in and open up the top like I could breathe again it was just
terrible that sounds terrible it was terrible it was really bad I remember I think that's where
my this is before or after foster care this is during foster care wow at some point I don't
know why I had to go to the hospital and my grandmother said it was some bad milk I think
it was related to the time my father and I don't know what I mean I've always been told it's an
overdose but I don't know for sure if that was it's still the truth but again I get contradicting
stories right constantly um but I do remember being in the hospital what did your mom say
when you would ask her why you've been in foster care um she said it was my father was a drug addict
he's a terrible person and she was a great person and why did she then not get you out of foster
care yes sorry no definable no answer that's the sticks okay and they're they're always changing
to like when I was a kid it would be one thing when I got older was another thing so okay so you
then get sent off to Rocky Mountain Academy for your junior and senior years yeah and the high
school and the and the sophomore junior and senior yeah oh these are three years I thought
well it's like the second half of sophomore okay um uh so while you're there one of your classmates
is this guy this kid John Avila John Avila yeah um who is kind of a dork that people you know
did you describe the school yeah I described this I just the school is crazy it's crazy yeah um
uh but one day in 1994 and again this isn't even from you know you told me the story originally
but I verified this through um just their local news articles at the time uh how do you say it
Avila uh John Avila okay he uses a belt to hang himself from a pipe in his dorm room yeah and it
my dorm room that was actually your room uh yes that's my dorm room and I became the
dorm head like the guy in charge of the the dorm afterwards okay I'll move back in there um yeah
sorry no no no sorry no I became it was my dorm room after so when they for a month no one lived
in that in that dorm and then when they allowed people to move back in I was the one living in
there in the the dorm head of that okay this is called Camelot the name of the dorm is Camelot I
remember um yeah see I hung myself from the belt I had been living in a different dorm okay to that
um and anyway that obviously was like not uh that was a scarring experience and you
found yourself for years thinking about that and that was the end of that school
yeah from right back from that point when that suicide happened it took down the school
it did not right away it didn't that was there is 2002 yeah but it was a slow climb and that yeah
I mean that was yeah eight years later um it and then other incidents appeared to right yeah okay so um
then we get into the whole Orange County debacle right and your dad's role in it which is kind of a
seminal moment for him because he turned him into a superstar yeah it turned him and it kind of
created the legend of Bill yeah um and I don't think we need to go through that right now you know
that story this is like the story is what you know it to be did you find a copy of the memo yeah okay
um and okay all sorts of history about Deutsche Bank which we're not going to go through right now
one of the last things my dad was asking uh in December uh or fall of 2013 was if I had to copy
that memo because he wanted it and I sent it to him oh that's interesting yeah I was like why do you
want to say because he was going to start looking for new stuff and he wanted to copy the memo to
send to some employers or somebody for some some reason yeah I haven't actually found a copy of the
memo what I found or like there's like substantial excerpts of it yeah that were published at the
time in like the LA Times I'll see if I can find the full memo for you again um but yeah um okay and
that memo saved Merrill well that memo actually hurt Merrill in a sense because I did Merrill from
no it showed that it actually he was the opposite of that right it was like it showed Bill doing the
right thing yeah very much but Merrill disregarded his vice no no no Merrill way understood it was
that Merrill the Orange County said uh Merrill it'll advise them yes and my dad said uh this you know
Orange County don't do this deal don't do the trade yeah and on advice of Merrill because he
represented Merrill no that's not quite right the so Merrill had the West Coast sales team that was
selling all this shit to Orange County and it Bill and John Bright the risk manager the particle
physicist I mentioned earlier got we're getting very nervous about this and so and no one would
really listen and so Bill sat down and wrote this long memo showed it to Edson Edson signed the memo
and then they sent it far and wide in Merrill Merrill there's like a bit of a civil war inside
Merrill that's overstating a bit of a tug of war inside Merrill they disregarded it ultimately
and kept selling even more and that worked for another year yes okay and so the fact that Merrill
had known that this is really risky right actually hurt them but that's like definitely not your dad's
fault that's well the your dad can come out of that in suit in one of the case yeah they have billions
of dollars so or they're sued for billions not sure they should got it okay so Edson
got hired at Deutsche Bank I had confused it in my head you're right Edson got hired at Deutsche
in 95 first thing he does is well he hired a bunch of people there well they retired first
what do you mean they both retired Edson and my dad had retired first Edson didn't retire first
I think he did no I mean I've got the chronology pretty solidly from people around him he he got
the job offer he took a helicopter at Princeton in Jersey where there's a retreat from Merrill
and told him I'm done give me the helicopter back to New York oh really he went to lunch that day
and I didn't know that interesting so Edson's first person he wants to hire is your dad
he doesn't do that well your dad says no and I'll get to why in a second he ends up hiring
kind of a small clique of people from Merrill one of whom one is Cassie Cabetti yeah do you
know Cassie yeah I do and who's a comedian okay another is Michael Phillip I don't know if you
ever crossed paths with him I don't remember Michael and another is Anshu Anshu so Bill said no
and Cassie's a brilliant guy too yeah I know and had a supermodel for a wife for a while yeah
so Bill said no part of it is that like it seemed like Edson was taking this huge risk
another part of it a big part was the Orange County mess was still playing out
who said no what was that who said no Bill said no your father said no I'm not kind of with you
Edson and the Orange County mess was still playing out in the legal system and in the press
and your dad wanted to stay at Merrill to help clean it up the biggest thing though is that he
was tired and which is a little unusual for a 40-year-old investment banker to admit to but
he wanted a break and so he announced he got in agreement with Merrill in March of 96
that he was retiring or taking a paid leave of absence Merrill's public statement at the time was
that he was leaving to spend more time with his family which is typically like a euphemism for
someone resigning in disgrace but in your dad's case it was actually true one little bit of hilarity
that I love is that when Bill rebuffed Edson Edson you know like the normal the normal thing to do
that situation is you know beg and plead and then if he says no okay see you later dude right uh
instead Edson enlisted Bill to interview job candidates on his behalf for jobs at Deutsche
Bank for even though even though Bill was his competitor right and Bill did it yeah and I've
talked to a couple of people who he interviewed and is like he was that's funny he's a good job
and candidate interviewer Edson's way to get him to take the job so yeah well the way to get him to
take the job that I want you to have the way that he got him to take the job was they were both families
were in Maine a few months later so a few months after Bill retires in March of 96 and Bill is still
saying no no no no although he'd missed the adrenaline on Wall Street uh the issue of working
for a German bank was kind of unpalatable for the Brooksman family given what uh you know the role
that Nazis had played in there in their lives and um so Edson figured out a way to convince Bill
and do you want to guess what that way was what was it he dangled a lot of money in Ola's face
oh my mom speaks very clever uh so he basically said how much money your dad could expect to make
and then he walked away and let Ola do the rest and she did and she pushed and pushed and pushed
and so in November of 96 so that's about let's see that's eight months after he retired from
Errol he and Ola and the girls moved to London you're in college at the time so you stay in the
States um and immediately they get taken out to dinner by Edson and Susan right and uh the recollection
of someone who's at a dinner is that Ola complained the whole time that Bill had refused to splurge
on business class tickets um okay so you're at Albright college um Matt Goldsboro recounted for
me the tale of you guys uh your little heist of uh the band room or the music room uh which um
Matt thought was pretty badass to quote him um and you were also the guy who became known
for you know trying to make girl get girls to make out with each other three in the morning
and find some coca three in the morning and uh not in a bad way people said this with admiration um
do you remember the your samurai sword yes oh i love that sword um says someone told me the
anecdote of how you the like RA was trying to get you to turn the music down like in the middle of
the night and you wouldn't and a football player got involved like threatened you and you went into
a room and emerged in a black cape with a samurai sword and said they're trying to kill the funk
whoever wants to kill the funk is going to have to kill me first uh so um yes wonderful college
days yeah god only knows what else we both have uh lurking in our college exactly um
to intrude upon your college when i do some research on you yeah let's not that happened with me uh
during the Kavanaugh hearings we had written some stories about Brett Kavanaugh and in his
i read them all yeah and someone on twitter like came after me oh one of my college classmates came
after me saying and rich i remember i read that like you one day like puked in my bathroom and
he didn't clean it up and he didn't even ask for it i was like it's a very strange thing to i know
it's actually one with yeah it was it was strange uh okay as if that was going to derail your
comments on Brett Kavanaugh uh man very strange uh
so you guys are Deutsche Bank you guys are Deutsche Bank uh edson's a Deutsche Bank the team is a
Deutsche Bank one of bill's tasks assigned by edson uh was to try and pry power away from Germany
in the markets business um and which market well so edson was running the entire global
markets business and your dad was a co-head of proprietary trading specializing in credit derivatives
and credit yeah so but he his job and this is kind of a thankless job that was perfect for Bill
because he was so non-threatening and so good at like dealing with other human beings um
was that he needed to Deutsche Bank one of the many problems the bank had in these days
was that they had like in each german city so like not just like Berlin and Frankfurt but like
like Stuttgart and like Monheim and i'm just making shit up at this point but there's they each
are cities yeah you're not making them up i am actually german do you know that i do um so i
i'm a german citizen so that's why i call you enrique and not enrich uh you americanized your
name ellis island americanized uh uh anyway all of these places had their only little bond trading
outposts there's no coordinated uh strategy no mechanism and so bill was in charge of doing that
organizing the bond traders or of pulling all this power into london away from sovereignty
and the way bill described it at the time was the the situation that he was set out to fix was
quote the sort of thing that produced duplication of effort and dissipation of energies um which i
just love because it's you know yeah it's just it's bill yeah um he succeeded in that and things
are starting to click and he by uh you know in a year or two being at the bank um the customers
seem to be responding to all the changes they're making and he felt like this was finally the
moment where deutch a bank it was real and uh let's say they bought a mercedes which is interesting
because not long ago they had been very opposed to anything german very opposed to mercedes um i
thought that was interesting too um a conversation uh my dad eventually said oh carries it was years
ago they're not out to get us and then my mom was like yes no big deal it's my mom was more opposed
to mercedes and my dad should we pause remember i'm extremely hungry yeah okay