Do not accept. Hello? Hello? Hello?
Is this, uh, hello Val?
Hey, Kaiser Sose. How you doing? One of my favorite characters of all time.
Sorry?
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah, I'm okay. I'm okay. How are you? How you doing with the whole virus thing?
You know, that, well, Bermuda is not exactly, uh, the tough place to...
That's right.
So, I mean, no, I've, I've, I'm stationed here for a year. It's just kind of coincidence. I'm out of New York.
Oh, okay.
We do have an office here. And an office that was designed for two people is now seven.
Huh.
Because, uh, when, when it started hitting Europe, uh, I have two colleagues in the organization.
They, they, they're from Lugano in Switzerland.
Oh, I know Lugano. Sure. UBS.
Where, uh, Syria.
Just an hour, just an hour, just an hour above, uh, Milano's. I mean, no, they were in harm's way.
Oh, wow.
Um, they came over. And then two, uh, from Finsbury, uh, in London, where we have our office.
Oh, yeah.
Uh, also came here. So, it's, it's now, the club is, uh, you know, the office is, whatever.
It's, it's okay.
But, uh, I, I wanted to give you, uh, some context for this.
Sure.
Uh.
Hold on. I just, you caught me really quick. Can I just grab a piece of paper so I can take some notes?
Hold on one sec.
Yeah, hold on. Um, I got a pen. I got a pen and paper. Ah, okay. And paper, paper, paper.
Um, paper. Oh, I got it. Okay. Okay. I gotcha. I'm back. Paper and pen. All right.
So, I'll just put Kaiser Schoen there.
Um, uh, he, well, I work, uh, we are a, um, we're a merchant bank.
Sure. Okay.
Based in, based in Lugano, as it were. Uh, not Stooky. And, uh, I think, uh, we are the,
I think we are the oldest, technically we're the oldest, uh, funder funds in the world.
Sorry, the oldest what?
How about that? We, we have a family office, we have a merchant bank, and we have a fund
of funds.
A fund of funds. Wow. And the oldest. I see. Okay.
Well, it's, it's a, it's a lot, um, in essence, but, uh, you know, it's, it's, we, we've been
around forever.
Huh.
And, uh, so, but is it, but is it, is it family office not a, uh, sort of a downgraded hedge
fund usually?
Excuse me?
Uh, there's a family office. Isn't that kind of a down, downgraded hedge, hedge fund?
It kind of is, yeah.
It is, right. Okay.
It's like we, we manage proprietary accounts for five families. We have some other outside
capital, and we have our partner capital. Um, so, we've been around forever, and once
a part-time, I worked at Drexel.
Ah, Drexel. They have quite a history.
Yeah. Yeah. So, I was, uh, on the desk, as it were, and, um, in essence, you know, when
that broke out and blew up, uh, some of us from the high-yield world went to, uh, SG Warburg,
and then that small group that I was in, we all went off to Not Skooky, where we've been
ever since. And there was another group that went to DLJ, Donaldson, Lufkin, Genret, which
is since, uh, in the past. Anyways.
Okay. I don't know.
If you roll it, if you roll it forward into the early 2000s.
Okay.
Actually, not even that, the late 90s. Let's call it the late 90s.
Um, in the late 90s, uh, a guy named Michael Phillip.
Michael Phillip?
Michael Phillip.
Phillip, got it.
Michael Phillip was hired by Deutsche Bank.
Okay.
To build a North American business.
Michael Phillip was the guy that, he was the guy that hired Frank Quattro, that banking group
from, um, from, uh, Morgan Stanley.
They came over and made quite a splash.
But, among other things, uh, they geared up on the fixed income side.
And most of the fixed income new hires they made were the former Drexel guys, who were
the former DLJ guys, who came to Beijing and some of them, uh, in New York at the 60th wall, which is where D.P.
America's is.
Sure.
That's where my father was.
That's where J.P.
Morgan was.
Yeah.
That's where my father was.
That's where J.P.
Morgan, yep, J.P.
Morgan was there.
Yeah.
And the balance of them went to Finsbury, a petty corner from us, which was in London.
There was a large group of credit default swap traders, CLO traders, credit loan traders, etc.
And Finsbury, what's in Finsbury, though, exactly?
It's, that's where your, that's where the other...
Yeah, no, Finsbury's just, uh, Finsbury's the city of London.
I mean, Finsbury's the street.
Okay, that's where Deutsche Bank is.
A lot of, a lot of the big banks are there.
Oh, yeah, sorry.
Yeah, that's where Deutsche had.
Sorry.
Yeah, I, I think Deutsche is in, Deutsche is currently in, uh, Cannery, Wharf, I believe.
But, you know, Finsbury Lane, the garden pod district.
I gotcha, yeah.
Sorry, I lived there for, I lived there for, I lived there for 10 years and I've already forgotten.
Okay, Finsbury Lane.
Yeah, Warburg's.
Yeah, Warburg's is down there, House of Schroeder, etc.
Oh, man.
House of Schroeder, owned by the, uh...
I grew up in Paddington.
Oh, you did?
Okay.
I lived in Kentish Town.
I grew up in Paddington.
Okay.
I, I grew up in Paddington, Queens Park Rangers, all the way.
Oh, cool.
Imperial College.
So, I mean, I, I, so that's, that's kind of my backwards.
Now, if you run it forward, um, we, we tether through our fund of funds.
We have LP interests, they're not big.
Okay.
But, you know, we have LP interests in some big credit side funds, big hedge funds.
Uh, we have access to balance sheet from the six Uber high net worth families that we manage proprietary capital for.
Okay.
So, I mean, we're, we're not, we're not the guys, but we, we can make references like that.
Sure.
And, um, so, fast forward some more, I'm in New York with Nas Stuckey.
I go back and forth to London quite a bit.
This was in like the early 2010s.
Okay.
So, I knew Fitchin very well.
Oh, you did?
You know, Fitchin is.
Sure, Jorgen.
Yeah, I knew him.
Huh.
Yeah, Jorgen and Fitchin.
Now, Fitchin was a guy that we knew really well.
I mean, it was pints after work kind of thing.
And, you know, it, it, it was, uh, in 2013, late in 2013, where he said, you know, we got
a thing, you know, we got, you know, we got something that, yeah.
Okay.
Uh, Fitchin did, Fitchin did.
Yeah.
Okay, wow.
And he called, he called my colleague, who is like one of his closer friends, uh, in
each other's weddings, that kind of thing.
Okay.
Yeah, just kind of quiet.
Yeah, hey, can we come over?
You know, let's, we got to talk about something.
Right.
And they sat down, and it was, you know, Fitchin, his associate, uh, your dad was there.
He was there.
And one other guy.
Yeah.
And one other guy from DB American.
Wow.
Who was, who, who else was there from DB American?
Fitchin's associate, and one guy who was a syndicate bond trader.
A syndicate bond trader.
Do you remember his name?
Out of London, yeah.
Syndicate bond trader.
Carl, I'm not placing, Carl, I'm not placing it.
It's Carl, not there anymore.
Carl.
Um, you know, just like a 27-year-old guy who, you know, was just fresh out of NPA somewhere.
Interesting.
He was, he was from, they were all from, they were all from London, more or less.
Mm-hmm.
And we were just kind of going through this and saying they wanted to do a CLO, but there
was one issue with indemnity.
And, you know, and they may have signed an NDA saying, okay, so I, by the way, I haven't
spoken.
You've got to help me out.
Can you help me out a little bit here?
So I know, so it's a collateralized loan obligation.
What, how, what is that any different from a CDS or a collateralized debt obligation?
Uh, and then why, and why would you, uh, and why would you buy one?
You wouldn't buy one.
You would buy a tranche.
Right.
You would buy a tranche that had literally hundreds, a hundred or hundreds of loans in
them.
So I thought you, the difference is.
I thought you said you were buying one.
Okay, sorry.
No, the, well, they're trying to do a tranche.
A tranche.
A tranche could mean a hundred different loans packaged into something.
And then it's like a wrapper.
Sure.
I know.
So a CDO would be a wrapper of debentures.
Yep.
A CLO would be a wrapper of loans.
And, but isn't it ultimately the same?
And like, what am I missing?
Is it a percentage rate?
Is it a basis point issue?
What?
They're the same.
They're, they're, they're, they're literally the same thing.
That's what I thought.
Yeah.
Okay.
A pool of debentures.
Yeah.
One is a pool of debentures or bonds.
Pool of bonds.
And the other is a pool, the other is a pool or a syndicate of loans, just loans.
Like debentures would have a securities purchase agreement.
Okay.
It could have multiple different investors.
It'd be 144A.
And they're securitized?
It could be a reg statement.
And those are securitized, bundled, and sold.
I see.
You know, like the, like the movie, you know.
You know, it's, you know, you aggregate all the whale shit and it's supposed to be diversified
and sold to people.
So we've seen this before.
And they, they said they wanted to do a CLO, but there was one instrument.
And they said instrument.
There was one instrument that was done by DBTCA.
And, you know, we're, you know, we're sitting, you know, I'm just saying, well, what the fuck
is DBTCA?
Right.
What does this mean to us?
And like, well, well, that's the high net worth division.
I'm like, we're still like, still not following this, guys.
And they basically said, you know, eyes only.
This, this is what happened.
Okay.
This is what happened.
Um, and this is in the fall of 2013.
This was before a certain guy's running for president.
This is, and in fact, if like, if you had said that meeting, this guy's going to someday
run for president and this could really be all this, you know, you'd be looked at like
you had a, a monkey standing on your shoulder.
I know.
It would have been that kind of weirdness.
Now here it was just like, you know, we're getting the sense, uh, from Juergen that, uh,
you know, they got some, they got a turd that they need to get rid of and they're trying
to figure out how to get rid of them.
And trying to sell it to you.
Okay.
And, and no, they're not trying to sell it.
They're just trying to figure out how to structure this.
Oh, so you're there to structure?
So your role there is to structure.
Okay.
To be clear, to be clear, these guys, this, these were the good guys.
And there is such a thing as the good guys at Deutsche and the bad guys.
Yeah.
The good guys were DB Americas.
Okay.
If your business card's a DB Americas, you were part of the broker dealer, part of the prime
broker.
Yeah.
Now, let, let me go through this very slowly because it is complicated, but it's also simple.
Okay.
So we get past the, well, what the fuck is a DBTCA?
So we look at it and, and they're telling us, well, here's what happened.
The private bank side of Deutsche or the high net worth group is DBTCA.
It is structured as a trust.
Right.
Yeah.
It's a pooled trust, which, which is not unusual.
We have a pooled trust.
And we're like, oh, okay.
Yeah.
So we have a pooled trust.
No problem.
And the trust made a loan.
Right.
And that's where our heads kind of started spinning.
We're like, what do you mean the trust made a loan?
And they're like, well, let us finish, let us finish.
Yeah.
And they said, once upon a time, we were approached by Deutsche Bank's high net worth group.
And it would be sufficient to say that Deutsche Bank's high net worth group is just strictly a loose confederation of independent contractors.
Right.
There's no corporate structure whatsoever.
I mean, if you produce, you get paid.
If you don't, you can sit there and stare at the wall until you get the memo and leave.
Right.
That's why I had no CRO for something.
And it's one of those places where you can literally be an entrepreneur and do whatever the fuck you want.
And if you produce and get paid, it's fine.
Yeah.
Okay.
So we were approached by a high producer on the HNW side.
And she, what she wanted to do was get a loan for one of her clients so you could make some acquisitions in commercial real estate and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And, you know, we're all sitting there, like, nodding along, like, this is Donald Trump, isn't it?
Like, well, yeah, yeah, it is.
It's just a Trump organization.
And we're not interrupting them.
And they're just like, and to be clear, we said no.
At TV Americas, we basically didn't just say no.
We said no, capital N, capital O, exclamation mark, exclamation mark, fuck no, fuck no, no, no.
Right.
So in other words, no.
Why was it so bad?
What was it that you refused?
Well, because he had a long history of default.
He was the punchline to every joke in town.
Oh, yeah, well, of course.
But if it's a tranche, what's the exposure?
But, like, we're not done yet.
We're not nearly done yet.
So we're saying, okay, so you didn't do the loan, so why are we here?
And they're like, well, the trust did the loan.
And I said, and I actually spoke up.
I said, you know, you're going to be, what?
It's like, that is the craziest thing I have ever heard.
So do you have, like, any details?
He's like, well, I have the long dots right here.
And I said, so where's the consent agreement?
And he said, there isn't one.
And all four of us on our side of the table just said, what?
What a consent.
Let me describe what I'm talking about here.
Like, let's do, this is very, very important.
I've read every word of what Scott's written.
I've read the book.
This is a distinction that really matters.
It really, really matters.
Okay, let's, it's an easy story for you to remember, okay?
Okay, well, I'm writing it down to you.
This is a hypothetical.
Okay.
This is a hypothetical, okay?
Got it.
Now, let's suppose that once upon a time you grew up in a certain neighborhood and you have four buddies.
It's like the five amigos.
You plus four other guys, okay?
Okay.
And you did good deeds for Mr. and Mrs. Jones.
Mr. and Mrs. Jones, in this hypothetical, they're some elderly couple.
And without asking, you would carry their groceries in.
Without asking, you'd shovel their driveway.
Without asking, you'd mow their lawn.
Without asking, you'd weed their flower bed.
Sounds like punishment.
No, because you were the good kids.
You were the good kids, right?
Yeah.
And then suppose 20 years later, you get a call straight out of nowhere saying, Mr. Jones and Mrs. Jones have both passed away.
And guess what?
They left their estate to you and your four buddies.
Hmm.
Okay.
I'm the trustee.
I work at the investment manager.
I work at this wealth management division of a bank.
And it's got $20 million in it.
So congratulations.
All five of you are now worth $4 million each.
I'm the trustee, et cetera.
So the kind of phone call you'd like to get.
Right.
Yeah, of course.
Let's also suppose that four years later, straight out of nowhere, you learn that one of your childhood best friends had borrowed a million dollars from the trust.
And it used that million dollars to speculatively put down a deposit on a ski resort in Vail, Colorado.
Right.
Some fancy resort.
Oh, I see.
And he also got equity in the project.
And he also got concessions.
And the good news is that loan got paid back.
Okay.
Okay?
Yeah.
And then the next thing you hear is that your buddy made five or six million bucks on top of that.
Right.
So he borrowed a million bucks from the trust.
Yep.
And he turned it into six or seven million dollars for himself.
And the trust got paid back a million dollars.
So no big deal.
Right.
What's the big deal here?
You're asking me?
Well, that he took the money without consent.
He took the money without consent.
There was no consent agreement.
That's right.
He just did it on his own.
And even worse, it was structured as heads he wins, tails he doesn't lose, or tails you all five who you lose.
Oh, really?
Okay.
So if this one million dollar loan had gone kaputski, at some point the trustee would have had to call the other four of you back and say,
I got some bad news for you, and I'm sorry about this, and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
You know, you're all down money.
You're all down 200 grand.
Right.
So in other words, even worse than the fact that they made the loan at all, even worse than the fact that they made the loan without your consent,
they placed you at a material risk.
Right.
You're accountable now.
Yeah.
So just consider that to be the story as to why you don't make loans from a trust.
Okay.
If one of our clients called us up and said, well, there's this acquisition I'd like to make, and I'd like to borrow $200 million, we'd say, all right, here, let's go get a meeting with the Bank of America or the Wells Fargo or the this.
I'd say, we're not a bank.
We're a private bank.
There's a difference, right?
Right, right, right.
There's a big difference.
You know, we don't loan money out to people that cross-contaminate the other clients.
That's not something anyone should ever do.
Oh, so cross-contaminate the loans, okay.
And here in this meeting, in London, we're being told by DB Americas, four guys at DB Americas, not four bozos, but four senior guys, this is what happened, okay?
Okay.
There is no consent agreement.
The other people in the trust, there are 8,000 clients in the DBTCA trust, 8,000 high-net-worth clients that have anywhere from $10 or $20 million, whatever the minimum is, up to hundreds of millions of dollars.
Okay.
There is this loan to this clownish developer in New York who has a history of bankruptcies for hundreds of millions of dollars.
Oh, and they didn't disclose it to anyone.
They didn't disclose it to anyone.
So who, man, who drew up these loans?
This guy to be Rosemary?
So, so, so basically we're looking at this guy.
But you're telling me my father's here, right?
So that's a big thing.
Well, he, he, but he's just listening, okay?
It's mostly, it's mostly, it's mostly the other guys talking.
Okay.
Okay?
It's mostly the other guys talking.
So, and basically I'm trying to get to the bottom of it with Juergen.
Okay.
I'm asking the questions.
He's given the answers and his trader is piking in.
Those are the only two, these are the only three people who are talking.
I was talking to Juergen.
And the bond trader?
My partner was asking some other question.
And the bond trader was adding a lot of clarifiers.
So, so basically I just called time out and I said, I slow it down and I say, how in the
world did DBTCA loan hundreds of millions of dollars without taking money out of other
client accounts?
That doesn't make any sense.
Right.
Said another way, how did this happen?
And they said, that's why we asked for this meeting.
Well, there is some good news and there's some bad news.
The good news is bad news.
The good news is these loans have been indemnified.
In fact, within two weeks or within two weeks of these loans happening, uh, hundreds of millions
of dollars were remitted from, uh, two foreign banks.
Remitted?
You just said it like that.
Two foreign.
Two foreign banks.
Okay.
Well, that's gotta be VTB.
Two foreign banks.
Two, two foreign banks wired hundreds of millions of dollars into DBTCA.
Okay.
And I said, well, that doesn't make sense.
You mean clients of two banks, two foreign banks, right?
Right.
Yeah.
Clients of two foreign banks.
Okay.
So it's not really, okay, which banks?
And they said the two Russian banks.
I'm like, oh, okay.
So it would be clients of VB and clients of the other one.
Right.
That's fair.
And they said, a client, and they said, a client of VB and a client of the other one.
Oh.
And I said, okay.
One, a client?
A single client.
Okay.
Single client.
And I said, well, okay.
All right.
Let's slow this down.
Let's just talk about VB.
Now, VB, when you say two foreign banks wired in hundreds of millions of dollars, you mean
a client of VB wired in hundreds, and a client of the other bank wired in hundreds.
So what did the client of VB do?
And they said, well, the client of VB signed basically an indemnity agreement so that they
could segregate this money within the trust away from the other principals and investors
in the trust.
Okay.
Can I just ask one question?
Oh, kind of like a...
Sorry.
Can I interrupt you for a second?
Yeah.
I just need to verify an indemnity agreement is just an under...
Is this someone that backs up the loan, right?
Because I'm thinking a double indemnity.
So, okay.
It's just a backup.
Okay.
So basically, I said you have an indemnity agreement for the trust.
The trust.
Okay.
So that they can say with a straight face that they didn't cross-contaminate any client
funds.
Okay.
Do you have one of those?
And they showed it to me.
It was ribald.
Ribald, yeah.
Yeah.
Okay.
Jeez.
Yeah.
And I didn't look at the other one.
I said, okay, we get the memo here.
All right.
And they said, so, do you think that we will be able to say that this loan was made by DBTCA
and that it has two indemnity agreements, and we can even say the banks that the indemnity
agreements came from, but do you think we can get away with doing a CLO where we describe
this loan without saying who the indemnitors are and who the indemnity is?
In other words, can we get away with just saying this is one of the loans that goes into
the pool, and the indemnity agreement is basically these two banks fortified by a client, and
it is client money, cash money, and it is segregated from the trust, and it is to a U.S. corporation.
Oh, a U.S. corporation.
That's it.
Oh, okay, interesting.
Like, not even say that it's Trump, and I said, not in a million years.
Look at the count, in 2008, like, the one thing the world learned to do after 2008 is
if you are looking at a CLO or a CDO, you are going to crawl all the way up the ass, and
you're going to look at every single loan, you're going to ask for every single indemnity
agreement, you're going to ask for every single segregated pool or SPV or consent agreement
or whatever it is, your clients are going to ask you for everything, everything, everything.
There's no way this is going to be stopped.
No way at all.
You're basically being asked to launder money, right?
That's kind of a classic money laundering.
So let's put this through a corporation.
I wouldn't go that far.
I mean, it could have been just a loan, and then the loan either gets defaulted on or gets
paid back.
Now, if there was some kind of a scheme where, you know, these two Russian bank clients, one
of them who was Bribovilev, if there had been some pre-arrangement where Trump Org would
borrow the money and then knowingly default, and then the lender would knowingly just have
a pre-arrangement to write it on.
Right.
And then it's just a loan, which isn't really income, that got defaulted on.
That's it, right.
Now, the way money laundering works is, you know, the person that got the loan that defaulted
on the loan would pick some of it back.
Now, I don't want to get way ahead of myself here and say, I know what I don't know.
I mean, I don't know any of that.
My point is, once upon a time, DB Americas got stuck.
Once upon a time, DBTCA, by way of this Rosemary Clown.
But, I mean, they really stuck it to them and said, look, this is going to rot on the
books, and it will default, and it will cause all kinds of embarrassment, so why don't you
guys take it on the syndicate desk?
The syndicate desk?
No.
Okay.
Why don't you guys on the syndicate desk try to put it in a structured product and sell it?
Right.
And they said, well, we'll look into this.
I mean, look, the four guys in the room that they had no intention of trying to sell us
something.
They did not.
Okay.
What they wanted to do was tell us the whole scenario and then hear our reaction.
And they all took very copious notes.
They all took copious notes, and they listened to every word of our responses.
They had listened to our questions.
They answered our questions.
They asked us questions.
We answered the questions.
I mean, this meeting went on for about two hours.
Lots and lots and lots of notes.
The trader had his laptop open.
He was typing in his notes the whole time.
Yeah.
And I think what they were trying to do was document, okay, we did talk to an institutional investor.
We talked to Knott Stuky in London.
And basically, here was the reaction.
Here's the notes to the file.
Okay.
And the reaction that these guys had, these guys have been around since the 80s.
These guys are here for all the crashes and crushes.
They've seen it all.
And this was their reaction.
Right.
So, once again, the answer is no.
This is crazy.
We can't just put this in a CLO or a CDO.
And, like, basically, the meeting ended with those guys just saying, hey, thanks for taking a meeting.
We really appreciate this.
It's important that everyone at DB is on the same page.
It's important that everyone understands this.
Huh.
Okay.
Yeah.
Because once upon a time, and, like, basically, it sounded to me like they were trying to load up the deck to really stick it to this Rosemary woman at DB2CA and get her fired.
Interesting.
Because they did a loan.
To me, is it possible it was for compliance?
Like, they wanted your reaction so they could say we spoke to you guys and they said no as well to the compliance team.
You know, as a presentation.
I don't think so.
I think the whole point of the meeting was to make the point, this is crazy.
Nobody gets out of this alive.
Nobody gets out of this alive now.
And, literally, these loans sit on the books until or if they default or get paid back.
And they're probably going to default.
And when they default, there's no way, there's no way that we can avoid disclosure.
Okay.
There's no way that we can avoid disclosure.
And then that blows up the whole DB2CA.
Look, it amazes me.
It amazes me that articles have been written and now a book has been written.
And nobody has focused on the fact, the fact, that DB2CA was the one that broke the loan.
Right.
That is crazy.
Hey, you're speaking to the, preaching to the choir here.
Thank you.
Crazy.
Now, why is it crazy?
Well, ask anyone with a high net worth account at DB2CA if they have a copy of a consent agreement.
Okay.
It's a real question.
Through all the connections you may have to people at DB, blah, blah, blah, high net worth people,
this is a good thing.
High net worth clients of DB2CA, step forward.
Do any of you have a, what's called a consent agreement?
Just a copy of a standard consent.
Because once upon a time, DB2CA, by their own admission, loaned hundreds of millions of dollars out of a trust.
Now, the trust had $20 billion.
Right.
But still, that's not the point.
We're right back to square one.
Okay, what's the big deal about one of your childhood buddies taking a $1 million loan out from a $20 million trust?
Oh, and he paid it back.
Right.
What's the big deal?
I'll tell you what the big deal is.
You cross-contaminated me.
You cross-contaminated your other two buddies, your other three buddies from childhood.
In this instance, you're cross-contaminating each and every one of the other clients within their high net worth brokerage group.
And if that was disclosed, it was disclosed.
It amazes me.
They would pull their funds, right?
Yes.
It amazes me that no one has focused on that.
Now, if that is not true, if that is not true, that they are cross-contaminated, then there has to be an indemnity agreement.
There has to be an indemnity agreement.
And guess what?
All of the investors in the trust are entitled to see that indemnity agreement to confirm that they are not cross-contaminated.
Every single one in the trust?
Every single one of them.
Interesting.
Ask every single one of them, do you have an indemnity agreement that basically documents that you are not exposed to any material adverse change because DVTCA loaned hundreds of millions of dollars to Donald Trump?
Wow.
Do you have one of those?
Interesting.
If you don't have one of those, that's another red flag.
Okay?
Yeah.
That basically says, and then for them to say, well, there is an indemnity agreement, but we can't really talk about that.
Oh, really?
Okay.
Huh.
But that's...
Which is, sounds to me like, it sounds to me like where we're at now is maybe they have confessed to the indemnity agreements.
Maybe they haven't.
Mm-hmm.
But it doesn't sound to me like anyone is really making demands.
Huh.
If there is a default, and if it is, quote unquote, no big deal, it's not going to expose any of the other investors in the trust or the other high net worth contributors to the trust.
If that is true, who's stopping that out?
Who's what?
Who's stopping it out?
Who is indemnifying it?
Now, Scott came very close.
Yeah, they're good.
Look at the hundreds of millions of dollars that got wired in from Russian banks.
Well, you know, that's...
Okay, well...
Just so I...
That all came from me.
I gave Scott all that data.
Okay, okay, well...
I know.
It's all...
It's all Gazprom, Sparebank, and VTV.
And there's...
I have the breach report that says it's very clear.
Of course you do.
And that's an excellent piece of information that confirms...
Yeah.
Sure, that confirms a lot of this.
But my point...
My point to you is it's not the bank.
Uh-huh.
It's not the bank.
It's the clients of the bank.
Banks don't just wire money to some fucking trust or some fucking bank in the private banking group.
Right, that's true.
I mean, Gazprom Bank, last I checked, is not a high net worth client of anyone's.
No, I know.
We're not looking to buy...
I mean...
Well, neither is Johnson & Johnson.
Johnson & Johnson has one billion parked there.
You know, it's shady.
I mean, I'm going through my father's emails.
Why does Johnson & Johnson have a billion dollars parked in DVTCA?
Exactly.
Right.
Okay, now, the answer to that question is they wouldn't.
The answer to that question in that room in 2013, in the fall of 2013, this is like October, November of 2013,
in that room, we all basically nodded in agreement at the end.
Yep, that's what it is.
Yep.
That's what it is.
Basically, the capital that got put into DPTCA by Gazprom and by BP is ostensibly nothing but just cash sitting there to indemnify a loan that they don't want to disclose anymore.
Yep.
And it's not the banks.
It is...
There's...
Basically, that's like you loaning your brother-in-law, if you have one, $100,000 to buy a house.
Like, your brother-in-law saw a nice house and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
My father's done that.
He wants $100,000.
My father did that.
Okay.
So, you wire money to your brother-in-law.
Yep.
$100,000.
And he sees a wire come in from Bank of America.
Did Bank of America loan him $100,000?
Right.
No, of course not.
No.
You did.
Right.
That's the way banks work, right?
Of course.
Banks have clients.
Right.
Banks don't...
Banks aren't high-net-worth clients.
Banks aren't private banking clients looking to do a non-revocable trust for their fucking grandkids.
So...
What are you kidding me?
So, why would they put on the balance sheet?
Why would they put Gazprom and not the actual client?
It's a mistake.
Do you think so?
Do you think it was a purposeful mistake?
I think it's a mistake.
By design?
The only reason why anyone knows about that is the breach reports.
Is the breach reports?
Yeah.
The breach reports.
The breach reports basically spread the virus, as it were.
Yeah.
Okay?
Now, but really focus here.
Yeah.
As far as DB Americas was concerned,
they couldn't disclose to anyone who the indemnidor was without the consent of Rosemary Revol...
Whatever her name was.
Revolving.
Why did they need her consent?
Client confidentiality.
Really?
Okay.
You can't just run out in the street and say, it's this guy's...
But they showed us one of them.
They showed us one of the indemnity agreements,
and it was not VV Bank.
It was their client.
It was Rob Althamon.
And there was another one.
I didn't see...
I didn't see the signature on the other one.
Did anyone mention Victor Vechteberg?
I recall the name, but that's it.
That's it.
Okay.
Interesting.
Wow.
That's all I know.
That's a lot.
That's all I know, but that's a lot, okay?
It's huge.
Yeah.
That's great.
Wow.
What do you think about going on the record ever?
I will.
You will?
That'd be great, man.
I will.
That'd be great.
I mean, we need you.
And this is important.
It won't be sometime tomorrow morning.
Okay?
I got you, yeah.
I will be thoughtful to get back to you again.
Okay.
I've heard from Rocco via this Twitter thing,
and I've heard from Sandy.
But I would be glad to add the clarifiers,
but in two hours, I think I learned a lot.
Yeah.
And I think I'm just describing to you what it is.
What did you think of my father?
I mean, he was there, yeah?
What was he doing there?
I think, to be clear, I didn't know him.
Yeah.
He was just, as far as I could see, just quiet.
He was the best guy.
Yeah.
He was quiet.
And polite.
I mean, I can't make more of this than what I told you.
I mean, that's what I remember.
I knew the other guy.
I knew Juergen.
You knew Juergen.
Okay.
I'm just curious as to just, you know, it's good to hear.
Anyone that's met my father, it's always good to hear a story or something.
Yeah.
I think the one thing that I would add with emphasis is like,
at DB, you had good guys and you had bad guys.
Yeah.
These were the good guys.
We met with the good guys.
Yeah.
The good guys wanted to do something that was, they wanted to do the right thing.
They did.
Yeah.
That's my father.
It sounds like him.
All right.
And he was a good guy.
And in essence, it was just, it was just such a hot mess.
I mean, no one there, no one there could believe it, that they, they took, they wouldn't take
no for an answer and they, they did it within the trust.
That was really reckless.
Wow.
And so it's very crazy.
So what do you think if I was going to get a hold of these loans, let's say I had like
a magic key that could open up any computer in the world, where computer would I go for?
Within DPTCA, there is a general counsel's office.
Okay.
Mark Stein?
Mark Stein.
General counsel, general counsel.
Okay.
Got it.
General counsel's office.
Interesting.
That's where they would keep the loan.
I wouldn't be, I wouldn't, I wouldn't be surprised if the original box are in his office.
Okay.
They would be computerized there as well.
Yeah.
They'd be scanned there.
That's fascinating.
Okay.
Did you, did you have any interactions with, with like a Michele Faisola by any chance?
He's the head of wealth and asset management.
I would think that he would be there because he was, he was the head of wealth asset management.
Nope.
He wasn't there.
He was not there.
Okay.
That's interesting.
This was strictly, this was strictly, this was strictly DB Americas trying to figure it out with us and trying to, trying to basically go back with something.
And it was all because of this Trump, just because of fucking Trump, huh?
And so his loan was so severe, it was such a big, massive breach that it would take down the rest of this Trump and if it defaulted.
And what was, I mean, it's interesting that yesterday the news comes out about the loan.
And, uh, that couldn't be the same loan, did it?
Well, this is some years later, but I have a hard time believing those loans were ever paid back.
You don't think so?
It's not that way.
Okay.
Um...
Do you know how much we're talking about?
Look, I mean, we, we, we don't, we don't know what we don't know.
Right.
I mean, look, the guy is always broke.
Yeah.
He's always broke.
He's always asking for money.
And he's an opportunist.
So, of course he's out there asking for money and concessions.
I mean, even if he wasn't dead broke, and he probably is.
He'd do it anyway.
He'd still be trying to rock and, he'd still be trying to rock and roll and get the better of somebody and slip away.
And, which is why nobody in their right mind would lend money to him.
That's right.
Except for...
That is exactly why nobody will do business with him, except for apparently this woman at TV, who's no longer there, I understand.
Nah, she's gone.
Where's my problem?
Well, actually, technically she is.
They have her employed, because the, uh, we just spoke to one of their lawyers and said that they, she is employed still.
Um, on some level.
She is.
I think that they have her there so she can't talk, is my guess.
Um, but Tom Bowers...
That makes sense, yeah.
Tom Bowers was, uh, her boss.
And you heard about him, right?
Uh-huh.
He killed himself just recently.
And, uh, Tom Bowers supposedly has the, uh, these documents as well.
I gotta fight...
In Malibu, yeah.
Yeah, in Malibu.
Um, and David Enrich, who I do not like at all, he's much, very much opportunist, and I did not see it coming, and I couldn't believe how, uh, I couldn't believe...
I mean, it was, it's unbelievable what he wrote, but the book, he was much kinder than the article to me.
And he was good to my father, so that was, that was, that was the best part of it, but...
Yeah.
Um, Tom Bowers gave David, uh, some loan, uh, loan agreements, loan documents.
And the, the, the, the consensus amongst, uh, the Deutsche Bank, I can't remember which lawyer it was, uh, not the head lawyer, it was the, it was some sort of intern type lawyer who said that these were all fraudulent documents.
That's his stance, and that's where he's been, the, the word around...
Oh.
Yeah, he said fraudulent documents.
Well, I don't know what that, I don't know what that means, there's all kinds of ways, there's all kinds of things that could be fraud.
Well, there's, basically, there's, so, God, what's his name?
Uh, some, uh, talk show, a talking head guy, uh, Chris O'Donnell, or something, Lawrence O'Donnell, uh, went on to the news and said,
I have these loan documents, um, that shows that, in fact, uh, Trump's loans were, Deutsche Bank loans were, in fact, underwritten by, uh, Russian banks.
Uh, and, uh, the next day, he goes on the air.
That's not true, that's not true.
No, the banks...
Were identified, sorry.
D-B-T-C-A, D-B-T-C-A wrote the loans, there's no doubt about that.
But, I'm sorry, I...
Who identified the loans?
I've been...
Yeah.
This is, this is very different.
You know, I had the wrong language.
The identity agreement?
Yeah.
Yeah, sorry, I had the wrong language.
I mean, identified the loans, identified the loans, were, uh, Russian oligarchs.
He said, he said the word oligarchs on air, and Deutsche Bank called him and said that you cannot, you have to retract this right away, um, the loan documents...
Oh, what he said was true.
What he said was true.
I, I, I, I'm one of maybe a few...
I'm one of not very many people in the world who have seen one of those.
I know, it's amazing.
It's amazing.
Um...
It's, it is true.
It is true.
They are lying.
I know they're lying.
Those fuckers, man.
I knew it.
Um, yeah, they're saying everything's fraudulent, and they made him take that, retract,
his statements.
The lawyer said, if you don't retract that statement, we're coming after you and the network.
So he retracted it the next day.
He should have invited it.
I know, right?
Exactly.
That's what I said.
That's the problem.
That's one of the problems, is, like, you let it rip, and they threaten to sue you.
Yeah.
Let them.
Discovery's a...
Yeah.
Discovery's a bitch, right?
Discovery's a bitch.
And this national spotlight's even more unforgiving.
Yep.
Exactly.
I don't know why they would blink, but, uh, I, look, I don't know if he saw something
or if he was just being told something secondhand, but I saw it in 2013.
Yep.
I remember, I remember every single detail about that meeting.
Every single one.
Because it was so terrible.
Because, and the reason why that is, is it was just so bizarre.
It was really...
It was so bizarre.
It was something straight out of a movie, almost.
It was like, it was weird.
It was wildly inappropriate.
And, like, to be clear, the D.B. America's guys were not trying to sell us something.
They were trying to, like, they were trying to get this figured out with us.
And then to go back to the wealth people and tell them why they were so crazy.
But so they knew, I mean, my dad would have known right away, and this is ridiculous.
He would have known, he did know right away.
They all knew right away.
So why would the purpose of calling in a third party would be to have on the record
that there was a third party that also objects to this, right?
They were asked to pitch this, and they came to us and said, hey, we're pitching this.
Like, we're not, yeah, we're going through the motions here.
Who do you think asked?
Huh?
Who do you think asked to pitch it to you?
I mean, who do you think asked my father's group?
We knew all the people at D.B. London very, very well.
Okay.
Let's just put it that way.
I mean, basically, they trusted us to sit down and figure this out with them so that
they could go back with a file and say, you wanted us to pitch this to a serious group?
We did.
Okay.
This is a group that could have referred us to these five family offices and these other hedge funds.
When you say you wanted us, when you're quoting them, you said, hey, you wanted us to pitch
it and we did, who are they talking to?
Who's the you?
Is that Anshu?
Is that...
Not Stooky.
No, we're not Stooky.
No, no, I'm sorry.
I'm not explaining myself.
Like, who do you think was the party at Deutsche Bank that asked my father and the group
that you spoke to to bring this to you?
Juergen did that on his own.
He did on his own.
Okay.
He was getting pressure from DBTCA's managing director in charge of blah, blah, blah.
They were all just...
They were basically a firing squad in a circle over at DBTCA.
My father went to DBTCA to clean it up in September, October, 2013.
That was his whole...
He was retiring.
That would have been right after the meeting.
Right after?
No, no.
He was still...
October...
Because he retired technically September, but he went right to work at DBTCA immediately.
So he was...
I see the emails from November and October, and he's asking...
He's trying to clean everything up, and no one's listening to him.
So if you say there's a managing director giving Juergen pressure...
When did he...
When did he start at DBTCA again?
When?
Around September.
End of September of 2013.
Or middle September.
This meeting...
This meeting would have been either right before...
Yeah.
He went over, or right after.
Okay.
It sounds like after.
And the guy...
No.
And the guy at DBTCA, who had pressured this meeting to happen...
Yeah.
It was not your dad.
It was definitely not.
Okay.
It was another higher-up guy who was just...
Again, another...
Oh, the French guy.
Okay.
The French guy, yeah.
Yes.
Another can't-take-no-for-an-answer guy.
You know, Jean-Philippe or something like that.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
And just...
They wouldn't let it go.
And they finally figured, you know, this group that we met with, the 4DB Americas guy,
said, look, we just need to acquit ourselves of this.
Right.
So we're gonna...
Let's go through this with you once.
Let's fill a file up.
Ask all your questions.
And, like, at the end of the meeting, it was just like, well, that was crazy.
Let's go get pints next Wednesday.
Right.
I mean, that was the thing.
We'd go over to the old...
Go over to the...
Go over to the banger around the corner and have a few pints.
And that was it.
The banger, yeah.
That's great.
Man, okay.
This is great.
Thank you, man.
This is fantastic.
This is huge.
So we gotta do something about this.
I mean, I know, of course, you can't go on the record tomorrow.
I don't know who to...
I know...
I'm gonna find out.
I'm a month or two...
I'm a month or two away from...
Yeah?
I'm a month or two away from, like, basically...
I'm gonna retire at the end of the year.
Okay.
I mean, I can't embarrass the firm while I'm there.
Sure.
And just...
You know, I'm trying to get an avenue to travel by so I can talk.
I understand.
But...
But I gotta figure that out.
But, like, Sandy has been guilting me.
Val, you gotta get Trump out of their office now, now.
I'm like, come on, Sandy.
Give me a break.
He's like, come on.
There are millions of lives at stake.
I'm like, what?
He's like, well, with the virus.
He's gonna fuck it all up.
And people are gonna die.
And then I started thinking about that.
I was like, fuck, maybe she's right.
You know?
So I'm trying to figure out the best way to do this.
I mean, if we can...
And I'm just worried that now, because this virus is taking over the media,
no one's gonna even care about Trump's loans.
That's what I'm worried about.
So maybe it's a timing issue as well.
Well, look.
Look.
Karma has a way of working, eventually.
Eventually?
I hope so.
I mean, come on.
Trump's president.
How's karma work?
Here's...
Here...
I know.
Well, karma took its time this time.
But here's my point.
Yeah.
I think he's...
I think he's dead broke.
Yeah.
Dead broke.
He's ass up.
And now he's gotta go back to them.
Yeah.
Again.
I agree.
And guess what?
It is impossible for them to do business with him now.
Impossible.
Yeah.
I mean, it was close to impossible in 2013, long before this whole shit show.
Well, he's just gonna go to Russian banks.
I bet you anything.
He's gonna go right back to those guys.
You know what?
But you know what?
It's...
All I'm saying is that is, like...
Back in the day, I mean, he had a lot of eyes on him.
He had a lot of people chasing him in the media.
Yeah.
Back in the day, he had a lot of attention.
Now he's under the world's biggest microscope.
Yeah.
And, look, I've met the guy just once.
That was in 1990.
Okay.
He's not a smart guy.
I know.
He's an idiot.
Of course.
He's a moron.
And his kids are as dumb as the day is long.
Oh, my God.
And just...
Look, at some point, at some point, the jig is up.
Yeah.
Like, people have to say, I just can't help you.
That's right.
I'm sorry.
You'll just have to take your medicine like everybody else.
That's right.
Hopefully, it's not...
You know, what if he's out of office is when the jig is up?
We want him out now and to let that happen quick, as fast as possible.
You know what?
If the noose tightens enough...
Yeah.
If the noose tightens enough, he really needs the money that badly.
Don't be surprised if he just...
Don't be surprised if one day just straight out of nowhere he quits.
Yeah.
Yeah, exactly.
That's what I was thinking, too.
It could...
It's not likely, but it's not an impossibility.
And he'll just take whatever he's built up while he's in office to try and make...
Just to try and monetize that, of course.
And then when everyone turns their back on him, then there'll be something else.
I just hope...
If that happens while he's in office, that could be very dangerous for everybody in the world.
That's what I'm worried about.
If people start turning their back on him now, for money-wise, he will act out.
Right?
Yeah.
So, let's let that happen after the presidency.
I'll tell you what.
I've got to meet someone for a late supper.
Okay.
And I will...
I'll keep the thing open.
I'll get a signal.
I will get a signal.
Okay.
I'll let you know, okay?
All right, man.
Can I get a first name so I don't call you Kaiser?
Even though I like Kaiser.
That's a good name.
No, we can do that.
It's Colin.
Colin.
Okay, Colin.
Thanks, Colin.
All right.
And please stay in touch, okay?
I will.
Okay.
All right, man.
Thanks.
Cheers.
Bye.
Okay.
I wouldn't care.
Yeah.