what happened no remember we i told i confronted him on the podcast about the meeting with uh
either dessa roseanne and she said that david was hounding her no and she yeah you tell you tell
her it doesn't but david wasn't hounding me oh he just recently uh he you asked me if i've heard
from david yeah and uh hold on i'm trying to pause this movie and it's not pausing one second one
second pause freaking pause this worst tv oh what are you watching i'm watching the bureau
classic french spy show emory french spy show oh really yeah the bureau the comedy no no it's not
comedy it's like a spy show like spies in syria and stuff like that totally my stuff cool i want to
see that cool no no you asked me if david had contacted me and i said he recently he reached
out because he wanted to he wanted to clear up something and he said that i had told you that um
uh you that that if he got offered money he would take it right and he said is that the truth did you
tell thou that and i said back to him i only told him what we had talked about in one conversation
right many like like two years ago at the new york times when i met him for lunch and i
asked you if if you got um you know a deal would you take it and he said that he would only
take it if it was large enough to split with you and satisfy both of you and that he would not do
anything without you right yeah see thank you that's that's what i thought yeah see yeah that's just cool
she she's she's she didn't lie he said that you lied about what he said that you never happened that
you never said any or what do you say the meeting never happened first of all until we got him to
admit that we knew about the meeting that first of all he's never met you right right that he never
met you and that he never said anything about money once but why would he what like why i don't
understand why he would lie he was he was caught on camera lying so he had to keep he had to like
double down you know i mean i have no reason to hide anything he said that and i told him that's
what i recounted to you i told him that too what was his reaction was he angry or he never responded i
left it on the voice note on his phone because i was in like dubai and he asked me and i just said
he never responded yeah he never oh wait he showed us he never responded remember he showed us this
thing this text uh oh god some weird text i can't remember but anyway that's we'll talk about that
later wait what he's a convoluted guy he's very convoluted but so this guy doug letter is the guy
that's running the investigation and
yes
that's right
i've had a good education anyway
thank you
my