cigarettes in town. And then you're stuck at the campground because your mom's credit card is
basically toast. And you're out of money because Avis has stolen or whatever. So at the campground
you're playing gigs there to earn your keep essentially? Yeah they said not to earn my keep,
just sort of. I had nothing else to do and they said look you can stay here and we'll run a tab for
you you know but we're going to have to move you out of the nice cabin and put you into the safari
tents in this other other. So you're staying in a tent? Yeah staying in a tent. It's like a you
know there's sort of big safari tents you see. Like on a platform? Yeah yeah I should have to
so many pictures. I'll show you some more. And it's like bunk beds inside this tent and so I had
the whole thing to myself and it was at the further reach of the campgrounds. And yes I would play
during the day I would just because I had nothing else to do so I just played music but it wasn't
earning my keep but in the sense they're sick well you know just keep playing and then we'll
do this for you. You can eat for free at the cafe and you can live in this tent until you get this
thing solved with Avis because I explained to them the whole thing and why I was here I showed
them the air post thing they understood okay this is Val's you know not trying to rob us here this
is a legitimate thing they saw the the tape on the car they saw the broken glass before and after
they saw the police report which is written in fucking Dutch so and they were all Dutch people
so they understood the police report so they all were kind of on my side and they're very good
people they're very nice people that ran that place you at the camper that's where you meet Julie
that's where I meet Julie yeah she's 24 at the time she's taking her class in Amsterdam yeah
her father had died in 2015 from her heart attack yeah and she says to me we shared the madness of
death uh that's very Julie and I also know that you also shared lots of mushrooms yes we did um
okay
I believe they're called truffles now, psilocybin truffles, truffles yeah because you can't in
Amsterdam legally sell mushrooms psilocybin mushrooms so they sell psilocybin truffles
it's just like a work around the law the same thing okay um you at this point I think find
another credit card in your mom's email yeah basically enables you to get back on the road
exactly and so you're at the camper and you make contact with David Rossi or sorry with a lawyer
for the winner it's a little more dramatic than that I escaped fleeing boats on the cover of night
because my stay was no longer accepted it was I overstayed my welcome did you put this in the
book too yeah I did not I overstayed my welcome and I was getting moved from the safari tent and
then when there was a bunch of Scottish kids coming in for some EDM concert they asked me to sleep in
the back of the car with the broken window and still had glass in the back because I didn't
want to touch anything for the insurance people in case avis actually fucking showed up I spend my
days on the reason why and this is important because this this is a really long story but I'm
going to do my best to summarize um is that I they had one phone I could not top up my phone
because I couldn't I was negative $15,000 in my accounts I could not top up my phone I could
not make a phone call I could use their wifi and the reason you're $15,000 negative is because
avis is basically charging for the price of a new car yes they charge me for the price of a new
fucking car and it took me a very long time and I was only allowed like a two hour period during
the day to use their house phone and that's what I would spend the days calling avis trying to get
figure out what's going on just from customer service person to customer service person six
weeks later okay I'm still working on it but I had I had managed to escape because they were
getting tired of me I overstayed my welcome I find that hard to believe
fuck you fucker um no but I I mean when they moved me and they said you have to sleep in your car
now it's that's what I knew like okay this is I've overstayed my welcome I got a guy it's avis is
still dragging their feet they haven't done anything they sent me from customer service agent
customer service agent nothing's been done I met Julie I'm like okay I'm just going to escape with
Julie and they had why did you do a skate because legan bus held on to my passport and my guitar
because then you I would go nowhere without my my why did they want to have anything in case in case
I left without paying the bill that I had oh so you had a bill I had a bill they gave me like a half
price for everything but they were still charging me for the food because I had to stay I had to
eat something yeah so I had how big was the bill it was about 2500 euros at the end of it which is
half price for everything yeah they did I mean they're still very kind and that was a very good
deal for what they gave me which was they let me live so wait why let me stay like they wouldn't
let me be homeless and I was very kind of but I had could not pay that 2500 dollar bill and no matter
even when I found the other credit card I tried so hard online to pay this with them and they could
not accept the digits it was chip and pin only and I was like come on please just plug in it's like I
love to believe me we want to get you out here and pay this no we don't care where you got this
number we believe you but we cannot do it without the chip it's like a law in in this in Amsterdam
so I went online they try and do it online they would not accept the card because it was not
an international card it was an American card they wouldn't accept it in the fleeing boat so I'm like
can you just change your fucking online payment system like that we don't know anything about it
we hired a tech company to do it we can't do it I tried so hard to pay them with with my mom's credit
card so I had no other choice when they when I was uh uh what's the word not so educated
regulated or when I was moved to the back of my car with the broken glass relegated relegated to the
back of the car broken glass with the fucking sleeping bag and you had to leave they had held
on to my fender strat they knew I would go nowhere without the fender strat and my passport
which I obviously would not go anyway my passport so over the weekends the security was very
lax days ago and there was this really great guy who's like a uh it used to be like a children's
clown for a long time and then something happened in his life he lost all his money his wife and
now he's a security guard for fleeing boats really nice guy I talk him into giving me my guitar
and that saturday night he says oh I just want to play it let me just keep in the car I'm sleeping
in the car right here I'm not going where it's out of course here's your guitar Sunday night
there's another guy who's a real dick he was a one it was a writer he was a terrible writer
really bad it was a dutch guy trying to cliches everywhere like he was asking everyone to read
his books and they're fucking terrible and so I talk him and I told him my story he wanted to
oh this is a really interesting story you should do I was like I don't want to hear your fucking
advice for my story but I talk him into giving me my passport because I said I want to buy some
cigarettes I don't have an ID I can walk to the nearest town with my friends here to buy some
cigarettes kind of just have my password so yes you can have just make sure you give it back
by him tonight so I take the password I have my guitar I'm all ready to go I'd say you know what
I can't walk I got to drive this broken fucking car to the uh cigarette store because the one
that's in walking distance is closed can you please open the gate I was like okay push the button
opens the gate and I'm fucking free fine I go straight to Julie's oh so Julie isn't living
at the camp her name no she's a student student right okay yeah she's okay and so at what point
do you make contact with uh luka garachi is that at the campground while I was living in the tent
yeah okay that's where I'm at yeah okay so um I quote you emailing him saying maybe I can help
maybe we can help each other and perhaps also help other families of those who've suffered
for all this misery yeah um he invites you to come to sienna yeah um you do so in early august
by then you've got an outing now right no no sorry it's a white BMW convertible yeah but that's
an a whole nother story because again after six weeks I get into I get into steinberger this is
where I check into the steinberger wait sorry hang on first there was the dorms Julie and I went to
the dorm when I got the credit card working and I'm like you know fucking haven't showered and God
knows how long I look like shit I got the beard and I got this 24 year old hot German girl with me
walking in with guitars in my hand and you know a bunch of and and no credit card again it's it
wasn't easy but all I had was memorized 15 digits of my mom's fucking american express I don't have
security code I had the expiration date so four more digits and I walk in there and I just
fucking talk them into letting me stay on this credit card and it was not easy and Julie was
very surprised that it worked I was like wow I can do this this is a steinberger no this is a
different this is at the dormant and then I did the same exact thing at the steinberger
okay don't you got booked we booked the biggest fucking suite possible and got the whole spa
package at the dormant and Julie and I would just relax for a bit it was just nice to have a
fucking campground have a little bit of civilization you know and we just fucked and had a good time
and went to the pool and saw it as it was just nice to get out of that fucking situation and then
they were booked um and I couldn't renew the suite and I didn't want to get one of those shitty fucking
so I didn't you know whatever I didn't want to live in a city where I just lived in a fucking
so then I go to steinberger and I stay there for about six more weeks and still dealing with
avis they still have not refining the money or or giving me a new car or done anything and this is
where the tab what I've got the tab this is where Julie gets a brilliant idea is to email the board
of directors at avis so just get the fucking call the ceo if you can like you're fucking right and I
go to like ceoemails.com there is a website to ceoemails.com and I find every board member on avis
and I send them all a fucking email like I'm stuck here get me out of this fucking thing it's been
six weeks fuck all you and then finally I get one of the board members gets back to me and that's
how they send out the specialist and remember I say in emails do you mean the specialist that
guy's fucking nuts the guy flies out from London to Paris to deal with this and he goes to the
headquarters in the stand bowl and he's still keeping me you know fucking with me this whole time
he says what we're gonna do is gonna swap out your car we're gonna give you a new car and after
that's how fucking long it is I think it's six weeks or sorry it was actually five weeks of
league and boasts and then it was another month at Steigenbreder the guy's finally swaps out the
car and it was a BMW convertible right a two-seater which is completely inappropriate for what I need
because I had so many bags and guitars at that point and I showed you the pictures where it all
just popping out of the fucking car I couldn't believe it and they said and and I had to talk
him say well we need a working credit card you can't use a debit card I said well you know I'm
negative 15,000 because of you fuckers on my debit card so I couldn't use that anyway and I
don't have a working credit card I said well you can't so we can't swap out this card because
officially we need a credit card number it's like okay I've got a family card that we can use I've
just called my family's private banker and I just played it out like I'm this you know this special
rich person with private bankers call the private banks they they've authorized the use of this
credit card it has my family name on it um it's actually a brooksmit family card you know I didn't
say a la brooksmit I said brooksmit family card I'm obviously Val as you know we've been talking
to each other say I'm not supposed to do this it's getting in trouble it's like look man
you know I just gave him a whole fucking charm spiel the best I could do is say fine okay just
use the card so I gave him that those 16 digits again sorry in the expiration code they put it
on my mom's card and I was finally free and then I could go to Siena I checked out at Steigenberger
and I went to Julie moved from her student housing into this beautifully lovely dilapidated
squat with all these other girls and that was fucking great so we lived in this squat with her
and her friends and that was fucking fun and I'd moved all my shit in there and use that as my
home base point for that for the next trip to Siena okay left the guitars and all this shit in there
and then I went to Siena but I stopped in Berlin first before no no I'm sorry I went to Siena first
and then Berlin but we'll get there okay so in Siena your and the whole the whole trip now
is funded by me walking in with guitars being the the exotic American with 16 digits pretending that
this is all I don't know anything about money all I know is they said you can use this card
okay Mr. Berksman yes of course and I got cash by by saying you know I don't know if you guys
still do this oh well we don't really give cash against the room anymore it wasn't you know like
I'm a bit of a trouble here I'm not quite sure what to do and then the bank rates and the exchange
rates are just terrible I'm losing so much money on these exchange rates like oh yes they are quite
terrible we can give you a better rate actually here but it's actually a nominal commission
charge okay let me let me get 500 euros against the card like of course Mr. Berksman and so I would
do like every other day get 500 euros and that's how we'd amass enough cash to get through it this
the next adventure um okay so after spending $10,000 a month on each hotel and the DAS stew is
probably my favorite of all of them the which one the DAS stew in Berlin is the greatest hotel
great people what do you think you spent overall overall Jesus I don't know there's 10 grand there
another 10 20 maybe about 45 50 grand on that card over what time period
from spring or summer of oh no oh I forgot about the plane tickets yeah maybe about 50 grand
from a spring of 2016 to uh November of 2016 right yeah um okay so
splurge um okay so you go you're in sienna you go you walk over to garachi's home and office yeah
you meet and I bought two more guitars and amplifier which are still at charles
and I walked into the music store in nuremberg with Julie hey I'm on tour and I need some new guitars
and you know all I'm the tour manager gave so we can use this credit card number say oh of course
mr. Berksman uh what's your name again is oh if you look me up uh bikini robot army so oh you have a
lot of albums like oh yes you know so like oh you must be an american oh I play guitar you know I have
a show coming up you should are you gonna be in nuremberg oh yes I'll try and make it to your
show young man of course that's a place this whole bullshit game and they let me buy these guitars with
no credit cards it's 16 digits and you didn't feel any you didn't feel all bad no no I did not
I'm using my mom's card no absolutely um okay because again keep in mind I know I've seen the
money reports I've seen what's happened I've seen the way it's been treated did not feel bad at all
but I would never ever I mean I never I mean I had so many chances even from just the Sony hack
you know me credit card numbers I'd access to I mean for fuck's sake I mean I could hack anybody
anytime never use anyone else's card it's the only target just your mom just my mom that's it
that's the money was owed for me from her I felt kind of owed to me or just to stay alive I mean
I would rather stay in the streets than steal from some stranger I that's and I have many times has
you know yep and I had many options to do so and I never did it's only my mom's card never even
my sister's I could have taken my sister's credit cards never didn't want to ever touch my sister's
money it's my mom okay so you go to garachi's head and my uncle Bob so many options is to
so much money from so many people but I would never do that that's not you know I make that
quick sound people here is some hacker that steals people's shit you know I mean yeah I owe
fleeing boats 2500 still yes but that was I had to go there was it was time was up and technically
then steal I just owed them this money and then and anyway you know you get my I get your point
thank you okay so you're in sienna go to garachi's house you exposed light bulb dangling from the
ceiling yeah man guys red central casting caravaggio is my favorite yeah italian renaissance
is excessive fantastic yes I used to be really obsessed yeah until like two weeks ago we had in
my house a print of saint gerome writing which is this wonderful caravaggio saint gerome with you
know his halo bald head and kind of a robe over him sitting at a table kind of stooped over writing
with like a skull on the table oh yeah with the with the candle on the top of the skull yes that's
it's like it's a beautiful beautiful it's beautiful um yeah the print like a it's not like it was it's
like a essentially like a poster oh okay it is uh uh but I had no nice frame anyway so the widow uh
what's her name tibonasi uh uh no the widow um uh dig rossie and antonella antonella tibonasi
yeah so she comes out of the corner she scares you like the scene in vertigo yeah really like
the very end vertigo the nun coming listen man yeah you do did you watch vertigo I mean
not recently but I've seen vertigo better listening yes you should watch vertigo I've seen vertigo
yeah yeah oh okay did you watch the girl the dragon tattoo yeah I watched I've seen the one of them
yeah the first one yeah probably remember how I kept saying the girl the dragon tattoo ending
is what I had planned I don't remember the end it's where she hacks the the bad guy the bad
businessman steals all his money puts it all offshore and and it goes to different banks
as a as a character she created that doesn't exist only on paper kind of like the straw
shank redemption ending as well and that's what I had planned with my mom was to take all that
for myself and do that and just live in some somewhere where that couldn't be extradited for
stealing back the you know and putting my mom into a rehab making her living in a sober living
environment that was my plan that's how angry I was very very angry but that's the the girl
with the dragon tattoo ending I've been saying that to you for fucking years um David I'm going
for the girl with the dragon tattoo ending I know and I don't pay any attention to the girl with the
dragon tattoo I should I should I'm pretty sure I've seen it anyway so the widow's there you
she asked you what is it you want she's crying you say I'm looking for connections
you want to understand how did she talk to luka did you know me with her yeah okay although the
language barrier was really something so did his daughter's help no um okay he's got a lovely daughter
so you um are asking him and her you're trying to figure out is there something that kind of links
the deaths of your father and david rossi yeah and then also mckaylee fights a lot yeah um so you
talked for an hour so uh and but the language barrier is too much you offered to get a translator
he said I can't mind I'm staying at the hotel now directly across the yep I've got that yep um
it uh it's two level sweet and a duplex duplex with frescoed ceiling yeah it's beautiful um
I've stayed in a hotel near there actually it's uh with also a frescoed ceiling yeah yeah
which one I don't remember it's years ago um
okay so you offered a hired translator he says no the stuff we're talking about is too sensitive
to have a stranger he instead invites you for lunch the next day and his two daughters would
translate but did you put in keep in mind that this david rossi's story is like the oj simpson
story of sienna yes yes it's huge so that's why he was so paranoid um okay so you come next day
and he paints this kind of sordid picture of the corrupt relationship between doigcha and
monnie deposky talks about how faisola knew or should have known that these guys were up to no
good it talks about the monnie deposky's connections to the mob and corrupt local politicians and
that was complete open secret uh he told you the lawyer told you that rossi had been mixed up in
some bad stuff himself renting a car once a month and driving to switzerland to logano yeah to logano
to put cash and secret bank accounts for like local mobsters basically you know including uh one
cardinal scurrano and vatican if chief uh about a vatican financial officer yeah okay it was the
chief one but and so you're taking notes and like really intrigued by in fact he showed me these
notes yeah i still got them in the suitcase do you want me to pull them on no that's okay um
and it 13 pages of notes no you've showed them we we went over this last time i was here um
so um the way you explained this to me the last one i talked about this is which was a year ago
was that this was like really intriguing but you were also like a little bit jealous about it in
some ways like it was so simple it was obviously very complicated but like it seemed like rossi
had been murdered yeah right he like felt the window backwards those two guys approach yeah going back
to David Gray showing me this right yeah exactly and that is like much easier to understand in a
way even though it's complicated than what your dad did absolutely yeah um which is why i like this
theory but of course you like the theory that your dad was murdered you're extorted they're
forced to kill himself right this is my leading theory at the time okay okay so he gives you a
bunch of documents uh luca garachi and you leave tuscany yeah with tuscany and sienna well sienna's
in tuscany sorry okay tuscany's like the region yeah well more specifically it leaves yeah but
fine i can eat tuscany because it's tuscany it sounds a little broad in general it's like
it's about now with the tuscany because if you go to tuscany you go to tuscany well sienna is a tuscan
hilltown okay fine i don't have to figure about it but i it's now you don't want to figure about it
i mean it's it's it's it's it's move it's move you want to figure um i i'm going to tuscany like
we're in tuscany i'm going to okay okay okay i gotta do it uh um but but but but let's see so i'm
tuscany no um but florida's tuscany oh i don't think so i think florida's south it's really
further south i'm pretty sure i'm not plugging the internet here but if you really care it's easy
enough to look up uh find the bicker yeah okay so so okay you and i might need a little help with
the chronology here so you leave sienna yeah you go to germany i go to berlin you go to you go to
germany this tells me to get in touch with mort's enders okay well just hang on hang on a second
so you and julie reconnected this point she is an apartment in nuremberg that she's their sister
right yeah not yet not yet though i first goes to uh berlin uh to meet morris and then after that
i'm meeting sorry who's morris mort's mort's mort's who's he so he's the the german filmmaker
right okay yeah yeah i did that german thing and now he's at the dossier and that's where i spent
all that money and time in the dossier in berlin okay um and we shoot the documentary there for a
couple days about uh what i learned from david rossi because luke put me in touch with him he said
here's a film maker that's interested in the story i think you should speak to morris i called morris
he said meet me right away in berlin so go to berlin hang with morris wait i'm not this doesn't
actually matter i can tell by the picture it doesn't even matter to me what i want so i might i might
go and see julie first i don't remember it doesn't matter you go to germany you do some shit then you
and julie drive to nuremberg and on your way to nuremberg you stop in frankfurt yes right which you
you've never been to frankfurt never been to frankfurt okay and so you and julie are standing
outside the deutch event towers yeah and staring up at it and you told her that up there the guys
are responsible for your dad's death yeah and that she felt like a she could sense your visceral anger
and actually found that was scary yeah okay good we're set i don't need she also thought of being
followed all the time by this folks wagon some guy because we always saw the same license plate
around the steigenberger hotel i remember this and it's this there's this guy in the
fucking boats wagon the same license plate we keep passing him the highway all the time
he's asking about that okay um okay so we're gonna fast forward a little bit okay you end up in
prog julie's exited yeah see you guys the relationship kind of ended over a fight over money
no no she had a she was going on with some other girl she had a she met somebody else
and she didn't tell you that did she no she didn't uh but she did tell me there was a big a huge
fight over money that yeah no because i used her i had to use her account to get money from america
but it wasn't a fight over money it was because she was seeing some other girl she had a fair
with some girl and that's why i didn't it's like the fuck you i'm not going back to to to perler
to apsham and she said okay well whatever but you can still use my account because i still use her
account okay and then she had done some and i have all the documents i'm gonna i'm definitely i sent
you the bank statement i'm not at all interested in she took out a bunch of money that i had put in
and then when i cleared my money out because i got i got snow it's it's important because i got
stuck in prog and that's when all the credit cards were cancelled i'm on frozen yeah and we're
about to get into that so the um so you enjoy the breakup yes and you're in prog you're translating
money to posky documents yeah you're sharing them with a bunch of journalists yeah there's like a
small flurry of stories and other media about yeah this stuff that you've been planted um
um this is when i've got the view switch to oxy um i actually did that in amsterdam uh so when i
first before the car was uh uh someone had stolen the computer from the car i had seen a doctor and
started on about 20 milligrams he gave me like 30 20 milligram pills of oxy because i was still
kind of detoxing from france as decoding was you know harder to get in amsterdam and hamsters
hamster and get anything else why am i dealing with over the counter code code even i'm fucking
in amsterdam so i go i find a doctor who describes whatever you want because me oxy i run out of that
while i'm at uh league and bows and i switched to opium poppies so there's you can buy just dried
opium poppies you crush them up pour hot water on it let it sit for a couple minutes and you drink
opium tea and it's fucking glorious it's glorious and that got me through a lot of misery when i had
no money but you can always get the opium poppies for like a euro you know you can borrow a fucking
european somebody get 20 of them it's dirt cheap and it just was great um and then when i finally got
cash again that i went to the doctor it was in nuremberg it was a great doctor to prescribe me
80 milligrams like 200 tablets for two weeks okay so what i've got is that by the time you're in
prog you're it got me through it got me through it's you're doing about 10
80 milligram pills a day no not in prog that was in france when it got to france i was up to 10
so how many what were you doing in prog um i'd say uh about half that five maybe six a day okay
five yeah um
i've never done that or is that like an addiction at that point or is it what is an addiction is
a habit it's not like a habit you know i mean but what happens if you stop taking it i don't know
there's many different people who give you well what's your experience a theory between
addiction and habit but yeah i mean i could stop if i didn't want to you know and i was forced to
a few times so i mean went off and on them um but it was just easier than buying off the streets
the doctors would give it to you you know you're getting you know it's reliable makes you happy
get through the day i'm not miserable i've got this described here as an addiction is that do you
think that's unfair no it's not unfair um i would say more you know uh tool but um okay i mean it's
the opiate addiction right i mean all i know that is what i read and it's like obviously extremely
addictive well i mean i think about just think about alcohol in terms of alcohol yeah but it's
a lot more addictive than alcohol isn't it it depends on the person then okay fair enough so
hate oxycodone some people love alcohol they hate all other drugs but yeah okay you know some people
hate and i'm the other the flip side of that yeah um okay so september 2016 you go to a
vote-of-fun store to get a new sim card and guess what happens in prog yes okay so your turn i got
pulled over by the interval people remember i tell me tell me the license plate number i went to sleep
in uh somewhere between nuremberg and prog and i had already been pulled over for a speeding
through a checkpoint when i was going to lugano and they took my passport i told them that i was a
journalist and i was doing a story on montia pasca and i showed them all the documents i had
etc etc and they they bought my story and they said okay well just don't go through fast these
checkpoints and how long you've been in this country by the way let's go back and forth it's
like well you need proper visa to be to be staying here longer than three weeks so it's okay i'll
coming back through again i said well you can't come back through again it's the thing you have to
actually you know i didn't pay attention to them i just kept going back through the they're all
shagging countries you're supposed to be allowed to do this i don't understand the issue um but and
then i at this last point that we're talking about now i'm going to prog i pull over at like a rest stop
during the day to just sleep in the car and snore a couple more of the oxys and just because i was
fucking exhausted um and i wake up and there's they're knocking that well actually i wake up i
saw them pull in i was already up i was listening to some podcast Neil deGrasse Tyson this fucking
podcast was getting through all this shit it was it's a good podcast um and the car pulls in
in front of me and it's another bmw and that just it's like an undercover copper i don't know how
they do it in germany or in interpol um and this sort of short-stop guy comes out and this sort of
tallish elderly or older blonde woman uh the woman can speak english the other guy cannot and he's
carrying a gun and they've got official documents saying that they're uh with interpol and but in
conjunction with uh a german something that bnd here i don't know whatever german state
running agencies and they're one of what i'm doing here why i keep going over the
the border so many times can't there's so many times can they search my car
i'm like dude i'm just a guy you know i'm a journalist i'm trying to figure out the story
because i don't want to talk about my dad so i just it's just easier to say i'm a journalist at
this point it's my cover it's like you know i'm just i can show you all what i'm working on here's
here's search me on the internet so i i am who i am here's my passport
do nothing wrong um they say well you've been going over the border waits many times you
cannot come back to germany unless you get a proper visa and they say can we search your car
and i'm like well you can but take a look and i do the old the shirt from the electric
electric gulet acid test if you remember tom wolf and when neil castley gets pulled over by a uh
uh a cop anywhere in america he keeps the back of his car does a filthy fucking mess and he says
my license is somewhere in the back of his car officer please uh let me just find it for you
might take some time and he just keeps pretending to look for the license until they give up so i
say well yes of course you know i have all my travel documents and visa stuff and everything's
available right here somewhere in my luggage and they see the luggage piled up as you've seen piled
up beyond the convertible roof and then i pretend to start opening up from the trunk and i start
looking for oh no i've got everything right here you know i've got the press uh pass i think it's
just lied my ass up and they just sort of sat there and watched the the older guy was just new
ass full of shit but you couldn't really do anything and the woman they got some call about
something else and he heard them talking german and they said okay look just get a fucking visa
next time you're through here and they just wanted to verify and they didn't ask me if i
drugs in the car and i said i did and i have prescription for them and i showed them prescription
i got from the doctor in urnberg and that was enough for them at that point okay and then i cross
over and there's no there's no passport check to get into prod at that point right so you are
supposed to have a visa to be in the EU you don't you're a european citizens don't need visas to
travel between countries but americans after three months and i'd been there well over three months
at this point yeah okay so shakin or tushkin what's the word it's i can't even maybe it's shakin
it's the it's the treaty that allows open borders between european countries so okay anyway you're
in prog so yeah 2016 yeah you go to the vote upon story you get a sim card come back to your the
bmw convertible life cigarette prepare to drive away and all of a sudden out of nowhere comes this
hulking dude and asks what you do yeah and i remember feeling that there was something wrong
with that day as soon as i got into that that fucking that mall is like a check a mall in check
and then prod it's very strange just looking for a vodafone and i felt like i was being followed
and i remember larry saying be careful and like god damn it i don't see you know i can't my skills
aren't that good to pick up on being followed and i don't want to live in this fucking paranoid world
that larry wants me to live in so like i'm not being followed not being followed but just the fact
that thought popped into my head at that specific time this means my instincts were up
and the alarms were going off and i probably should have listened to them but i just pretended
that it was my own paranoia and i don't really know what you could have done about it it's like
there's like that guy was like following the guy i mean i don't know he for some reason he waited
till i got into the car um right there so okay and you know where his car was it was parked right
across from mine you know so okay so as this guy's attacking you and obviously i've seen the video so
there's uh the thing that keeps flashing through your mind is that this is deutcha that sent someone
to finally kill you no not deutcha the the mafia because of the everything i learned from luca
about montian poskey and the calibria mafia calibria mafia i thought this is a mafia fucker
because he was italian and it just came from fucking i've been spending all my time translating
by hand pdf documents that were scanned from montian poskey david rossi's emails and just the
antevented to deal everything that he gave me you've seen it thousands and thousands of fucking pages
so i've got italian mafia in my head i just have been to legano to try and get the search
of your money looking at the at the banks that have david rossi was dropping these his bags of
cash off so i'm thinking mafia mafia mafia here's an italian doesn't speak a word pulling me out of
my fucking car i thought i was gonna die i really thought i was gonna die it's terrible and i'm so
stupid because i had bought for uh just for the show a uh in urmberg you can buy like a pellet gun
it looks exactly like a proper gun and i had that in the glove compartment and had i brought it out
maybe the guy would have run away i don't know yeah or maybe he would have shot you or maybe
he would have shot me but all i could think of was use the phone so it's the best weapon i have is
this phone um okay so please come in the video recording of the phone right of course the um
and it remained a miracle to me that you both videoed it and we're smoking a cigarette and
we're fighting this guy it's impressive thank you very well coordinated um okay so it turns out
obviously after uh dealing with the cops this guy's not an assassin yeah he is a repo man repo
man and he gets your car he gets the car and you did at that point in fact owe abis a lot of money
no they still owe me 15 grand they had not given me anything right but they but so put that aside
they you owed them for this bmw like you hadn't been paying you'd had this now for a few months
yes and because they had told me they this was free this car was now free because of all this
shit that because i did not charge it i i was well but i was looking for lawyers to the best i could
but no one would represent me for free against avis so their thing was you can have this car for
free but you have to return it to france you know and they say you can have it for a month
i'm like okay great but i kept it longer than a month because i was like fuck you avis and keep
as long as i fucking want after what you did to me and that was how that worked out for you it did
well and you know how it worked out for me but that was the thing and then it wasn't i didn't
owe them any money they still owed me money right since i went back to berlin that they gave me half
of that back half of it okay so seven thousand okay so now you owe me fucking five grand okay so
now you were without a car yeah uh and six weeks later it's the election you stay up all night
uh watching the results well just for the chronological order i went like when i first
got to prog or checked into the holiday because it was the easiest thing at three in the morning
and they accepted late check-ins and that's where i had the car and that's the hotel staying out
in the car was repossessed and i did the whole thing and the woman from central cast do you
have the whole woman that came in there and talked to us it's an interpolated from central casting
came walked in the room to manage the situation between the guy that couldn't speak english me
oh right yeah yeah yeah i'm just a story yeah but i don't need the whole story i mean there's
ultimately and the police drove me back to the holiday right okay i stayed in there
just highs how this might i was defeated it was feeling terrible i'm just watching netflix
trying to write my story because the whole purpose of going to prog was to write my story
you know everything that's happened up to this point couldn't outright shit and started hacking
more into my mom's uh my mom's files to see if i can find more credit cards at this point
i found one that i was still usable and i checked myself into a nicer hotel i can't remember the
name of it in downtown or sort of center downtown center prog by where they all did
like a staple center equivalency uh a prog rather than the you know the businessmen go for their
businessmen things you know the auditoriums and big speeches and shit and i got a great
suite there and then in the middle of that stay my mom froze her credit and then they were trying to
charge me for room service and they said we haven't been able to charge her the last few days you know
you owe us this much money like yeah the cards cancels like are you serious let me call the bankers
if i know what's wrong right away and like well we're gonna have to escort you to the room ask
you to leave if you can't pay this right now i was like okay well what can i pay so i get all the
money that i had masked uh by taking cash out against the rooms which is i had a bunch of cash but
i think it was about 3,500 euros i owed and plus i had julie's account that i had money coming into
from america from vju which is about 25 to 2,800 a month and from that i took out what i put in
exactly what i put in julie unbeknownst to me had already been taking money out of that account
that i had put in so i was like fucking julie is like well you know what i owe her she's letting me use
her her bank accounts she had to do is a joint account it had my name on it i had a card with
my name on it as well and julie had her own so i was pissed off that she was taking money out of
this account but i had enough to cover the 3,500 i owe this place but i didn't know what to do about
going to a new place so that's why i went to an airbnb and started using airbnb i've never used
airbnb in my life and i should have been doing it the whole time because you can get
fucking great value especially in prog and that's why i started going to airbnb and using
the money i had left i transferred to a new account i did a new td bank account online
from prog and put money instead of going to julie's account cancelled that and put it back into my
account in my name from td bank okay that's how i started so i lived on 2,500 a month at that point
in airbnb okay we're gonna pause okay just break this up yeah